<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<links:doc>
<links:group name="Tutorials and documentation">
  <links:link name="Dia Tutorial" url="http://www.seanet.com/~hgg9140/comp/diatut/all/all.html">
   Dia tutorial written by Harry George
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Dia documentation" url="http://togaware.com/linuxbook/dia.pdf">
   A chapter about Dia from the book "The GNU/Linux Desktop" by Kayon Toga
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="UML Tutorial" url="umltut/index.html">
   A nice little UML tutorial using Dia
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Dia Mailing List" url="http://mail.gnome.org/mailman/listinfo/dia-list">
   The Dia mailing list, for developers and users alike.
  </links:link>
</links:group>

<links:group name="Tools that generate Dia diagrams">
  <links:link name="AutoDia" url="http://droogs.org/autodia/">
    AutoDia is a modular application that parses source code or data (if a
    handler is available) and produces an XML document in Dia format.
    Handlers for Perl, C++, Java and PHP are available.
    (This used to be called AutoDIAL.)
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Diazy" url="http://diazy.sourceforge.net/">
    Diazy is an open source software package that is modeled after portions
    of the proprietary system Rational Rose. Diazy's two main objectives
    are to generate a source code framework from a UML diagram that was
    created in the popular open source-diagramming tool Dia. It will also
    generate a Dia UML class relationship diagram form any object oriented
    code source.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="pstoshape.pl" url="http://public.logica.com/~redferni/dia/">
    A perl script that attempts to extract connected shapes from PostScript
    files.  In some cases, this makes it very easy to generate shapes.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="EMF Decoder" url="http://public.logica.com/~redferni/emf/">
     A Perl script that attempts to decode Visio documents (even inside
     Word documents) by looking at the EMF (Enhanced MetaFile) part.
     Unfortunately, Visio 2002 only uses bitmaps for EMF, but older files
     can be converted with some restrictions.  
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="HappyDoc" url="http://happydoc.sourceforge.net">
     HappyDoc generates documentation for Python programs, and can output
     Dia diagrams.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Synopsis" url="http://synopsis.sourceforge.net/docs/index.html">
     Synposis is a documentation extraction tool.  It can output Dia
     diagrams among other things.  It doesn't try to do layout.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="ArgoUML2Dia" url="http://jerome.abela.free.fr/dia.html">
     ArgoUML2Dia converts from the ArgoUML format to Dia, though not all
     object types are supported yet.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="SchemaMania.org" url="http://www.schemamania.org">
    SchemaMania.org aims to be a repository for database design schemas.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="PostgreSQL AutoDoc" url="http://www.rbt.ca/autodoc/">
    A perl script which takes the database structure and exports an XML
    file which Dia can use, together with various documentation formats.
    This used to be called Postgres_to_Dia.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Agata" url="http://agata.codigolivre.org.br/">
     Agata Report is a Report Generator, written in PHP-GTK.
     Allows you to edit and get SQL results from several Databases as
     Text or PostScript Files.  It can generate Dia diagrams with all the
     tables you are working on.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Medoosa" url="http://medoosa.sourceforge.net/">
    Medoosa is a documentation tool for C++ that can produce UML class
   diagrams including generalizations and associations. Corrections can
   be made interactively in a diagram editor (Dia) and are fed back into
   the source as Javadoc-style comments.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="cpp2dia" url="http://cpp2dia.sourceforge.net/">
    "cpp->dia" aka "cpp2dia" has been developed to create UML diagrams for
  Dia from an existing C++ source.  "cpp->dia" is a small console based
  Tcl script, that should not be too intractable. 
  The main focus for "cpp->dia" is at creating nice-looking UML diagrams, and
  not writing an high-end parser for C++ code. Therefore "cpp->dia" uses
  "ctags" to do the main work on parsing the C++ source. 
  To layout the UML graph in a not-random way, "cpp->dia" can utilize
  "Graphviz" from A T &amp; T Labs. 
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="OraSchemaDoc" url="http://oraschemadoc.sourceforge.net/">
  The goal of oraschemadoc is "JavaDoc" style detailed documentation for all
  objects in schemas covering Oracle specific features.  The result of
  executing oraschemadoc is a set of static html files.
  It is also possible to export the datamodel to Dia UML Diagram.
  </links:link>
</links:group>

<links:group name="Tools that generates something from Dia diagrams">
  <links:link name="teDia2SQL" url="http://tedia2sql.tigris.org">
    Dia2SQL is a Perl script to convert Dia diagrams to SQL databases, by
    Tim Ellis.  It supports a number of database systems, including
    Sybase, Postgres, Oracle, DB/2, MS-SQL, MySQL, and others.  It is
    the most complete Dia-to-DB program available.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Nautilus Thumbnails" url="http://www.flyn.org/projects/nautilus_thumbnailers/index.html">
    A bunch of scripts that create thumbnails for Nautilus.  They support
    Dia file format.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Dia2Code" url="http://dia2code.sourceforge.net/">
    Dia2Code is a small utility used to generate code from a Dia diagram.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Dia2SQL" url="http://www.karyopse.de/dia2sql/">
    Dia2SQL is a Perl script to convert Dia diagrams to SQL databases, by
    Alexander Troppmann.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Dia2SQL" url="http://sourceforge.net/projects/dia2sql/">
    Dia2SQL is also a Perl script to convert Dia diagrams (exported as EPS)
    to SQL databases, by Douglas Spencer. 
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Eros" url="http://www.postgres.org.mx/eros.html">
    Eros is another a Perl script to convert Dia diagrams to SQL databases,
    by Roberto Andrade Fonseca. 
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Dia2SQL" url="http://codigolivre.org.br/projects/dia2sql">
    Dia2SQL is yet another transformer from Dia to SQL, this one written in
    PHP. 
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Dia2SQLpy" url="http://honeypotdiary.org/earnoth/html/modules.php?name=Content&amp;pa=showpage&amp;pid=16">
    Dia2SQLpy is yet another transformer from Dia to SQL, this one written in
    Python.  It supports both PostgreSQL and MySQL.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Dia2Postgres" url="http://www.nocternity.net/index.php/projets/dia2postgres?langage=C">
    Dia2Postgres is a Perl script that can be used to convert Dia diagrams
    into PostgreSQL scripts or PHP mirror classes which can add, update and
    modify entries automatically.  It has support for inheritance, simple
    references (limited to a single field), and a fake enum type which
    creates a table.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="dia2fsm" url="http://sourceforge.net/projects/dia2fsm/">
    dia2fsm takes a dia diagram containing an FSM specification (please see the
    user guide for details of general usage and the UML objects to use) and
    forward generates skeleton code.
 
    The current version (V 0.0.2) supports C and C++ code generation (Java
    coming soon), and also creates a makefile to allow the skeleton code to be
    built and tested. It will also create an input file for AT&amp;T's dot
    application, and generate a PNG image of the machine on request. 
 
    The generated code is _not_ intended to be an academically sound FSM
    implementation, but is intended to provide an efficient, working state
    machine. 
 
    dia2fsm is written in C++, and although it is built on Win2K only at
    present, any platform-sensitive code is implemented with the Qt library. 
  </links:link> 
</links:group>

<links:group name="Dia ports">
  <links:link name="Dia for Win32" url="http://hans.breuer.org/dia/">
   Yes, you can now use dia on windows ...
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Dia Win32 Installer" url="http://dia-installer.sourceforge.net">
   Dia setup program for Windows with uninstall option.
  </links:link>
</links:group>

<links:group name="Cool uses of Dia">
  <links:link name="ecolNet" url="http://helvete.escomposlinux.org/ecolnet/">
    ecolNet uses Dia to dynamically generate graphs of service
    relationships.  A novel application.
  </links:link>
</links:group>

<links:group name="Dia sightings in the news">
  <links:link name="Newsforge" url="http://software.newsforge.com/article.pl?sid=05/07/13/1928225%26tid=131">
   An article that explains basic use of Dia 0.94 in a positive, but
  not jubilant light. Includes a bit about how to make new shapes,
  though he missed the fact that you can save .shape files from Dia.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Software Development Magazine" url="http://www.sdmagazine.com/documents/sdm0003i">
   An article about Visio that mentions Dia as a not-quite-as-polished
   version of Visio.  Requires free registration.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="O'Reilly Linux Network Administration" url="http://linux.oreillynet.com/pub/a/linux/2001/02/15/LinuxAdmin.html">
   An article comparing four diagramming programs for Linux (Dia (v0.83),
   Tgif, Tkined, Xfig).  Finds hierarchial views very important.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="IBM developerWorks" url="http://www-128.ibm.com/developerworks/linux/library/l-metaprog3/">
    Third part of an article series about metaprogramming, this article uses
    Dia as the example tool for implementing the idea of Model Driven
    Architecture. 
  </links:link>
</links:group>

<links:group name="Underlying code">
  <links:link name="DiaCanvas widget" url="http://members.linuxstart.com/~arjan/diacanvas.php3">
   A Gtk+ canvas widget based on the Dia canvas code
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="The gimp" url="http://www.gimp.org">
   A free Photoshop like image editor for Unix
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="GTK.org" url="http://www.gtk.org">
   The Gimp toolkit, the toolkit used by Dia.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Gnome" url="http://www.gnome.org">
   Gnu Object Model Enviroment. A desktop enviroment for Unix.
  </links:link>
</links:group>

<links:group name="Related programs">
  <links:link name="Vector graphics foundry" url="http://vectorgraphics.foundries.sourceforge.net">
   The SourceForge Vector Graphics Foundry is a list of programs dealing
   with vector graphics.  It lists many smaller, specialized programs as
   well as the generalized ones.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Visio" url="http://www.microsoft.com/office/visio">
   A diagram creation program for Windows. The inspiration for Dia.  Now
   bought by Microsoft.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Ideogramic" url="http://www.ideogramic.com/">
   Two specialized diagramming programs, one for UML, one for generic
   diagrams.  Commercially available for Linux and Windows.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Kivio" url="http://www.thekompany.com/projects/kivio/">
   The KDE diagram program, closely modelled on Visio.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="ArgoUML" url="http://argouml.tigris.org/">
   A UML editor written in Java.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="JGraph" url="http://jgraph.sourceforge.net/">
   A highly configurable Java-based diagramming editor.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Gaphor" url="http://gaphor.sourceforge.net/">
   A UML editor based on DiaCanvas2.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="RoboChart" url="http://www.digins.com">
   A commercial diagramming program for  Sparc and Linux systems.  Offers a
   no-save evaluation download.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Tkined" url="ftp://ftp.ibr.cs.tu-bs.de/pub/local/tkined/">
   A diagramming program specialized for networks.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Ideagraph" url="http://www.ideagraph.net">
   A simple idea visualization tool.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Xfig" url="http://epb1.lbl.gov/xfig/">
    Quite old vector drawing program for X11.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Tgif" url="http://bourbon.usc.edu:8001/tgif/">
   A vector drawing program for X11 with hierarchial objects.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="OmniGraffle" url="http://www.omnigroup.com/applications/omnigraffle/">
   A commercial diagramming program for Mac OS X.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Ipe" url="http://www.cs.uu.nl/~otfried/Ipe/">
   An extensible drawing editor for creating figures for inclusion in LaTeX documents.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Sodipodi" url="http://sodipodi.sourceforge.net/">
   A vector drawing program using GTK.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Sketch" url="http://sketch.sourceforge.net/">
   A drawing package for X windows.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="Gyve" url="http://www.gyve.org/">
   A free vector drawing program for Unix.
  </links:link>
  <links:link name="idraw" url="http://www.vectaport.com/ivtools/idraw.html">
   A vector-graphics program.
  </links:link>

</links:group>
</links:doc>
