<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
<!ENTITY gnomeversion "2.20">
]>

<sect1 id="rnadmins">
	<title>What's New For Administrators</title>

	<para>
			As of GNOME &gnomeversion;, the GNOME Project now includes an Administration Suite, which
			is a collection of tools that are aimed squarely at systems administrators. The
			two new tools that form the beginnings of this suite are incredibly powerful and
			should help administrators in both large corporate deployments and situations
			where machine lockdown is required.
	</para>

	<sect2 id="rnadmins-pessulus">
		<title>Pessulus - Lockdown Editor</title>

		<para>
			Pessulus is a lockdown editor that allows administrators to easily
			disable certain features of the GNOME desktop, as may be
			desired in corporate environments and Internet cafés. While
			lockdown features have now been available in GNOME for many years,
			Pessulus makes it far easier for administrators to perform these tasks.
		</para>

		<figure id="rnadmins-figure-pessulus">
			<title>
				Using the lockdown editor to prevent system shutdown by users
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-pessulus.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					Editing lockdown settings with pessulus
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		
		<para>
			Some of the features that can be disabled include:
		</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para>
				Command-line access
			</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>
				The ability to shut down or reboot the machine
			</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>
				Access to specific protocols in the web browser
			</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>
				The ability to edit the GNOME panels
			</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="rnadmins-sabayon">
		<title>Sabayon - Profile Editor</title>

		<para>
			Sabayon allows administrators to set up user profiles inside a live,
			interactive GNOME session. When a profile is created or edited, a nested
			GNOME session is started up, which the administrator can use to change
			GConf default and mandatory keys in their own GNOME session.
		</para>
		
		<figure id="rnadmins-figure-sabayon">
			<title>
				Sabayon editing a user profile
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-sabayon.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					Using Sabayon to edit a user profile in an embedded window
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<para>
			Within the nested window a system administrator can create personalized
			profiles based on job description (e.g. receptionist, data entry clerk,
			programmer, human resources manager, etc.). These profiles can then be
			saved and deployed to various desktop machines with ease, saving the
			system administrator time. The profiles can also be modified and fine
			tuned as needed based on user feedback and since they are in a centralized
			location, allow for easy maintenance and deployment.
		</para>

	</sect2>

</sect1>
<!-- vi:set tw=80 ts=2: -->
