<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
<!ENTITY gnomeversion "2.20">
]>

<sect1 id="rnadmins">
	<title>What's New For Administrators</title>

	<para>
			GNOME releases a collection of tools for systems administrators to help 
			with large corporate deployments and situations where machine lockdown is required.
	</para>

  <sect2 id="rnadmin-sabayon">
      <title>Lockdown and User Profile Editor</title>
		<para>
			The &quot;Sabayon&quot; User Profile Editor allows administrators to set up user profiles inside a live,
			interactive GNOME session. When a profile is created or edited, a nested
			GNOME session is started up, which the administrator can use to change
			GConf defaults and mandatory keys in their own GNOME session.
		</para>
		<para>
			Within the nested window a system administrator can create personalized
			profiles based on job description (e.g. receptionist, data entry clerk,
			programmer, human resources manager, etc.). These profiles can then be
			saved and deployed to various desktop machines with ease, saving the
			system administrator time. The profiles can also be modified and fine
			tuned as needed based on user feedback. Since they are in a centralized
			location they allow easy maintenance and deployment.
		</para>
		<para>In GNOME &gnomeversion; the User Profile Editor can also be used to set 
		default preferences for OpenOffice applications in addition to the existing support 
		for GNOME and Mozilla applications.</para>

    <figure>
				<title>Setting default OpenOffice preferences for a user profile.</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="figures/rnadmin-sabayon_editing_openoffice.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
  </sect2>

    <sect2 id="rnadmin-gdm">
      <title>GDM (GNOME Display Manager)</title>
      <para>GDM now has better utmp/wtmp auditing, so when users log in or log out entries are placed in /var/adm/utmp and /var/adm/wtmp. For instance, this allows programs such as who and finger to use the utmp database to get information about who is on the system. In addition, support for Linux auditing, via libaudit, logs the success or failure of each login attempt with the Linux kernel audit system.</para>
      <para>GDM can also now use RBAC (Role Based Access Control) to control access to the Shutdown, Reboot, and Suspend features.</para>
    </sect2>


</sect1>
<!-- vi:set tw=80 ts=2: -->
