<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
<!ENTITY gnomeversion "2.20">
]>

<sect1 id="rndevelopers">
	<title>What's New For Developers</title>

	<para>
		The GNOME &gnomeversion; Developers' Platform provides a stable base for independent
		software developers to create third-party applications. GNOME and its
		platform are licensed to allow the creation of both free and proprietary
		software to run on top of GNOME.
	</para>

	<para>
		Libraries in the GNOME Platform are guaranteed to be API and ABI stable for
		the rest of the GNOME 2.x release series. Libraries in the GNOME Desktop do
		not have this guarantee, but most remain consistent from release to release.
	</para>

    <sect2 id="rndevelopers-gtk">
      <title>GTK+</title>
      <para>GNOME &gnomeversion; uses version 2.12. of the GTK+ UI toolkit API, which adds new features and important bug-fixes. The largest changes are: </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem><para>A new GtkVolumeButton widget, for use by media players.</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>A new GtkRecentAction class to provide recent-files menu items.</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>An improved GtkTooltip API, which is much more convenient and powerful than the now-deprecated old GtkTooltipsAPI. For instance, this allows tooltips in GtkTreeViews, and on insensitive widgets.</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>The new GtkBuilder API, which can build user interfaces from XML descriptions, intended to replace libglade soon.</para></listitem>
        <listitem>Support for some simple graphical effects, where the hardware and drivers support them, via functions such as gdk_window_set_composited() and gdk_window_set_opacity().</listitem>
        <listitem>New input methods for the Thai and Lao languages, plus a mobile-phone-style multipress input method for embedded devices.</listitem>
        <listitem>The built-in stock icons were updated to comply with the Tango freedesktop specification, so the appearance of GNOME applications is even more consistent with other toolkits and desktops.</listitem>
        <listitem><para>The GtkFileChooser now shows the recent files list, and can be integrated with desktop search systems such as Beagle and Tracker, as mentioned above in the File Management section.</para></listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>See also the list of <ulink url="http://library.gnome.org/devel/gtk/2.11/ix08.html">new functions in GTK+ 2.12</ulink>. Full details are in a series (see <ulink url="http://mail.gnome.org/archives/devel-announce-list/2007-June/msg00006.html">1</ulink>, <ulink url="http://mail.gnome.org/archives/devel-announce-list/2007-June/msg00003.html">2</ulink>, <ulink url="http://mail.gnome.org/archives/devel-announce-list/2007-June/msg00004.html">3</ulink>, <ulink url="http://mail.gnome.org/archives/devel-announce-list/2007-June/msg00005.html">4</ulink>) of emails from Matthias Clasen, and in the GTK+ 2.12 release announcement. TODO: Link to the announcement when it happens.</para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="rndevelopers-glib">
      <title>Glib</title>
      <para>The Glib utility library now has a g_get_user_special_dir() that provides the path to special folders defined by FreeDesktop.org's <ulink url="http://www.freedesktop.org/wiki/Software/xdg-user-dirs">xdg-user-dirs</ulink> specification and tool.</para>
      <para>And for text processing, the new GRegex API provides regular expression string matching without the need for an additional library.</para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="rndevelopers-pango">
      <title>Pango</title>
      <para>The Pango text rendering system has several improvements.</para>
      <para>For instance, it has a new shaping engine for the <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/N%27ko">N'Ko</ulink> script used by the minority Mande languages in West Africa. These languages have not been well served by computer systems until now.</para>

			<figure>
				<title>An example from the N'Ko shaping engine.</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="figures/rndevelopers-pango-nko-part.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>

      <para>The improved OpenType Layout engine helps Pango to select the correct Glyph depending on the current language.</para>

			<figure>
				<title>Pango's OpenType layout engine choosing the correct glyph.</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="figures/rndevelopers-pango-opentype-language.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>

      <para>In addition, the new version of Pango has:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>Support for specifying multiple preferred languages.</listitem>
        <listitem>Vertical text shaping that uses vertical variants of punctuation marks.</listitem>
        <listitem>New pango_cairo functions, allowing simpler use of Pango with Cairo.</listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="rndevelopers-glade">
      <title>Glade</title>
      <para>The Glade user interface designer is much improved, adding user interface and architectural improvements. For instance, tool windows, such as the editor, the inspector, and the palette, are now dockable.</para>

			<figure>
				<title>Glade, with an undocked window.</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="figures/rndevelopers-glade-dockable.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>

      <para>And you can now right-click on widgets to conveniently make some of these changes:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem><para>Add or remove the parent widget.</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>Insert or remove a placeholder before or after the selected widget in a GtkBox.</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>Insert or remove a page before or after the selected page in a GtkNotebook.</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para>Insert or remove a row or column in a GtkTable.</para></listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Library authors will be pleased to see that new widgets may be declared in the catalog without the need to write supporting source code, allowing developers to use your extra widgets in Glade.</para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="rndevelopers-accerciser">
      <title>Accerciser</title>
      <para>The new accerciser Accessibility Explorer allows you to check whether your application provides the information needed by accessibility tools such as GNOME's Orca screenreader.</para>

			<figure>
				<title>The Accerciser utility examining an application's user interface.</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="figures/rndevelopers-accerciser.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="rndevelopers-documentation">
      <title>Developer Documentation</title>
      <para>GNOME's new documentation website, <ulink url="http://library.gnome.org">library.gnome.org</ulink>, lists all the latest tutorials, manuals and API references. It's the result of a Google Summer Of Code project which ensures that the online documentation stays up-to-date, even showing several versions of the same documents, in multiple languages too.</para>
      <para>This includes the new <ulink url="http://library.gnome.org/devel/platform-overview/unstable/">Overview of the GNOME Platform</ulink> document, which is now an official part of GNOME's software releases, in the gnome-devel-docs module. It's a good place for new GNOME developers to start.</para>
      
			<figure>
				<title>GNOME's new online library of developer documentation.</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="figures/rndevelopers-library-gnome-org.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>

      <para>For offline documentation, we strongly encourage the use of the DevHelp utility, particularly when searching for function or class names, though you must remember to install the relevant documentation packages from your distribution. DevHelp is also now part of GNOME's official Developer Tools release.</para>
    </sect2>

</sect1>
<!-- vi:set tw=80 ts=2: -->
