<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
<!ENTITY gnomeversion "2.20">
]>

<sect1 id="rninstallation">
	<title>Installing GNOME</title>

	<para>
		You can try out GNOME &gnomeversion; via the LiveCD which contains all of the software
		included in GNOME &gnomeversion; on a single CD. It can be downloaded from the GNOME
		<ulink url="http://torrent.gnome.org/">BitTorrent site</ulink>.
	</para>

	<para>
		To install or upgrade your machine to GNOME &gnomeversion;, we recommend you install
		official packages from your vendor or distribution. Popular distributions
		will make GNOME &gnomeversion; available very soon and some already have
		development versions with GNOME &gnomeversion; available. You can get a list of
		distributions who ship GNOME, and discover the latest versions they ship on our
		<ulink url="http://www.gnome.org/~davyd/footware.shtml">Get Footware</ulink>
		page.
	</para>

	<para>
		If you are brave and patient and would like to build GNOME from source,
		we recommend you use one of the build tools.
		<ulink url="http://www.gnome.org/projects/garnome/">GARNOME</ulink> builds GNOME
		from release tarballs. You will need GARNOME &gnomeversion;.x to build GNOME &gnomeversion;.x.
		There is also <ulink
		url="http://www.freedesktop.org/Software/jhbuild">jhbuild</ulink> which is
		designed to build the latest GNOME from svn. You can also use jhbuild to build
		GNOME &gnomeversion;.x by using the <filename>gnome-&gnomeversion;</filename> moduleset.
	</para>

	<para>
		For those who really want to compile the entire desktop by hand, the order
		to compile the modules in is: 
		libxml2, libgpg-error, libgcrypt, libxslt, gnome-common, intltool, rarian, gtk-doc, glib, libIDL, ORBit2, fontconfig, cairo, pango, gnome-doc-utils, atk, shared-mime-info, gtk+, gconf, libbonobo, gail, at-spi, gnome-mime-data, desktop-file-utils, libdaemon, dbus, dbus-glib, dbus-python, pygobject, pycairo, libglade, pygtk, avahi, libvolume_id, hal, gamin, gnome-vfs, audiofile, esound, libart_lgpl, libgnome, libgnomecanvas, libbonoboui, hicolor-icon-theme, icon-naming-utils, gnome-icon-theme, gnome-keyring, libgnomeui, gnome-menus, alacarte, libtasn1, opencdk, gnutls, libsoup, mozilla, evolution-data-server, libgtop, startup-notification, gtk-engines, gnome-themes, gnome-desktop, bug-buddy, metacity, libgsf, libcroco, libgnomecups, libgnomeprint, libgnomeprintui, librsvg, eel, nautilus, libxklavier, libgnomekbd, gstreamer, liboil, gst-plugins-base, libwnck, gnome-panel, gnome-control-center, gnome-speech, dasher, pyorbit, gnome-python, gtksourceview-1.0, nautilus-cd-burner, gst-plugins-good, libmusicbrainz, iso-codes, totem, gnome-media, gnome-python-desktop, deskbar-applet, pwlib, opal, ekiga, eog, enchant, epiphany, poppler, evince, gtkhtml, evolution, evolution-exchange, evolution-webcal, fast-user-switch-applet, file-roller, gcalctool, gconf-editor, gdm2, gtksourceview, pygtksourceview, gedit, gucharmap, system-tools-backends, gnome-applets, gnome-backgrounds, gnome-games, gnome-keyring-manager, gnome-netstatus, gnome-nettool, libcolorblind, gnome-mag, gnome-power-manager, gnome-screensaver, gnome-session, libsigc++2, glibmm, cairomm, gtkmm, gnome-system-monitor, liboobs, gnome-system-tools, vte, gnome-terminal, gnome-user-docs, gnome-utils, gnome-volume-manager, gok, libgail-gnome, orca, seahorse, sound-juicer, tomboy, vino, yelp, zenity, pessulus, sabayon, devhelp, glade3, accerciser, gnome-devel-docs
	</para>
	<note><para>
		This list is provided purely for reference and we strongly urge anyone
		trying to compile GNOME from source to consider using one of the build
		tools listed above.
	</para></note>
</sect1>
<!-- vi:set tw=80 ts=2: -->
