<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect2 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
<!ENTITY gnomeversion "2.20">
]>

<sect2 id="rnusers">
	<title>What's New For Users</title>
	
	<para>
			The GNOME Project's focus on users and usability continues in GNOME &gnomeversion;
			with its hundreds of bug fixes and user-requested improvements. But the
			shear number of enhancements make it impossible to list every change and
			improvement that have been made. This page hopes to highlight some of the
			more exciting user-oriented features in this release of GNOME.
	</para>

	<sect3 id="rnusers-performance">
		<title>Performance Improvements</title>

		<para>
			Just as you would tune your car, our skilled engineers have strived
			to tune many parts of GNOME to be as fast as possible. Several important
			components of the GNOME desktop are now measurably faster, including
			text rendering, memory allocation, and numerous individual applications.
			Faster font rendering and memory allocation benefit all GNOME and
			GTK+ based applications without the need for recompilation.
		</para>

		<para>
			Some applications have received special attention to make sure they are
			performing at their peak. GNOME Terminal, the terminal emulator for the
			GNOME desktop, has been optimized in several ways to make it  faster
			and, at the same time, more resource efficient.
			The GNOME
			Log Viewer now starts up over 20 times faster than before.
		</para>

		<figure id="rnusers-performance-graph">
			<title>
				GNOME Terminal performance improvements between GNOME 2.12 and
				&gnomeversion;. Time taken is the time to print a list of all English words to the
				screen.
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-gnome-terminal-performance.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					GNOME Terminal performance improvements between GNOME 2.12 and GNOME
					&gnomeversion;
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<figure id="rnusers-performance-graph-2">
			<title>
				Log Viewer performance improvements between GNOME 2.12 and
				&gnomeversion;. Time taken to start the application and read
				a 2.9MB log file.
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-system-log-performance.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					Log Viewer performance improvements between GNOME 2.12 and GNOME
					&gnomeversion;
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>  
	</sect3>

	<sect3 id="rnusers-nautilus">
		<title>Richer Searching</title>

		<para>
			The GNOME file manager, Nautilus, now offers a powerful search interface
			available by pressing Ctrl-F on the desktop or in a file
			manager window.
		</para>
		
		<figure id="rnusers-nautilus-search">
			<title>
				Search with Nautilus
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-nautilus-search.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					Nautilus allows you to construct a search and save it later as a
					special folder
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<para>
			Searches are easily constructed and can then be saved in a folder or on
			the desktop. Saved searches can then be opened like a folder at a later
			date.
		</para>

		<para>
			If the Beagle search framework is available, Nautilus will take
			advantage of it for faster, more contextual searching.
		</para>
	</sect3>

	<sect3 id="rnusers-yelp">
		<title>More Help</title>

		<para>
			The GNOME help browser also includes new features for searching help and
			documentation installed on your machine. Now with access to both GNU Info
			and traditional UNIX manpages, as well as GNOME's high quality
			documentation, it is possible to search most of the documentation included
			on your system quite rapidly.
		</para>

		<figure id="rnusers-figure-yelp">
			<title>
				Search Help, view GNU Info files and read manpages
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-yelp.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					Yelp has new search features, as well as the ability to read
					GNU Info and UNIX manpages
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		<para>
			Like with the file manager, users who have the Beagle search framework
			available will be able to utilize it for even faster and more accurate
			searching.
		</para>
	</sect3>

	<sect3 id="rnusers-ekiga">
		<title>Ekiga</title>

		<para>
			Ekiga, formerly known as GNOME Meeting, is GNOME's voice and video-over-IP
			client. Ekiga supports both the SIP and H323 protocols.
			SIP, a popular protocol used in Google Talk,
			Asterisk, and many other software and hardware VoIP devices, is a recent
			addition to Ekiga. H323 is an
			older communications protocol, used in Microsoft Netmeeting and some
			telecommunications hardware.
		</para>

		<para>
			Ekiga also features STUN support to allow traversal through many types of
			firewalls, including Network Address Translating (NAT) firewalls. This
			means that you can use Ekiga to make and receive calls without having a
			public IP address or forwarding ports from your router.
		</para>

		<figure id="rnusers-figure-ekiga">
			<title>
				Making a SIP call with Ekiga
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-ekiga.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					Ekiga can handle both voice and video over SIP
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<para>
			Users can also setup an account with
			<ulink url="http://ekiga.net">Ekiga.net</ulink> which will provide them
			with  a SIP address they can use on the Internet to make and receive calls
			from anywhere.
		</para>
	</sect3>

	<sect3 id="rnusers-metacity">
		<title>Improved Window Management</title>

		<para>
		  <!-- Doesn't it use resistance, rather than magnetism? -->
			Several new features have been added to Metacity to improve window
			management. Window edges now have a magnetic attraction, making it
			possible to "click" windows together. Multiple monitor (head) handling has
			been improved in Metacity. Metacity will now attempt to displace windows
			that want to appear across a monitor boundary onto one monitor or the
			other.
		</para>

		<para>
			To help administrators and users of multiple machines from the same X
			server, the hostname of windows which are not running locally
			will be displayed in the title bar.
			This is especially useful when changing settings on
			machines graphically to ensure that you're making changes on the correct
			machine.
		</para>
		
		<figure id="rnusers-figure-metacity-remote">
			<title>
				Running an identical window locally and remotely
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-metacity-remote.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					XClock remotely, XClock locally
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
	</sect3>

	<sect3 id="rnusers-deskbar">
		<title>Deskbar</title>
		<para>
			New to GNOME is the Deskbar. Power users, keyboard enthusiasts and users
			of the old panel command line will find this replacement incredibly
			powerful and easy to use. Deskbar uses plugins (written in Python) to
			provide search functionality for programs, files, folders, bookmarks,
			contacts and much more. Deskbar can also use the live search functionality
			of Google Live, Yahoo and Beagle.
		</para>

		<figure id="rnusers-figure-deskbar">
			<title>
				Searching for 'net'
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-deskbar.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					Deskbar shows a list of matches for 'net'
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<para>
			Deskbar has both an in-panel mode, and a collapsed mode for use on
			vertical panels or panels with little free space. To search you simply
			press Alt-F3 and enter some terms. You can also
			browse or search your command history.
		</para>
	</sect3>

	<sect3 id="rnusers-gdm">
		<title>Login Improvements</title>
		<para>
			There have been many new improvements to the login system (GDM). The
			performance tweaking seen throughout the desktop has also found its
			way into the login system. There is also a new enhanced "Options" button
			in the login greeter that allows for quick access to various login
			functions. A new "secure remote" feature has been added so that users
			can connect to a X server securely and easily. The look of the login
			greeter has also improved by allowing for more user customization.
		</para>

		<figure id="rnusers-figure-gdm">
			<title>
				It is now easier than ever to change your login preferences in the
				totally redesigned GDM preferences window.
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-gdm.png"
						format="PNG"/>
					</imageobject>
					<textobject><phrase>
						The gdmsetup preferences window
					</phrase></textobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>

		<para>
			Note: The file used by users to set their GDM configuration settings
			has changed from /etc/gdm/gdm.conf to /etc/gdm/custom.conf. For more
			information see the <ulink url="http://www.gnome.org/projects/gdm/">
			GDM Project</ulink> page.
		</para>
	</sect3>

	<sect3 id="rnusers-fusa">
		<title>Fast User Switching</title>
		<para>
			GNOME &gnomeversion; includes support for fast user switching throughout the
			desktop. Both the logout and unlock screen dialogs offer the option to
			switch to another user. A menu can also be added to the panel allowing
			quick access to user switching.
		</para>
		
		<figure id="rnusers-figure-fusa">
			<title>
				Fast user switching from the panel
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-fusa.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					A list of possible users you could switch to
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		
		<figure id="rnusers-figure-fusa-lock-screen-dialog">
			<title>
				Switch users from a locked session
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-lock-screen-dialog.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					Screensaver lock dialog allows you to switch user
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
	</sect3>

	<sect3 id="rnusers-evolution">
		<title>Shared Calendaring</title>
		<para>
			A new feature in Evolution 2.6 is shared calendaring over CalDAV. The
			CalDAV shared calendar protocol is implemented by a number of groupware
			servers, including the freely available <application>Hula</application>
			server.
		</para>

		<figure id="rnusers-figure-evolution">
			<title>
				Viewing a shared calendar from <application>Hula</application>
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-evolution.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					View and edit shared calendars in Evolution
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
	</sect3>

	<sect3 id="rnusers-epiphany">
		<title>Smarter Bookmarking</title>

		<para>
			The Epiphany Web Browser continues to make browsing the world wide web
			easier.
			New in this release is the automatic construction of bookmark hierarchies.
			This reduces the burden of handling large bookmark collections, but
			retains the simpler topic-based system of bookmark management popular in
			Epiphany. Topics are now much easier to select and create;
			Epiphany will even suggest topics based on past usage.
		</para>

		<figure id="rnusers-figure-epiphany">
			<title>
				Improved bookmark management and stylesheet control
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-epiphany.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					Epiphany now builds hierarchical bookmark menus from your topics,
					and gives the user control over page presentation.
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		
		<para>
			Also in this release is support for user-defined stylesheets, providing
			improved accessibility and user control over page presentation.
			Behind the scenes Epiphany can now use Firefox, Mozilla or XULRunner as
			its backend. If you're using <application>NetworkManager</application>,
			Epiphany will be able to automatically detect your network settings.
		</para>
	</sect3>

	<sect3 id="rnusers-gedit">
		<title>Better Editor</title>

		<para>
			Gedit continues to provide the usability of a simple text editor with all
			the features you need to develop applications or websites. Features in
			Gedit &gnomeversion; include improved handling of multiple documents and writing to
			remote files. For example Gedit now allows for the seamless browsing and
			editing of SFTP, FTP and WebDAV directories directly from the file browser.
			It also has improved syntax highlighting of HTML, PHP, PSP and much more.
			These features combine to make Gedit a powerful text editor that can handle
			all the tasks that users require.
		</para>
		
		<figure id="rnusers-figure-gedit-mdi">
			<title>
				Gedit can handle multiple source files easily, opening and saving them
				locally or over a network
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-gedit-mdi.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					Gedit with several Python files open, saving one of them on GNOME.org
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<para>
			Also new is the ability to write plugins for Gedit in Python. This allows
			the functionality of Gedit to be extended and customized easily, even if
			you're not a strong programmer. Some useful plugins that come with Gedit
			include one to execute external commands, support for tag-based completion,
			and an interactive Python console.
		</para>
		
		<figure id="rnusers-figure-gedit-plugins">
			<title>
				Plugins dialog showing the properties for the External Commands plugin
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-gedit-plugins.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					The plugins dialog lets you select installed plugins to activate or
					disable plugins and configure their preferences
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
	</sect3>

	<sect3 id="rnusers-imageviewer">
		<title>Image Viewer</title>

		<para>
			The GNOME Image Viewer has a new navigation-driven toolbar. Now when you open
			an image, you can easily view other images from the same directory.
		</para>

			<figure id="rnusers-figure-eog">
				<title>
					Easy navigation through images from same directory
				</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-eog.png"
							format="PNG"/>
					</imageobject>
					<textobject><phrase>
						EOG main window
					</phrase></textobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
	</sect3>

	<sect3 id="rnusers-screensaver">
		<title>Integrated Screensaver</title>
		
		<para>
			GNOME now features an integrated screensaver. GNOME Screensaver is
			compatible with the "hacks" popular in Xscreensaver, but also has lots of
			new features unavailable in Xscreensaver. Applications that are aware of
			GNOME Screensaver will be able to communicate with it to set properties
			like "do not blank screen" over a standard interface. Dialogs such as the
			unlock screen dialog are now translatable into native languages and
			accessible to users with disabilities. These accessibility enhancements
			allow users with disabilities to easily unlock their displays and are part
			of the ongoing accessibility improvements being made to the entire GNOME
			Desktop.
		</para>

		<figure id="rnusers-figure-gscreensaver">
			<title>
				Configuring GNOME Screensaver properties
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-gscreensaver.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					The GNOME Screensaver properties dialog
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<para>
			Users who wish to continue using Xscreensaver will still be able to do
			so and should consult their vendor's documentation on the specifics. 
		</para>
	</sect3>

	<sect3 id="rnusers-gstreamer">
		<title>Latest GStreamer</title>
		<para>
			GNOME &gnomeversion; utilizes the technology of <application>GStreamer
			0.10</application>. The GStreamer multimedia framework is a powerful,
			pluggable audio and video framework used on Linux and UNIX desktops as
			well as in embedded devices. This latest major version of GStreamer is
			faster and more stable than its predecessors. Issues like synchronization
			of audio and video across different devices has been addressed, as has
			threading and the dynamic handling of multimedia plugins. You can find out
			more about GStreamer from the <ulink url="http://www.gstreamer.org/">GStreamer website</ulink>.
		</para>

		<para>
			All of the multimedia applications that ship with GNOME have been upgraded
			to take advantage of the latest GStreamer; including Totem, Sound Juicer,
			and Volume Control.
		</para>

		<para>
			GStreamer 0.10 will also allow users to take advantage of multimedia
			plugins distributed by third-party vendors. This will allow vendors to
			offer support for licensed codecs where a free codec is not available
			or distributable (for legal reasons). These may include support
			for AC3, WMA, MP3 and more. A licensed, yet freely available MP3 plugin
			for GStreamer 0.10 is already being made available by
			<ulink url="http://www.fluendo.com/">Fluendo</ulink>, a long-time
			supporter of GStreamer.
		</para>
	</sect3>

	<sect3 id="rnusers-control-center">
		<title>Easy Configuration</title>
		<para>
			GNOME prides itself on being easy to configure and offering users simple
			choices while still remaining flexible. A number of elements in
			the GNOME control center have been made easier so that you can set the
			preferences you want quickly and easily.
		</para>
		
		<figure id="rnusers-figure-control-center-preferred-apps">
			<title>
				Set preferred applications by choosing from a list or entering a
				command.
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-control-center-preferred-apps.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					The preferred applications dialog
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<figure id="rnusers-figure-control-center-sound">
			<title>
				Select from a list of available sounds or select your own file from the
				file system.
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-control-center-sound.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					The sound configuration dialog
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
	</sect3>

</sect2>
<!-- vi:set tw=80 ts=2: -->
