<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
<!ENTITY gnomeversion "2.22">
]>

<sect1 id="rndevelopers">
	<title>What's New For Developers</title>

	<para>
		The GNOME &gnomeversion; Developers' Platform provides a stable base for independent
		software developers to create third-party applications. GNOME and its
		platform are licensed to allow the creation of both free and proprietary
		software to run on top of GNOME.
	</para>

	<para>
		Libraries in the GNOME Platform are guaranteed to be API and ABI stable for
		the rest of the GNOME 2.x release series. Libraries in the GNOME Desktop do
		not have this guarantee, but most remain consistent from release to release.
	</para>

	<sect2 id="sect:gvfs-gio">
		<title>GVFS and GIO</title>

		<!-- much of this text is stolen from
		     http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Features/Gvfs and the GIO API docs -->

		<para>
			GVFS is a userspace virtual filesystem with backends for things like SFTP,
			FTP, DAV, SMB, ObexFTP, etc.
			GVFS is the replacement for GNOME-VFS. GNOME-VFS should now be considered
			deprecated and developers should not use it in new applications.
		</para>

		<para>
			GVFS/GIO aims to provide a modern, easy-to-use VFS system. Its goal is to
			provide an API that developers prefer over raw POSIX IO calls. Rather than
			closing the POSIX IO API, it provides a higher-level, document-centric
			interface. As well as reading and writing files, GIO provides facilities
			for file monitoring, asynchronous IO and filename completion.
		</para>

		<para>
			GVFS consists of two parts:
		</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para>
				GIO, which is a new shared library that is part of
				<application>GLib</application> and provides
				the API for GVFS; and
			</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>
				GVFS itself, which is a new package containing backends for various file
				system types and protocols such as SFTP, DAV, SMB and ObexFTP.
			</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>

		<para>
			The way GVFS works is that it runs a single master daemon (gvfsd) that
			keeps track of the current GVFS mounts. Each mount is run in a separate
			daemon (some mounts share a daemon process, but most don't). Clients talk
			to the mounts with a combination of D-BUS calls (on the session bus and
			using peer-to-peer D-BUS) and a custom protocol for file contents.
			Moving the backends out-of-process minimises dependency bloat for
			applications and makes the whole system more robust.
		</para>

		<para>
			GVFS also offers a FUSE mountpoint in <filename>~/.gvfs/</filename>
			so that GVFS mounts can be exposed to legacy applications utilising
			standard POSIX IO.
		</para>

		<para>
			Unlike
			GNOME-VFS, connections in GVFS are stateful. This means that a user only
			needs to enter his or her password once, not over and over again for each
			successive connection.
		</para>

		<para>
			With the switch to GVFS, automounting and autostart are now handled
			directly by <application>Nautilus</application> rather than
			gnome-volume-manager.
		</para>

		<para>
			API documentation for using GIO is
			<ulink href="http://library.gnome.org/devel/gio/unstable/">available
			online</ulink> along with migration guides for moving from POSIX IO and
			GNOME-VFS to GIO.
		</para>

		<sect3 id="sect:gvfs-regressions">
			<title>Regressions</title>

			<!-- FIXME: check we need this section -->
			<para>
				Although GVFS fixes a lot of problems that previously existed by using
				GNOME-VFS there are currently some feature regressions. Most notably:
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem><para>no FTP support; and</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>no fonts:// or themes://
												targets.</para></listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para>
				These issues will be fixed as soon as possible. There are also some
				applications that still remain to be ported over to GVFS, the state of
				this port is <ulink href="http://live.gnome.org/GioPort">documented
				online</ulink>.
			</para>
		</sect3>

	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="sect:anjuta">
		<title>Anjuta IDE</title>

		<para>
			The <application>Anjuta</application> IDE has been made part of the GNOME
			Developer Suite. Anjuta is a GNOME integrated IDE that offers many
			features for developers, such as an integrated debugger, integrated Glade
			UI editor and Valgrind interface.
		</para>
	</sect2>

</sect1>
<!-- vi:set tw=80 ts=2: -->
