<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
<!ENTITY gnomeversion "2.22">
]>

<sect1 id="rnusers">
	<title>What's New For Users</title>
	
	<para>
			The GNOME Project's focus on users and usability continues in GNOME &gnomeversion;
			with its hundreds of bug fixes and user-requested improvements. The
			sheer number of enhancements make it impossible to list every change and
			improvement made but we hope to highlight some of the
			more exciting user-oriented features in this release of GNOME.
	</para>

	<sect2 id="sect:cheese">
		<title>Say Cheese</title>

		<!-- FIXME: cheese screenshot -->
		<para>
			GNOME 2.22 introduces a new application,
			<application>Cheese</application>. Cheese lets you take photos and make
			videos using your computer's webcam apply a range of different effects
			(like XXX and XXX) that you can share with your friends, load into
			<application>F-Spot</application> or set as your account photo.
		</para>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="sect:metacity">
		<title>Window Compositing</title>

		<para>
			GNOME 2.22 introduces window compositing on capable platforms. Fitting
			with GNOME's "keeping it simple" policy, the features are very low key.
			The most noticeable changes are drop shadows on windows, live previews when
			switching windows with Alt-Tab and transparency effects.
		</para>
		<para>
			Not all graphics hardware reliably supports compositing, so this feature
			is currently turned off by default. To enable it... XXX XXX.
		</para>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="sect:gvfs">
		<title>Better Networked Filesystems</title>
		<para>
			GNOME 2.22 introduces <application>GVFS</application> a new
			network-transparent virtual filesystem layer for GTK+. GVFS is designed to
			overcome the shortcomings of the older GNOME-VFS system such as
			remembering login credentials for the entire session and being more
			resilient to failures.
			Many GNOME applications are already using GVFS including all of the core
			applications.
		</para>
		<para>
			With the switch to GVFS, GNOME is now using the Freedesktop.org
			<ulink href="http://www.freedesktop.org/wiki/Specifications/trash-spec">
			Desktop Trash Can</ulink> specification to handle the storage of deleted
			files.
		</para>
		<para>
			Technical information about GVFS is available in <xref
			linkend="sect:gvfs-gio" /> of the What's New For Developers section.
		</para>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="sect:totem">
		<title>DVD, Digital TV and more</title>

		<para>
			GNOME's <application>Movie Player</application> now offers improved
			support for DVD playback. Also new in GNOME 2.22 is support for
			digital television (DVB).
		</para>

		<!-- FIXME: DVB screenshot -->

		<para>
			Also appearing in 2.22 are a selection of new plugins, including support
			for MythTV, Youtube and Tracker-based searching. Also new is playlist
			sharing and the ability to select subtitles for files.
		</para>

		<para>
			GNOME 2.22 premieres the capability to preview and play Flash content and
			video using the free and open Flash decoder
			<application>swfdec</application>.
		</para>

	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="sect:gnome-panel">
		<title>International Clock</title>

		<para>
			No need to do any more mental arithmetic to work out what time your
			teleconference starts in Sydney, GNOME 2.22 now has internationalisation
			built into its clock. Add locations from around the world to see the local
			time and weather.
		</para>

		<!-- FIXME: screenshot -->
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="sect:evolution">
		<title>Continual Evolution</title>

		<para>
			<application>Evolution</application> continues to be improved
			with new support for Google Calendars and custom message labels (tagging)
			for your email.
		</para>

		<!-- FIXME: Evolution Google Calendars screenshot -->

		<para>
			Work has also gone into improving the speed of spam filtering and making
			error dialogs less intrusive on your desktop session by using the status
			bar rather than popups.
		</para>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="sect:vinagre">
		<title>VNC Client</title>

		<para>
			New in GNOME 2.22 is the <application>Remote Desktop Viewer</application>.
			This application complements the existing remote desktop server
			support in GNOME, it features the ability to discover machines on the
			local network and bookmark your favourites.
		</para>

		<!-- FIXME: vinagre screenshot -->

		<para>
			Users desiring more control over the remove desktop server will also
			appreciate the addition of an <guilabel>Advanced</guilabel> tab in the
			properties dialog.
		</para>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="sect:small-things">
		<title>But that's not all...</title>

		<para>
			GNOME 2.22 also features many bug fixes and user-required enhancements
			from the last 6 months of development including:
		</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para>directly open Evolution contacts in
											<application>Deskbar</application>;</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>improved printing in <application>Text
															Editor</application>;</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>network multiplayer in
											<application>Chess</application>;</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>download notifications in
											<application>Epiphany</application>;</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>LZMA (7-zip) support in <application>Archive
															Manager</application>;</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Inhibit automatic suspend/hibernation while burning
											CDs;</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><application>Document Viewer</application> is now faster
			and uses less memory;</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><application>Document Viewer</application> can also now
			support page transitions in PDF Slideshows;</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><application>Tomboy</application> can now organise your
			notes into notebooks;</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><application>Sound Juicer</application> now supports more
			meta-data, including disc number and year; and</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>much, much more that you'll have to install or upgrade
			to see!</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</sect2>

</sect1>
<!-- vi:set tw=80 ts=2: -->
