<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN" 
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY version "2.12">
<!ENTITY oldversion "2.10">
<!ENTITY nextversion "2.14">
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
]>

<!-- Now uses xinclude. To validate now requires use of                         -->
<!-- the "xinclude" and "postvalid" command line options to xmllint             -->
<!-- and the "xinclude" option to xsltproc                                      -->

<article id="index" lang="en" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <articleinfo>
    <title>GNOME &version; Release Notes</title>

    <abstract>

      <title>GNOME &version;</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-gnome-desktop.png" format="PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>The GNOME Desktop</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>

      <para>GNOME 2.12 is the latest version of the
      popular, multi-platform free GNOME desktop environment,
      providing all the tools a computer user needs, 
      and a platform for software developers.</para>

      <para>GNOME releases occur every six months, delivering new
      improvements to our users as fast as
      possible. GNOME &version includes several interesting new 
      features and hundreds of bug
      fixes. These release notes demonstrate the changes in &version;
      and provide some background about GNOME. 
      If you are familiar with GNOME, you might go
      directly to <link linkend="rnusers">What's New for Users</link>
      or use the other navigation links. If you're not familiar with GNOME,
      or would like more background, continue reading this
      page.</para>
      
      <para>If you'd like to learn more about GNOME in general,
      including many of the qualities that distinguish GNOME from
      other computer desktops (like freedom, usability and
      accessibility), information about our community (including our
      great translation and quality teams), and pointers to many other
      sources of information, try our <ulink
      url="http://www.gnome.org/about">About GNOME</ulink>
      page.</para>

      <para>GNOME &version; includes all of the improvements made in
      GNOME &oldversion;. If you'd like to learn more about those, you
      can read the GNOME &oldversion; <ulink
      url="http://www.gnome.org/start/2.10/notes/">release
      notes</ulink>.</para>

      <para>This release contains all the applications needed to
      provide basic user functionality, like system menus, file
      management, web browsing, and email. These pieces form the basis
      for a whole ecosystem of applications built on the GNOME
      development platform, including great applications like
      <application>Gnumeric</application>,
      <application>Abiword</application>, <application>the
      GIMP</application>, and
      <application>Inkscape</application>. These applications don't
      necessarily release on the same schedule as GNOME, and are not
      part of our 'core' desktop, so they are not covered by these
      release notes. To find out more about them and other great GNOME
      applications, check out <ulink
      url="http://gnomefiles.org">GNOMEfiles.org</ulink>.</para>

      <para>GNOME is part of the GNU Project, and is proud to be and
      to support <ulink
      url="http://www.fsf.org/philosophy/free-sw.html">free
      software</ulink>.</para>

    </abstract>
  </articleinfo>

 <xi:include href="rnusers.xml"/>
 <xi:include href="rnadmins.xml"/>
 <xi:include href="rndevelopers.xml"/>
 <xi:include href="rni18n.xml"/>
 <xi:include href="rninstallation.xml"/>

  <sect1 id="rnknownissues">
    <title>Known Issues</title>
    <para>All software, when it is released, contains bugs the developers know
    about but have chosen, for a variety of reasons, not to fix before
    releasing. Free software is no different in this regard from proprietary
    software, except that with free software, we tell users about these problems.</para>

    <para>We also encourage our users to report bugs so that they can be
    fixed. The best way to report bugs found in GNOME is to use the <ulink
    url="http://bugzilla.gnome.org/simple-bug-guide.cgi">Simple Bug
    Guide</ulink>. This will take you through the necessary steps to file a
    quality bug report, and make sure that it is tagged appropriately. If you're
    too advanced for anything with the word 'simple' in it, there is also the
    <ulink url="http://bugzilla.gnome.org/enter_bug.cgi">traditional bug
    form</ulink>.

    More details on bugs already reported can be found at our <ulink
      url="http://bugzilla.gnome.org/">Bugzilla</ulink>. Among the
    most prominent GNOME &version; bugs:</para>

    <sect2 id="rnknownissues-list"><title>List of known issues</title>
    <para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>The 'open terminal' action has been removed from the
          Nautilus right-click menu, in order to improve manageability
          and default usability. If you miss it, we recommend
          installing <ulink
          url="http://manny.cluecoder.org/packages/nautilus-open-terminal/">the
          Nautilus open-terminal plugin</ulink>, which not only
          restores 'open terminal' to the nautilus menu, but actually
          makes it better by opening the terminal in the directory in which you
          are browsing.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para><ulink url="http://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=116814">
          Session startup temporary hang</ulink>: Applications with broken
          session management can cause login to hang for a few minutes at the
          splashscreen.  The default session does not contain any such apps so
          this will only become a problem if you save your session on logout.
          If you run into this problem, just wait for the login to proceed and
          then remove any such applications before saving your session
          again.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    </sect2>

    </sect1>

  <sect1 id="rnlookingahead">
   <title>Looking to GNOME &nextversion; and Beyond</title>

        <para>GNOME operates on a time-based release schedule, an
    attempt to continuously provide the best of our developers' efforts
    to users as quickly as we can. The following features are on the radar of GNOME developers and may land in the next few releases.</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem><para>Support of the <ulink url="http://www.apple.com/macosx/features/bonjour/">Apple Bonjour<ulink> standard for detection of services on the network, potentially via <ulink url="http://www.freedesktop.org/Software/Avahi">Avahi.</ulink></para></listitem>
          <listitem><para>Support of the <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Caldav">caldav</ulink> open calendar services standard in Evolution.</para></listitem>
	  <listitem><para>Use of <ulink url="http://people.redhat.com/dcbw/NetworkManager/">Network Manager</ulink> to give all network-aware apps intelligent behavior in the face of network connection and disconnection.</para></listitem>
          <listitem><para>Consolidation of gtk and gnome libraries to ease development and deployment of GNOME applications, via <ulink url="http://live.gnome.org/ProjectRidley">Project Ridley.</ulink></para></listitem>
          <listitem><para>Increased usage of new rendering infrastructure to improve looks and usability, for example, by integrating it with <ulink url="http://www.stellingwerff.com/?p=5">Clearlooks, our new default theme.</ulink></para></listitem>
          <listitem>
	      <para>For further information, see the <ulink url="http://live.gnome.org/RoadMap">GNOME roadmap</ulink> on our wiki.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
  </sect1>
  <sect1 id="rngettinginvolved">
    <title>Getting Involved</title>
    <para>
      The core of GNOME's success is its many volunteers, both users and
      developers.
    </para>
    <para>
      As a user, your contribution can be as simple as filing good bug
      reports. You can file bugs in our Bugzilla using the <ulink
      url="http://bugzilla.gnome.org/simple-bug-guide.cgi">simple bug
      assistant</ulink>. If you want to contribute more, you can join our active
      <ulink
      url="http://developer.gnome.org/projects/bugsquad/">bug-squad</ulink>.
    </para>
    <para>
      For developers, there is much exciting progress to be made in any
      of our active developer groups - Accessibility, Documentation, Usability,
      Translation, Web, Testing, Graphics, and Desktop &amp; Platform
      Development. Here is a 
      <ulink url="http://live.gnome.org/JoinGnome">guide to help you get started</ulink>.
    </para>
    <para>
      Helping on GNOME can be an incredibly satisfying experience, allowing you
      to meet a wide range of motivated, skilled, and helpful people all working
      towards a unified goal. Join us today and see what a difference you can make.
    </para>
  </sect1>

<!--<xi:include href="rnthanks.xml"/>-->
      <appendix id="rncredits">
        <title>Credits</title>
        <para>These release notes were assembled by Murray Cumming, Davyd Madeley, and the GNOME community.</para>
      </appendix>
</article>
