<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect2 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
                  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
<!ENTITY version "2.10">
<!ENTITY oldversion "2.8">
]>
<sect2 id="rndesktop">

  <title>Desktop</title>

  <sect3 id="rntheme"><title>Look and Feel</title>
    <para>GNOME &version; introduces a new standard theme, also known as &quot;ClearLooks&quot;, making your desktop more attractive while remaining simple and uncluttered.
    </para>

  <figure id="rnscreenshot-theme">
    <title>Attractive, friendly, simple, the new default theme.</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-theme.png" format="PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>The new default theme</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
  </figure>

  </sect3>

  <sect3 id="rnnautilus"><title>The File Manager</title>
    <para>
     The file manager, also known as Nautilus, has several user interface improvements in 
     GNOME &version;. Most noticeably, the list view can now show files in directories, allowing you to navigate down to a sub-folder and open a new folder window only when necessary. Also for your convenience, the Bookmarks menu now shows the same locations as the File Chooser dialog.
    </para>

    <para>In GNOME &version;, dragging text from an application to a folder window will save you time by creating a new text document. You'll also notice that GNOME now shows a preview of the text being dragged, instead of just an icon.</para>

  <figure id="rnscreenshot-nautilus">
    <title>clean-cut and powerful, the Nautilus file manager</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-nautilus.png" format="PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>The file manager</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
  </figure>

    <para>
     There are also major improvements to the browse mode, making it similar to GNOME's existing File Chooser dialog:
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>Places and Bookmarks may be displayed in a sidepane.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>The location is now show with the GNOME's path bar instead of a text entry. The text path is still available via the Control-L keyboard shortcut.</para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    </para>

    <para>GNOME's simple CD-burning feature can now create Audio CDs instead of just data CDs. Just drag the tracks to the window that opens when inserting a blank CD. TODO: better explanation of how this actually works?</para>
  
  </sect3>

  <sect3 id="rngeneral"><title>Clipboard</title>
    <para>GNOME now remembers data that you copy, even when you close the window from which it was copied. This long-standing problem has finally been solved without the performance problems usually associated with clipboard deamons, by allowing applications to explicitly request the use of this feature.
    </para>
  </sect3>

  <sect3 id="rnpanel"><title>The Panel</title>
    <para>
     The panel, which you normally see at the top and bottom of the screen, allows you to start applications and control various aspects of your environment. In GNOME &version; vertical panels with menus are possible, thanks to the rotated menus.
    </para>


  <figure id="rnscreenshot-panel">
    <title>The GNOME Panel</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-panel.png" format="PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>A vertical panel</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
  </figure>

  </sect3>


</sect2>
