<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect2 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
                  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
<!ENTITY version "2.12">
]>

<sect2 id="rnplatform">
  <title>Platform Improvements</title>
  <para>The GNOME &version; Development Platform provides a stable base for third-party software developers, and for the GNOME Desktop itself. GNOME &version; adds some API improvements, while maintaining backwards compatibilty and API-stability.</para>

    <para>In GNOME &version;, <ulink url="http://www.gtk.org">GTK+</ulink> 2.8 provides the following new features
    <itemizedlist>
       <listitem><para>GTK+ now uses the freedesktop Cairo drawing API, making custom widget drawing easier to implement and allowing new effects. In the near future, this should allow GNOME to use new graphics effects and take advantage of hardware acceleration, as well as improving our printing APIs.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>GtkFileChooser can now display a file-overwrite confirmation dialog when in save mode.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>GtkWindow can have an urgency hint, instructing the window manager to, for instance, flash the window title.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>GtkIconView now impements the GtkLayout interface, and can render items via GtkCellRendererCells.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>GtkTextView now allows you to set a background color for pargraphs, and you can now skip over invisible text when iterating.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>GtkScrolledWindow has functions to get the scrollbars.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>GtkMenu now supports vertical (rotated) menus, and it can ignore keyboard focus, for special applications such as the onscreen keyboard.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>GtkEntryCompletion's popup menu may now be wider than the Entry, and the popup can be avoided when there is only a single match.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>GtkAboutDialog's license text can now be wrapped.</para></listitem> 
      <listitem><para>GtkToolButton can now use named icons from icon themes, and these icons may also be used when dragging.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para></para>GtkSizeGroup can ignore hidden widgets.</listitem>

    </itemizedlist>

    </para>

    <para>See also the full list of the <ulink url="http://developer.gnome.org/doc/API/2.0/gtk/ix06.html">new API in GTK+ 2.8</ulink>.</para>
    
</sect2>
