<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN" 
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY version "2.12">
<!ENTITY oldversion "2.10">
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
]>
<sect1 id="rnusers">
  <title>What's New For Users</title>
  
<sect2 id="rndesktop">

  <title>Desktop</title>

  <sect3 id="rntheme"><title>Look and Feel</title>
    <para>GNOME &version; introduces a new standard theme, also known as &quot;ClearLooks&quot;, making your desktop more attractive while remaining simple and uncluttered.
    </para>

  <figure id="rnscreenshot-theme">
    <title>Attractive, friendly, simple: the new default theme.</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-theme.png" format="PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>The new default theme</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
  </figure>

  </sect3>

  <sect3 id="rnnautilus"><title>The File Manager</title>
    <para>
     The file manager, also known as Nautilus, has several user interface improvements in
     GNOME &version;. Most noticeably, the list view can now show files in directories, allowing you to navigate down to a sub-folder and open a new folder window only when necessary. Also for your convenience, the Bookmarks menu now shows the same locations as the File Chooser dialog.
    </para>

    <para>In GNOME &version;, dragging text from an application to a folder window will save you time by creating a new text document. You'll also notice that GNOME now shows a preview of the text being dragged, instead of just an icon.</para>

  <figure id="rnscreenshot-nautilus">
    <title>clean-cut and powerful: the Nautilus file manager</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-nautilus.png" format="PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>The file manager</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
  </figure>

    <para>
     There are also major improvements to the browse mode, making it similar to GNOME's existing File Chooser dialog:
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>Places and Bookmarks may be displayed in a sidepane.</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>The location is now shown with the GNOME's path bar instead of a text entry. The text path is still available via the Control-L keyboard shortcut.</para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    </para>

    <para>GNOME's simple CD-burning feature can now copy Audio CDs as well as data CDs. Just drag the tracks to the window that opens when inserting a blank CD. TODO: better explanation of how this actually works?</para>

  </sect3>

  <sect3 id="rngeneral"><title>Clipboard</title>
    <para>GNOME now remembers data that you copy, even when you close the window from which it was copied. This long-standing problem has finally been solved without the performance problems usually associated with clipboard daemons, by allowing applications to explicitly request the use of this feature.
    </para>
  </sect3>

  <sect3 id="rnpanel"><title>The Panel</title>
    <para>
     The panel, which you normally see at the top and bottom of the screen, allows you to start applications and control various aspects of your environment. In GNOME &version; vertical panels with menus are possible, thanks to the rotated menus.
    </para>
    <para>You might also notice that applications may now flash their names in the Window List, to indicate that they are ready. For instance, an instant messenger application could flash its icon when a friend sends a message.</para>
  

  <figure id="rnscreenshot-panel">
    <title>The GNOME Panel</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-panel.png" format="PNG"/>
          </imageobject>
        <textobject><phrase>A vertical panel</phrase></textobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
  </figure>

  </sect3>
</sect2>

<sect2 id="rnapplications">
  <title>Applications</title>

  <sect3 id="rntotem">
    <title>Video Player</title>
   
   <para>GNOME's &quot;Totem&quot; video player, uses GNOME's GStreamer multimedia framework. In GNOME &version;, the video player now has a playlist sidebar instead of a separate window, and supports DVD menus and subtitles.
   </para>    
 
   <figure id="rnscreenshot-totem">
      <title>The video player</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-totem.png" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
          <textobject><phrase>The Totem video player.</phrase></textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>

  </sect3>

  <sect3 id="rnsoundjuicer">
    <title>CD Ripping</title>
   
   <para>GNOME's CD ripper easily extracts audio from CDs for later playback on your PC or portable music player. And now, you can play tracks before extracting them. This latest version can also extract files to networked servers or removable devices, using GNOME's VFS system.
   </para>    
   
   <figure id="rnscreenshot-soundjuicer">
      <title>The audio extractor</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-soundjuicer.png" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
          <textobject><phrase>The audio extractor.</phrase></textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>

  </sect3>

  <sect3 id="rnbrowser">
    <title>Web Browser</title>

    <para>GNOME's &quot;Epiphany&quot; web browser is based on Mozilla yet integrates fully with the GNOME desktop environment. Improvements in &version; include 
    <itemizedlist>
    <listitem><para>A Find Bar, as seen in Firefox, and previously available as an Epiphany extension. This allows you to find text on the page, without hiding the page behind a dialog window.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Clearer error messages, shown directly in the browser.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Use of the standard GNOME printing system.</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Bookmarks can be easily shared over the network.</para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    </para>
   
    <figure id="rnscreenshot-epiphany">
      <title>The web browser</title>
        <screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-epiphany.png" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
            <textobject><phrase>The web browser.</phrase></textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>

  </sect3>

  <sect3 id="rnevolution">
    <title>Evolution</title>
   
   <para>
   GNOME's integrated Email and Groupware client, Evolution, supports traditional mail setups as well
   as Novell Groupwise and Microsoft Exchange. With Evolution you can read, write, 
   and manage your emails, contacts, and calendar events.
   </para>
   <para>In GNOME &version; evolution now has an easier-to-use menu layout and an improved attachments bar, and allows inline PGP encryption and PGP signatures. In addition, the calendar now allows delegation of your meeting attendance.</para>
   <para>Groupwise proxy and IMAP accounts are now supported, and some compatibility problems were solved for people also using Mozilla Thunderbird with IMAP.</para>   
   <figure id="rnscreenshot-evolution-mail">
      <title>The email client</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-evolution-mail.png" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
          <textobject><phrase>The Evolution email client.</phrase></textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>

  </sect3>
</sect2>
  <sect2 id="rncontrolcenter">
  <title>Control Center</title>

  <sect3 id="rn-controlcenter-aboutme">
  <title>About Me</title>

    <para>GNOME now has a new About Me control panel in which you can enter your personal details, such as your telephone numbers, address, email address, and instant-messenger IDs, instead of repeating the information in several applications. You can also change your password here.
    </para>

    <figure id="rnscreenshot-controlpanel-aboutme">
      <title>About Me</title>
        <screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-controlpanel-aboutme.png" format="PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
          <textobject><phrase>The About Me control panel.</phrase></textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>

  </sect3>

  <sect3 id="rn-controlcenter-mouse">
  <title>Mouse Preferences</title>

    <para>The Mouse Preferences control panel now allows you to change your cursor theme.
    </para>

    <figure id="rnscreenshot-controlpanel-mouse">
      <title>Mouse Preferences</title>
        <screenshot>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-controlpanel-mouse.png" format="PNG"/>
            </imageobject>
          <textobject><phrase>The Mouse Preferences control panel, showing cursor themes.</phrase></textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
  </sect3>
</sect2>

<sect2 id="rnutilities">
  <title>Utilities</title>

  <para>The GNOME utilities have some improvements, such as:</para>

  <sect3>
    <title>Document Viewer</title>

    <para>GNOME &version; has a new document viewer, also known as &quot;Evince;&quot; to replace the previously separate PDF and .ps document viewers. This new viewer is simpler and more convenient, with a useful search feature and the ability to show several pages at once.</para>

    <figure id="rnscreenshot-evince">
    <title>Document Viewer</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-evince.png" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
          <textobject><phrase>The document viewer.</phrase></textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>

  </sect3>

  <sect3>
    <title>Image Viewer</title>

    <para>The GNOME image viewer can now show pictures with color correction, using ICC profiles.</para>

    <figure id="rnscreenshot-imageviewer">
    <title>Image Viewer</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-eog.png" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
          <textobject><phrase>The image viewer.</phrase></textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>

  </sect3>

  <sect3>
    <title>Help Viewer</title>
    <para>
     GNOME's Help Viewer, Yelp, now uses the same engine as Epiphany, the web
     browser. The look, feel, speed and stability of Yelp have been vastly
     improved.
    </para>
    <para>
     Yelp also has improved support for locale specific formatting, allowing
     documentation to be rendered using language specific formatting rules, an
     excellent complement to the new documentation translation system, that
     allows translators to translate help documents as easily as applications.
    </para>
    <figure id="rnscreenshot-yelp">
    <title>Help Viewer</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-yelp.png" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
          <textobject><phrase>The help viewer.</phrase></textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
  </sect3>

  <sect3>
    <title>Search</title>

    <para>The GNOME search tool now shows image thumbnails instead of just generic icons.</para>

    <figure id="rnscreenshot-search">
    <title>Search</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-search.png" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
          <textobject><phrase>The search tool, showing image thumbnails.</phrase></textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>

  </sect3>


 <sect3>
    <title>Dictionary</title>

    <para>The GNOME Dictionary now has a simplified user interface and presents the entries in an easier-to-read layout. You may now select the fonts used to show entries.
    </para>

    <figure id="rnscreenshot-dictionary">
    <title>Dictionary</title>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject><imagedata fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-dictionary.png" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
          <textobject><phrase>The dictionary.</phrase></textobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>

  </sect3>


</sect2>

</sect1>
