<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
]>
<sect1 id="rnbackend">
  <title>Code cleanups and backend improvements</title>

  <sect2 id="rnbackend-gtk">
    <title>Upgrade to GTK+ 2.10</title>

    <para>GNOME 2.16 now depends on GTK+ 2.10, making use of many improvements
    that were made available by Project Ridley; an effort to consolidate a
    number of GNOME libraries into GTK+.</para>

    <para>One of the first benefits made available to GNOME users is the new
    printing functionality of GTK+ 2.10: It features a high level,
    platform-independent API, <ulink
    url="http://developer.gnome.org/doc/API/2.0/gtk/Printing.html">GtkPrintOperation</ulink>,
    that also includes a new printing dialog. A low-level, UNIX-specific API
    is available as well that currently supports CUPS and lpr for
    printing.</para>

    <figure>
      <title></title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="???" />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para>Many GNOME applications were ported to use the new printing
    functionality, such as the document viewer Evince, the web browser
    Ephiphany, and the help browser Yelp.</para>

    <para>This also marks also the start of deprecating the previously used
    libraries <emphasis>libgnomeprint</emphasis> and
    <emphasis>libgnomeprintui</emphasis>: External projects are encouraged to
    use the new functionality provided by GTK+ 2.10.</para>

    <para>Another important improvement introduced by GTK+ 2.10 is the new
    API, <ulink
    url="http://developer.gnome.org/doc/API/2.0/gtk/RecentDocuments.html">GtkRecent</ulink>:
    It manages a single list of recently opened files and documents. Among the
    GNOME applications using the new functionality are the file manager,
    panel, document viewer, and editor.</para>

    <para>The file chooser dialog has also been improved: the location entry
    (previously opened by using <keycombo>
        <keycap>Ctrl</keycap>

        <keycap>L</keycap>
      </keycombo>) has been integrated and the dialog as a whole remains
    responsive even when performing time-consuming file operations.</para>

    <figure>
      <title></title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="???" />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para>GTK+ 2.10 provides the gtk-touchscreen-mode mode controlling a
    number of changes that make GTK+ work better on touchscreens, which are
    widely used on mobile and embedded devices.</para>

    <para>Several other improvements made available by GTK+ 2.10 are used
    throughout the desktop: New widgets to display clickable hyperlinks, or to
    create multi-step wizards, for example and better drag-and-drop support in
    notebooks allowing tabs to be reordered, moved between notebooks, and made
    into windows by dragging to the desktop.</para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="rnbackend-csharp">
    <title>GTK and GNOME get sharp</title>

    <para>GNOME 2.16 now offers bindings to GTK+ and GNOME libraries for fans
    of the C# (C sharp) programming language. This also means that the
    development framework Mono is a dependency of the GNOME bindings.</para>

    <para>Additionally, software written in C# can be proposed as new modules
    for later GNOME releases. However, existing GNOME modules need to go
    through the proposal process again if they gain a new dependency on GTK#
    and/or Mono.</para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="rnbackend-bugbuddy">
    <title>New Bug-buddy backend</title>

    <para>GNOME's bug reporting tool, <application>Bug-buddy</application>,
    now uses an XML-RPC protocol and no longer requires that the user have
    <application>sendmail</application> installed. As a result of this change,
    projects using Bug-buddy must have the correct information in their
    application's <filename>.desktop</filename> file.</para>

    <para>The previous way to create bug reports
    (<application>sendmail</application> method) will still be supported for
    one year. After that, users of old <application>Bug-Buddy</application>
    versions won't be able to file bug reports anymore.</para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="rnbackend-unicode50">
    <title>Unicode 5.0 support</title>

    <para>GNOME 2.16 will be the world's first desktop release that features
    support for the Unicode Character Database (UCD), version 5.0, which
    defines more than 99,000 characters for the languages of the world. The
    improvements are built into GNOME libraries GLib and Pango, and are thus
    available to all other open source and free software projects that use
    these libraries.</para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="rnbackend-deprecated">
    <title>Removals and other notes</title>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Due to the lack of active maintainership, the themes
        <emphasis>Rand-Canyon</emphasis>, <emphasis>Ocean-Dream</emphasis>,
        <emphasis>Simple-Blus</emphasis>, <emphasis>Smokey-Blue</emphasis>,
        and <emphasis>Traditional</emphasis> were removed. Likewise, the
        <emphasis>Lighthouseblue</emphasis> and <emphasis>Metal</emphasis>
        theme engines were removed as well.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>The screenreader <application>Gnopernicus</application> has been
        replaced by <application>Orca</application>.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
<!-- vi:set tw=80 ts=2: -->