<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
]>
<sect1 id="rnfeatures">
  <title>Feature Enhancements</title>

  <para>If you're using a laptop, have problems finding free space on your
  hard disks, want to customize your menu items, or find it hard to keep up
  with all your personal information, you'll be happy to upgrade to GNOME
  2.16.</para>

  <sect2 id="rnfeatures-laptop">
    <title>A longer life for your laptop</title>

    <para>If you're traveling a lot with your laptop computer, the new
    integrated power management support of GNOME 2.16 will be a major help: It
    lets you manage your battery, UPS, and wireless peripherals. It also
    offers graphs showing you how much power is being used.</para>

    <figure>
      <title></title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="figures/rnfeatures-laptop.png" />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para>Power management is easily controlled via a panel icon. A simple
    preference dialog lets you adapt to the situations you typically use your
    GNOME-based computer.</para>

    <figure>
      <title></title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="figures/rnfeatures-laptop2.png" />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para>By providing hooks via standardized DBUS methods, other programs are
    able to interact with power saving and thus reduce the necessity of taking
    care about power management manually. For example, an application like
    nautilus could stop the computer sleeping automatically when copying large
    files, or a service like beagled could use a slow indexing mode when on
    battery power.</para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="rnfeatures-tomboy">
    <title>Note taking made simple</title>

    <para>A telephone number, an idea, a meeting with friends -- your life is
    an endless flow of small pieces of information. Keeping track of it all
    can be difficult and frustrating but GNOME 2.16 makes it easy with a
    powerful new note-taking application called
    <application>Tomboy</application>.</para>

    <figure>
      <title></title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="figures/rnfeatures-tomboy.png" />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para>Making a note is as simple as clicking the icon in your panel and
    selecting 'New note'. But the key to Tomboy's usefulness lies in its
    ability to relate notes and ideas together: Just highlight a phrase, click
    the link button and a new note appears. In this way you can organize your
    ideas in a way that makes sense to you. And links between your ideas won't
    break, even when renaming and reorganizing them.</para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="rnfeatures-menuedit">
    <title>Enhanced menu editing</title>

    <para>Menu editing just got even more easier. The old menu editor is
    replaced with a new one, <application>Alacarte</application>, which is
    already known to Ubuntu users. Whether you want new menus, new items or
    separators: Alcarte makes it easier to make changes, and adapt the menu to
    your liking.</para>

    <figure>
      <title></title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="figures/rnfeatures-menuedit.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="rnfeatures-baobab">
    <title>Finer control of your disk space</title>

    <para>If you're one of the people who always seem to struggle with an
    insufficient amount of free hard disk space, you'll be pleased to know
    that GNOME 2.16 provides a new tool to get a better overview of your hard
    disk space: With <application>Baobab</application>, you can analyse how
    the space is used and find and remove files that take up space. Scan local
    or remote directories, requested folders or the complete filesystem and
    <application>Baobab</application> displays an image showing the size of
    all the directories found.</para>

    <figure>
      <title></title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="figures/rnfeatures-baobab.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="rnfeatures-orca">
    <title>New screen reader</title>

    <para>People with visual impairments will welcome GNOME's new screen
    reader, <application>Orca</application>. Using the Assistive Technology
    Service Provider Interface (<acronym>AT-SPI</acronym>) to query the
    display, Orca outputs the content using various combinations of speech
    synthesis, braille, and magnification. It thus supports all applications
    and toolkits that support AT-SPI.</para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="rnfeatures-totem">
    <title>Totem improves media web browsing</title>

    <para><application>Totem</application>, the GNOME video player has new
    support for reading and writing XSPF playlists, an <ulink
    url="http://www.xspf.org/">open standard allowing people to share
    playlists</ulink>.</para>

    <para><application>Totem</application> has exciting new features and some
    important fixes on its browser plugin, making
    <application>Totem</application> in conjunction with your web browser pure
    pleasure. Notable features are its ability to happily interoperate with
    web pages that embed Real and Windows media players even if the page
    specifically checks for Windows Media or Real Player. Even the javascript
    interfaces around them will work. <application>Totem</application> now
    allows you to listen to music in the background on web pages that support
    it as well.</para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="rnfeatures-misc">
    <title>Many small but useful changes</title>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>You can now check the spelling of the text entered in the
        <application>Epiphany web browser</application>.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>You can now switch between the open windows of a certain
        application by using the shortcut <keycombo>
            <keycap>Alt</keycap>

            <keycap>F6</keycap>
          </keycombo>. Of course, you can still use the short cut <keycombo>
            <keycap>Alt</keycap>

            <keycap>Tab</keycap>
          </keycombo> to switch between the open windows on a work
        space.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>You can now move applications between different workspaces by
        dragging their taskbar icon onto the wanted workspace.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>You can now spot password-protected files in archives more
        easily due to an new emblem shown for these files.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>You can now preview a screensaver in fullscreen.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>You can now burn DVDs directly with <application>Nautilus CD
        Burner</application>; there's no need to make an image anymore.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>You can now also use Reminder Notes from existing GroupWise
        accounts by using <application>Evolution</application>.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
<!-- vi:set tw=80 ts=2: -->
