<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
]>
<sect1 id="rnfrontpage">
  <title>GNOME 2.16 prepares for eye candy age</title>

  <para>While version 2.16 continues to enhance GNOME with useful features,
  makes it easier to use, and removes rough edges, it also takes the first
  steps into the advancing age of eye candy: windows that wobble, vanish,
  fade, shrink, or explode -- such effects are possible due to ongoing
  advancements of graphics hardware.</para>

  <para>Some of these changes are still under development, and are not enabled
  by default: you need to use a special configuration to use them.
  Nevertheless, they provide a peek into the age to come.</para>

  <para>Come along on a short journey into the future!</para>

  <sect2 id="rnfrontpage-3d">
    <title>Advanced 3D effects</title>

    <para><application>Metacity</application>, GNOME's default window manager,
    makes its first steps into the world of 3D accelerated desktop computing.
    Many extensions to its compositor engine let your windows wobble, shrink,
    explode, fade in and out, bounce on window focus, and show other
    interesting, unusual or funny effects such as having different
    transparency for different window types like menus, dialogs, and main
    windows.</para>

    <para>Not yet enabled by default, new compositing affects are only
    available when Metacity is compiled with the special
    <option>--enable-compositor</option> option. The new compositing features
    also depend on support for the <literal>GLX_texture_from_pixmap</literal>
    extension, which is only available to owners of Intel i830 to i945, and
    ATI Radeon 7000 to 9250 chips at the present time.</para>

    <para><quote>It's important to note,</quote> says Vincent Untz, member of
    the GNOME release team, <quote>that it's an ongoing work, and that more
    will come in 2.18</quote>.</para>

    <para>Once <application>Metacity</application> is compiled with the
    correct option, the effects can be turned on and off without a restart or
    new login, and applications can take advantage of this. For example, the
    GNOME terminal can now offer real transparency.</para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="rnfrontpage-graphics">
    <title>Cleaner icon theme, Cairo, and Wanda</title>

    <para>GNOME 2.16 doesn't just provide eye candy for curious testers; there
    are also many improvements that are immediately visible: an improved icon
    theme that follows the <ulink
    url="http://tango.freedesktop.org/Tango_Desktop_Project">Tango</ulink>
    style guidelines, a new view on events in the calender module of GNOME's
    email application, <application>Evolution</application>, and a long
    overdue face lift for Wanda -- GNOME's cute fortune-telling fish.</para>

    <para>GNOME 2.16's new icon theme follows the artwork guidelines proposed
    by the Tango project, thus supporting a more consistent graphical user
    interface experience for free and open source software. By now also
    following the Freedesktop <ulink
    url="http://www.freedesktop.org/wiki/Standards_2ficon_2dnaming_2dspec">icon
    naming specification</ulink>, the GNOME icon theme now also works for
    applications written for other popular desktops, such as KDE or
    XFce.</para>

    <figure>
      <title>The new and improved GNOME icon theme</title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="figures/rnfrontpage-graphics.png" />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para>Additionally, the icon theme was also cleared up: many application
    icons are now shipped with their applications, making it easier to use
    them from other desktops environments than GNOME. Many icons are also
    scalable now, meaning you can now change their size on your desktop and
    they still look good! GNOME's default meta-theme has also gone through a
    clean-up.</para>

    <para>More eye candy is also available in
    <application>Evolution</application>'s Calender module: it now uses <ulink
    url="http://cairo.freedesktop.org/">Cairo</ulink> to display a much more
    appealing view on events: They now have a top header that displays the
    start time, and the end time if you re-size the event icon. Selected
    events are now shown using a drop shadow. Cairo is a 2-dimensional
    graphics library designed to support a number of modern graphics
    techniques such as stroking, alpha blending and antialiasing.</para>

    <para>GNOME's cute little fortune-telling fish, Wanda, received a face
    lift, too. Being an old companion since the beginning of GNOME, some
    people wonder if that's one of the most important changes of GNOME
    2.16.</para>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
<!-- vi:set tw=80 ts=2: -->
