<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
]>
<sect1 id="rnusability">
  <title>Usability improvements</title>

  <para>Ease of use is one of the highest priorities of GNOME, and
  contributors continue to ensure that GNOME adheres to the highest standards
  of software usability. GNOME 2.16 includes updates that simplify changing
  file permissions, reporting bugs, using the Deskbar applet, and creating
  application launchers.</para>

  <sect2 id="rnusabiliy-permissions">
    <title>Change file permissions comfortably</title>

    <para>Sometimes it's necessary to change the file permissions of
    everything within a certain folder. The Nautilus File Manager now supports
    this by right-clicking a folder and selecting <menuchoice>
        <guimenuitem>Properties</guimenuitem>

        <guibutton>Permissions</guibutton>
      </menuchoice>.</para>

    <figure>
      <title></title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="???" />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para>GNOME 2.16 also introduces fine-grained control of file permissions
    with support for access control lists and Security-enhanced Linux
    (SELinux) attributes.</para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="rnusability-nautilus">
    <title>Simplified bug reporting</title>

    <para>To ensure that GNOME bugs are resolved quickly, developers depend on
    bug reports provided by users. To simplify the process of filing bug
    reports, the <application>Bug-Buddy</application> utility is now
    automatically launched when a GNOME application crashes. To help users
    save time, the new version asks fewer questions and displays everything in
    a single window.</para>

    <figure>
      <title></title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="???" />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="rnusability-deskbar">
    <title>Improvements to Deskbar</title>

    <para>Now Deskbar, a powerful utility for searching your files and the
    web, is even faster to use and takes up less space on your screen.
    Pressing <keycombo>
        <keycap>Alt</keycap>

        <keycap>F3</keycap>
      </keycombo> (or clicking on its icon) allows you to directly enter
    search terms -- your hands can remain on the keyboard all the time.</para>

    <figure>
      <title></title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="???" />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="rnusability-launchers">
    <title>Ready for take-off</title>

    <para>Launchers are a flexible means to start a particular application, to
    execute a command, or to open a particular folder or Web page. GNOME 2.16
    streamlines the process of creating custom launchers with a redesigned,
    easy-to-use dialog.</para>

    <figure>
      <title></title>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="figures/rnusability-launchers.png" />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
<!-- vi:set tw=80 ts=2: -->
