<?xml version='1.0'?>
<page>
  <title>Download</title>
  <body>
    <h2>Requirements</h2>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="http://www.gnome.org/">GNOME</a>, with GTK+ at least 2.2.</li>
      <li>A playback library - you can use either
      <a href="http://gstreamer.net/">GStreamer 0.8</a> or <a href="http://xine.sf.net/">Xine</a>.  If you use
      GStreamer, you will need decoder plugins (e.g. <samp>mad</samp> for MP3 support), in addition to the following core plugins:
      <ul>
	<li><samp>gnomevfssrc</samp></li>
	<li><samp>spider</samp></li>	
	<li><samp>volume</samp></li>	
	<li>An output sink such as <samp>osssink</samp>, <samp>alsasink</samp>, or <samp>esdsink</samp></li>	
      </ul>
      </li>
      <li>
      <p>
	If you use the Xine player, you will need the following libraries to load metadata:
      </p>
      <ul>
      <li>For <span style="font-weight: bold">MP3</span> support, you will need <a href="http://www.underbit.com/products/mad/">libid3tag</a> from the MAD project.</li>
      <li>For <span style="font-weight: bold">Ogg Vorbis</span> support, you will need <a href="http://www.xiph.org/ogg/vorbis/">libvorbis</a> from the Ogg Vorbis project.</li>
      <li>Likewise for <span style="font-weight: bold">FLAC</span> support, you will need <a href="http://flac.sourceforge.net/">libflac</a>.</li>
      </ul>
      </li>
    </ul>
    <h2>Releases</h2>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="http://ftp.gnome.org/pub/GNOME/sources/rhythmbox/0.8/rhythmbox-0.8.8.tar.gz">0.8.8 Source code</a>  (<a href="http://prdownloads.sourceforge.net/rhythmbox/rhythmbox-0.8.8.tar.gz?download">SourceForge mirror</a>) </li>
    </ul>
    <h2>User Contributed Binary Packages</h2>
    <p>There are no <em>official</em> binary packages of Rhythmbox.  Supporting binary versions for
       many different operating systems is too difficult, so we don't even try.  However some users
       have created binary packages, and the Rhythmbox project provides links to them here for
       your convenience.  The existence of a link on this page should not necessarily be considered an
       endorsement.
    </p>
    <dl>
      <dt>Bug Isolation Project binaries</dt>
      <dd><p><a href="http://www.cs.berkeley.edu/~liblit/sampler/downloads/">Specially instrumented RPMs</a> are available from <a href="http://www.cs.berkeley.edu/~liblit/sampler/">the Cooperative Bug Isolation Project</a>.  These builds send feedback that may help us find and fix bugs even faster.</p></dd>
      <dt>RPM</dt>
      <dd><p><a href="http://dag.wieers.com/packages/rhythmbox/">binary and source RPMs</a> of Rhythmbox created Dag Wieers are in his <a href="http://dag.wieers.com/apt/">APT repository</a>.</p></dd>
      <dt>Debian</dt>
      <dd><p>Debian packages are available in the main Debian <samp>unstable</samp> archive.</p></dd>
    </dl>
    <h2><span style="color: #ff0000">Development versions</span></h2>
    <p>
      No development snapshots are available at this time.
    </p>
  </body>
</page>
