<?xml version='1.0'?>
<page>
  <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
  <body>
    <a name="badfiles"/>
    <h3>
      Some files don't play back or aren't loaded into the library.
    </h3>
    <blockquote>
      <p>
	See <a href="http://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=138435">this</a>
	tracker bug on GStreamer (only applicable if you use the GStreamer
	player).
      </p>
    </blockquote>

    <a name="loadcrash"/>
    <h3>
      When I try to import a folder to my library, Rhythmbox crashes. 
      What do I do now?
    </h3>
    <blockquote>
      <p>
	Run Rhythmbox from a terminal passing it the -d option, and import
	the folder which crashes Rhythmbox. It will display a lot of 
	information, and should tell you which file it was trying to import
	when it crashed. Move away that file from the folder and try again. 
	You'll often find that it's a wma or Quicktime file which make
	GStreamer crash. Once you spotted the bad file, file a bug on 
	bugzilla.gnome.org and make the file available to the developers
	somehow.
      </p>
    </blockquote>

    <a name="fedoramp3"/>
    <h3>
      I'm using Fedora, and Rhythmbox can't import nor play mp3 files. 
      What's wrong?
    </h3>
    <blockquote>
      <p>
	Red Hat can't ship mp3 players as part of Fedora because of legal 
	issues. Follow these <a href="http://gstreamer.freedesktop.org/download/fedora.html">instructions</a> to get GStreamer packages with mp3 support.
      </p>
    </blockquote>


    <a name="xineplayer"/>
    <h3>
      I would like to use the Xine player instead of the GStreamer
    one. How can I enable it?
    </h3>
    <blockquote>
      <p>
      The xine-lib backend was removed as it was unmaintained, and GStreamer
      reached the necessary standards for Rhythmbox' use. It also allows use
      to do things like Music sharing and Audio CD creation otherwise not
      possible with the xine-lib backend.
      </p>
    </blockquote>
    <a name="activation"/>
    <h3>
      When I start Rhythmbox, I get this "failed to activate the
      shell: (null)" dialog box. What can I do about this?
    </h3>
    <blockquote>
      <p>
      This issue is caused when Rhythmbox is not installed in the same
      prefix as GNOME (bonobo-activation, specifically). The easy
      workaround for this is to pass <samp>--no-registration</samp> to
      Rhythmbox.  You may also link the
      <samp>GNOME_Rhythmbox.server</samp> file into your
      <samp>prefix/lib/bonobo/servers</samp> directory.
      </p>
    </blockquote>
    <a name="tagediting"/>
    <h3>
      Why will preferences not let me edit my song tag info?
    </h3>
    <blockquote>
      <p>
      Some mp3s are not detected properly by <a href="http://www.gstreamer.net">GStreamer</a>.
      Rhythmbox supports id3 tag editing as an experimental feature. This is a
      feature that will be supported at some point in the future. Use the
      <samp>--enable-tag-writing</samp> flag to <samp>configure</samp> to enable
      it, at your own risk obviously.
      </p>
    </blockquote>
    <a name="tagediting-other"/>
    <h3>
      So if I cannot edit my song tags in Rhythmbox, what is the best way?
    </h3>
    <blockquote>
      <p>
      A 3rd party application like <a href="http://easytag.sourceforge.net/">EasyTAG</a> will allow
      you to edit your song information.
      </p>
    </blockquote>
    <a name="searchclear"/>
    <h3>
      Would it be possible to have a <i>Clear</i> button next to the search entry?
    </h3>
    <blockquote>
      <p>
      This was discussed numerous times on the mailing-list. Please read the
      thread on the <a href="http://lists.gnome.org/archives/rhythmbox-devel/2003-November/msg00189.html">mailing-list</a>, as well as the <a href="http://bugzilla.gnome.org/show_bug.cgi?id=128109">resolved bug</a>.
      </p>
    </blockquote>

    <div class="faqmaint" id="faqmaint">
      <p>
	 F.A.Q. maintained by <a href="http://www.dersoldat.org/">Sean Harshbarger</a>.
      </p>
     </div>
  </body>
</page>
