<?xml version='1.0'?>
<page>
  <title>Translation of Rhythmbox</title>
  <body>
    <h2>About the GNOME Translation Project</h2>
    <p>
      You are probably reading this because you are interested in the
      localization, or translation, of Rhythmbox. Rhythmbox is using the GNOME
      Translation Project (or GTP for short)
      for translations. The GTP web page is at:
    </p>
    <p>
      <a href="http://live.gnome.org/TranslationProject">http://live.gnome.org/TranslationProject</a>
    </p>
    <p>
      The GTP is a large team of volunteering translators (probably a lot
      like you) that translate the GNOME applications that they like into
      their native language. The GTP is divided into many language teams, all
      with their own team coordinator, and some with their own mailing list
      and website.
    </p>
    <p>
      To help us with Rhythmbox translations, we'd <em>really</em> like you
      to join the GTP and join your respective language team first. Joining
      is easy, what it takes is more
      or less just subscribing to some mailing lists. More on that below.
    </p>
    <p>
      There's a lot of reasons why we want you to do this. First of all, you
      will not be required to translate anything - it's all up to you, even
      if you join the GTP. Second, we'd really hate if there later was
      discovered that someone had done duplicate work - there might already
      be someone working on a Rhythmbox translation for your language, but
      there's no way to know until you have contacted your language team and
      asked if someone is already working on a
      translation. In most cases that's probably not the case, but asking
      first might save a lot of trouble later.
      Third, your translation team has people that probably have translated a
      lot of applications into your language before, and they can usually
      help you with any translation question (technical or linguistic) that
      you might have.
      Fourth, every translation team usually has at least one person with
      access to the GNOME CVS repository (where Rhythmbox translations are
      committed), and he/she
      can commit your finished translation directly into this CVS repository.
    </p>
    <p>
      Instructions on how to join the GTP are on the GTP web site, mentioned
      above. To join the GTP itself, you should (as mentioned on the GTP
      page) subscribe to the gnome-i18n@gnome.org mailing list. This can be
      done by going to:
    </p>
    <p>
      <a href="http://lists.gnome.org/mailman/listinfo/gnome-i18n/">http://lists.gnome.org/mailman/listinfo/gnome-i18n/</a>
    </p>
    <p>
      Subscribing to this mailing list will also make sure you get
      information when a new version of Rhythmbox will soon be released and
      the translations need updating.
    </p>
    <p>
      On the GTP site, you can also find information about existing language
      teams and their coordinators, and also web sites and mailing lists.
      Please let the coordinator for your language know that you will be
      working on a Rhythmbox translation. If there's a mailing list for the
      language team, consider joining it. That way you can ask other
      translators in your native language, if you have
      any problems when translating.
    </p>
    <h2>Getting the pot file</h2>
    <p>
      From now on I will assume that you have done the above, and joined the
      GTP and the team for your language. Now we come to the part on how to
      actually translate. You need at least one important software package
      installed on your system to be able to translate: "gettext". Please
      make sure that you have this package installed before you begin.
    </p>
    <p>
      To be able to start a new translation you need the application's
      untranslated messages, which is stored in a so called pot file (suffix
      .pot). The pot file for Rhythmbox can either be fetched from the web or
      generated from Rhythmbox source code taken from CVS or arch.
    </p>
    <h3>Fetching the pot file from the translation status pages</h3>
    <p>
      The easiest way to get the pot file is to fetch the pot file from the
      web. You'll find it on the GNOME translation status pages, located at:
    </p>
    <p>
      <a href="http://l10n.gnome.org/">http://l10n.gnome.org/</a>
    </p>
    <p>
      If you browse these pages you should find a reference to Rhythmbox and
      be able to download a pot file for it.
    </p>
    <h3>Generating the pot file from Rhythmbox source code in CVS</h3>
    <p>
      Another way of getting the pot file is by using anonymous GNOME CVS
      access. If you do intend to get the pot file this way you need to make
      sure that you have the software "intltool" installed on your computer.
      It should always be the latest available version; if it isn't, please
      upgrade before you begin.
    </p>
    <p>
      When you use CVS you need to checkout the "rhythmbox" module and
      go to the "po" directory of the module. Instructions on how to use
      anonymous GNOME CVS access are at:
    </p>
    <p>
      <a href="http://developer.gnome.org/tools/cvs.html">http://developer.gnome.org/tools/cvs.html</a>
    </p>
    <p>
      When you have checked out the module, go to the "po" directory inside
      it and run:
    </p>
    <pre>	intltool-update --pot
    </pre>
    <p>
      This should create the pot file for you.
    </p>
    <h2>Translating</h2>
    <p>
      Once you have the pot file, rename it to xy.po, where "xy" in the file
      name should be the language code of the language you are translating to
      (like "sv" for Swedish). Then it's just a matter of filling out the
      headers (if you are not sure about what the headers should be, ask your
      language team), and filling out the pairs:
    </p>
    <pre>      msgid "This is a message from the application."
      msgstr ""
    </pre>
    <p>
      In the example above, your translation should go inside the quotes
      after the msgstr. Proceed this way until all messages in the file have
      a translation. If you are unsure about anything regarding this, ask
      your language team.
    </p>
    <p>
      Once you have completed the translation, you should check
      that it is encoded in the "UTF-8" encoding (we require translations to
      be encoded in UTF-8). You can make sure the file is encoded in UTF-8 by
      running:
    </p>
    <pre>	msgconv -t UTF-8 xy.po &gt; xy.po.new &amp;&amp; mv xy.po.new xy.po
    </pre>
    <p>You should also make sure that the translation is syntactically
      correct. You can do that by doing this:
    </p>
    <pre>	msgfmt -cv xy.po
    </pre>
    <p>
      If there is any error, please go back and correct it before continuing.
      When all errors are gone, send the translation to a person in your
      language team that has GNOME CVS access, and ask him/her to please
      commit it. If you send the file by mail, it's usually a good idea to
      first compress the file with "gzip", since otherwise some mail software
      may do bad things and not preserve the encoding.
    </p>
    <p>
      That's it. If you have any questions regarding the PO format, gettext
      or translations, please ask your language team. If the question is
      specific to Rhythmbox (such as the messages themselves or Rhythmbox
      code), ask Rhythmbox
      developers.
    </p>
    <p>
      Thanks for your help!
    </p>
  </body>
</page>
