<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
]>

<sect1 id="rnadmins">
	<title>What's New For Administrators</title>

	<para>
		As of GNOME 2.14, the GNOME Project now releases an Administration Suite, which
		is a collection of tools that are aimed squarely at systems administrators. The
		two new tools that form the beginnings of this suite are incredibly powerful and
		should help administrators in both large corporate deployments and situations
		where machine lockdown is required.
	</para>

	<sect2 id="rnadmins-sabayon">
		<title>Sabayon - Profile Editor</title>

		<para>
			Sabayon allows administrators to set up user profiles inside a live,
			interactive GNOME session. When a profile is created or edited, a nested
			GNOME session is started up, which the administrator can use to change
			anything they would in their own GNOME session.
		</para>
		
		<figure id="rnadmins-figure-sabayon">
			<title>
				Sabayon editing a user profile
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-sabayon.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					Using Sabayon to edit a user profile in an embedded window
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<para>
			Sabayon will track changes to both files and GConf settings.
			The administrator can then choose to remove accidental changes, or make
			some of them mandatory rather than optional (e.g. lockdown and proxy
			settings). Once complete, the administrator can package up these profiles
			and deploy them to other machines.
		</para>

		<para>
			Users or groups (???) are placed into profiles which will be used when
			they log into their GNOME session. Being able to easily create multiple
			profiles and allocate each user separately allows users to have different
			setups based on their job description (eg. receptionist, data entry clerk,
			programmer, human resources manager, etc.).
		</para>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="rnadmins-pessulus">
		<title>Pessulus - Lockdown Editor</title>

		<para>
			Pessulus is a lockdown editor that allows administrators to easily
			disable certain features of the GNOME desktop, as may be
			desired in corporate environments and Internet cafés. While
			lockdown features have now been available in GNOME for many years,
			Pessulus makes it far easier for administrators to do.
		</para>

		<figure id="rnadmins-figure-pessulus">
			<title>
				Using the lockdown editor to prevent system shutdown by users
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-pessulus.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					Editing lockdown settings with pessulus
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		
		<para>
			Some of the features that can be disabled include:
		</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para>
				command-line access;
			</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>
				the ability to shutdown or reboot the machine;
			</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>
				access to specific protocols in the web browser; and
			</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>
				the ability to edit the GNOME panels.
			</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</sect2>

</sect1>
<!-- vi:set tw=80 ts=2: -->
