<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
]>

<sect1 id="rnusers">
	<title>What's New For Users</title>

	<sect2 id="rnusers-performance">
		<title>Performance Improvements</title>

		<para>
			Just as you would tune your car, GNOME's skilled engineers have worked
			hard to tune many parts of GNOME to be as fast as possible. Several
			important parts of the GNOME desktop are now measurably faster including
			font renderering, memory allocation and numerous individual applications.
			Faster font rendering and faster memory allocation for structures like
			list elements allows all GNOME and GTK+ applications to run faster without
			recompiling the application.
		</para>

		<para>
			Some applications have received special attention to make sure they are
			performing at their peak. GNOME Terminal, the terminal emulator for GNOME
			has been optimised so that it is faster and more resource efficent; not
			wasting valuable processessing time for updates you will never see on the
			screen.
		</para>

		<figure id="rnusers-performance-graph">
			<title>
				GNOME Terminal performance improvements between GNOME 2.12 and
				2.14. Time taken is the time to print the entire dictionary to the
				screen.
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-gnome-terminal-performance.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					GNOME Terminal performance improvements between GNOME 2.12 and GNOME
					2.14
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="rnusers-nautilus">
		<title>Richer Searching</title>

		<para>
			The GNOME file manager, Nautilus, now offers powerful search interface
			available by pressing <shortcut>Ctrl-F</shortcut> on the desktop or a file
			manager window.
		</para>
		
		<figure id="rnusers-nautilus-search">
			<title>
				Search with Nautilus
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-nautilus-search.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					Nautilus allows you to construct a search and save it later as a
					special folder
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<para>
			Searches are easily constructed and can then be saved in a folder or on
			the desktop. Saved searches can then be opened like a folder at a later
			date.
		</para>

		<para>
			If the Beagle searching framework is available, Nautilus will take
			advantage of it for faster, more contexual searching.
		</para>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="rnusers-yelp">
		<title>More Help</title>

		<para>
			The GNOME help browser also includes new features for searching help and
			documentation installed on your machine. Now with access to both GNU Info
			and traditional UNIX manpages, as well as GNOME's high quality
			documentation, it is possible to search most of the documentation included
			on your system quite rapidly.
		</para>

		<figure id="rnusers-yelp">
			<title>
				Search Help, view GNU Info files and read manpages
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-yelp.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					Yelp has new search features, as well as the ability to read
					GNU Info and UNIX manpages
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		<para>
			Like with the file browser, users who have the Beagle search framework
			available will be able to utilise it for even faster and more accurate
			searching.
		</para>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="rnusers-ekiga">
		<title>Ekiga</title>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="rnusers-metacity">
		<title>Improved Window Management</title>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="rnusers-deskbar">
		<title>Deskbar</title>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="rnusers-fusa">
		<title>Fast User Switching</title>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="rnusers-evolution">
		<title>Shared Calendaring</title>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="rnusers-gedit">
		<title>Better Editor</title>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="rnusers-screensaver">
		<title>Integrated Screensaver</title>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="rnusers-gstreamer">
		<title>Latest GStreamer</title>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="rnusers-control-center">
		<title>Stetic Configuration</title>
	</sect2>

</sect1>
<!-- vi:set tw=80 ts=2: -->
