<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1 PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY urlfiguresbase "figures/">
]>

<sect1 id="rnusers">
	<title>What's New For Users</title>

	<sect2 id="rnusers-performance">
		<title>Performance Improvements</title>

		<para>
			Just as you would tune your car, GNOME's skilled engineers have strived
			to tune many parts of GNOME to be as fast as possible. Several important
			components of the GNOME desktop are now measurably faster, including
			font renderering, memory allocation and numerous individual applications.
			Faster font rendering and faster memory allocation benefit all GNOME and
			GTK+ applications without the need to even recompile them.
		</para>

		<para>
			Some applications have received special attention to make sure they are
			performing at their peak. GNOME Terminal, the terminal emulator for the
			GNOME desktop, has been optimised in several ways so that it is faster
			and, at the same time, more resource efficient.
		</para>

		<para>
			Another example of enormous improvements in this direction is the GNOME
			Log Viewer: it now starts up over 20 times faster than its old version
			used to.
		</para>

		<figure id="rnusers-performance-graph">
			<title>
				GNOME Terminal performance improvements between GNOME 2.12 and
				2.14. Time taken is the time to print the entire dictionary to the
				screen.
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-gnome-terminal-performance.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					GNOME Terminal performance improvements between GNOME 2.12 and GNOME
					2.14
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<figure id="rnusers-performance-graph-2">
			<title>
				Log Viewer performance improvements between GNOME 2.12 and
				2.14: measurement of the time taken to start up the application.
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-system-log-performance.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					Log Viewer performance improvements between GNOME 2.12 and GNOME
					2.14
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>  
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="rnusers-nautilus">
		<title>Richer Searching</title>

		<para>
			The GNOME file manager, Nautilus, now offers powerful search interface
			available by pressing <shortcut>Ctrl-F</shortcut> on the desktop or a file
			manager window.
		</para>
		
		<figure id="rnusers-nautilus-search">
			<title>
				Search with Nautilus
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-nautilus-search.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					Nautilus allows you to construct a search and save it later as a
					special folder
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<para>
			Searches are easily constructed and can then be saved in a folder or on
			the desktop. Saved searches can then be opened like a folder at a later
			date.
		</para>

		<para>
			If the Beagle searching framework is available, Nautilus will take
			advantage of it for faster, more contexual searching.
		</para>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="rnusers-yelp">
		<title>More Help</title>

		<para>
			The GNOME help browser also includes new features for searching help and
			documentation installed on your machine. Now with access to both GNU Info
			and traditional UNIX manpages, as well as GNOME's high quality
			documentation, it is possible to search most of the documentation included
			on your system quite rapidly.
		</para>

		<figure id="rnusers-yelp">
			<title>
				Search Help, view GNU Info files and read manpages
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-yelp.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					Yelp has new search features, as well as the ability to read
					GNU Info and UNIX manpages
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		<para>
			Like with the file browser, users who have the Beagle search framework
			available will be able to utilise it for even faster and more accurate
			searching.
		</para>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="rnusers-ekiga">
		<title>Ekiga</title>

		<para>
			Ekiga, formerly known as GNOME Meeting is GNOME's voice and video over IP
			client. Ekiga supports both the SIP protocol, used in Google Talk,
			Asterisk and many other software and hardware VoIP devices; and H323, an
			older communications protocol used in Microsoft Netmeeting and some
			telecomms hardware.
		</para>

		<para>
			Ekiga also features STUN support to allow traversal through many types of
			firewalls, including Network Address Translating (NAT) firewalls. This
			means that you can use Ekiga to make and receive calls without having a
			public IP address or forwarding ports from your router.
		</para>

		<figure id="rnusers-figure-ekiga">
			<title>
				Making a SIP call with Ekiga
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-ekiga.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					Ekiga can handle both voice and video over SIP
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<para>
			Users can also get an account with
			<ulink url="http://ekiga.net">Ekiga.net</ulink> to give them a SIP address
			they can use on the Internet to make and receive calls from wherever they
			are.
		</para>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="rnusers-metacity">
		<title>Improved Window Management</title>

		<para>
			Several new features have been added to Metacity to improve window
			management. Window edges now have a magnetic attraction, making it
			possible to "click" windows together. Multiple monitor (head) handling has
			been improved in Metacity. Metacity will now attempt to displace windows
			that want to appear across a monitor boundry onto one monitor or the
			other.
		</para>

		<para>
			To help administrators and users of multiple machines from the same X
			server, Metacity will now give the hostname of windows not running locally
			in the title bar. This is especially useful when changing settings on
			machines graphically to ensure that you're making changes on the correct
			machine.
		</para>
		
		<figure id="rnusers-figure-metacity-remote">
			<title>
				Running an identical window locally and remotely
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-metacity-remote.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					XClock remotely, XClock locally
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="rnusers-deskbar">
		<title>Deskbar</title>
		<para>
			New to GNOME is the Deskbar. Power users, keyboard enthusiasts and users
			of the old panel command line will find this replacement incredibly
			powerful and easy to use. Deskbar uses plugins (written in Python) to
			provide search functionality for programs, files, folders, bookmarks,
			contacts and much more. Deskbar can also use the live search functionality
			of Google Live, Yahoo and Beagle.
		</para>

		<figure id="rnusers-figure-deskbar">
			<title>
				Searching for 'net'
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-deskbar.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					Deskbar shows a list of matches for 'net'
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<para>
			Deskbar has both an in-panel mode, and a collapsed mode for use on
			vertical panels or panels with little free space. To search you simply
			press <shortcut>Alt-F3</shortcut> and enter some terms. You can also
			browse or search your command history.
		</para>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="rnusers-fusa">
		<title>Fast User Switching</title>
		<para>
			GNOME 2.14 now includes support for fast user switching throughout the
			desktop. Both the logout dialog and unlock screen dialog will offer the
			option to switch user and a menu can be added to the panel allows fast
			access to user switching.
		</para>
		
		<figure id="rnusers-figure-fusa">
			<title>
				Fast user switching from the panel
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-fusa.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					A list of possible users you could switch to
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		
		<figure id="rnusers-figure-fusa-lock-screen-dialog">
			<title>
				Switch users from a locked session
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-lock-screen-dialog.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					Screensaver lock dialog allows you to switch user
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="rnusers-evolution">
		<title>Shared Calendaring</title>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="rnusers-epiphany">
		<title>Smarter Bookmarking</title>

		<para>
			The lighter Epiphany Web Browser continues to improve usability for the web.
			New in this release is the automatic construction of bookmark hierarchies,
			reducing the burden of large bookmark collections but retaining the simpler 
			topic system of bookmark management. Topics are now easier to select and
			and create, and Epiphany will even suggest topics based on past usage.
		</para>

		<figure id="rnusers-epiphany">
			<title>
				Improved bookmark management and stylesheet control.
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						fileref="&urlfiguresbase;figure-epiphany.png"
						format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject><phrase>
					Epiphany now builds hierarchical bookmark menus from your topics,
					and gives the user control over page presentation.
				</phrase></textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		<para>
			Epiphany also now supports user-defined stylesheets and dedicated zoom buttons,
			improving accessibility and user control over page presentation. Behind the scenes
			Epiphany can now use Firefox, Mozilla, or XULRunner, and will talk to NetworkManager
			directly to know when you're online or offline.
		</para>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="rnusers-gedit">
		<title>Better Editor</title>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="rnusers-screensaver">
		<title>Integrated Screensaver</title>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="rnusers-gstreamer">
		<title>Latest GStreamer</title>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="rnusers-control-center">
		<title>Stetic Configuration</title>
	</sect2>

</sect1>
<!-- vi:set tw=80 ts=2: -->
