<bounties>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[National, religious, event calendars]]></title>  <amount>15</amount> <category>Calendar</category>
<bug>127528</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

<p>In Evolution 2.0, users can aggregate multiple simultaneous
calendar sources into a single view.  This means that you can overlay
group calendars and other people's calendars into your own calendar
view, which helps you keep others in mind while you schedule your
life.  The various backend calendars can even be color-coded in the
calendar view.</p>

<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="evo-webcal-1.png"><img align=right border=0 src="evo-webcal-1-small.png" alt=""></a>

<p>We would like Evolution to ship with a large number of calendars
containing the schedules for national holidays, religious holidays,
and other events of general interest.  For example, calendars of
sporting events or a Linux conference schedule would be neat.</p>

<p>Because Evolution 2.0 allows you to specify a URL to a calendar, it
is even possible for these to be hosted online and cached locally.
This might be useful for things like the GNOME release schedule.</p>

<?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>

This task probably won't involve patching any existing modules, though
we will include any accepted calendars in the <? bonsai ("evolution"); ?> module.

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>

<p>Find and check the schedules for various types of events, and create a
calendar in the standard iCal format.  Submit the calendar file or
files, along with a short description, to <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="mailto:evolution-patches@ximian.com">evolution-patches@ximian.com</a>.</p>

<p>Until Evolution provides an 'Export' mechanism, the files should be
copied (if created in Evolution) from the Evolution2.0 tree, that is
<code>~/.evolution/calendar/local/OnThisComputer/"name"</code>, where
"name" is the name of the calendar you created.  If created in
Evolution 1.4, the file to copy is
<code>~/evolution/local/Calendar/subfolders/"name"</code>.</p>

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

The following links might be helpful:

<ul>
<li><a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://lists.ximian.com/mailman/listinfo/evolution">Evolution users list</a></li>
<li><a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://www.icalshare.com/">Apple's iCalShare site</a></li>
<li><?php rfc(2445); ?>, the iCalendar specification</li>
<li>The <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="#28528410">calendar publication</a> task is obviously somewhat related.</li>
</ul>

Please note that downloading proprietary <tt>.ical</tt> files and
submitting them is <i>not acceptable</i>.  To collect this bounty, you
must provide an unencumbered, freely-licensed (X11) iCalendar file.

<?php box_sec ("Special Note"); ?>

The bounty for this task is per-calendar.  We will pay bounties for up
to 30 calendars.</p>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>


<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Panel clock/calendar integration]]></title>  <amount>1000</amount> <category>Calendar</category>
<bug>127532</bug> <solved>http://www.gnome.org/~markmc/clock-evo-integration.diff</solved>
<html><![CDATA[
<p>When you click on the clock on the GNOME panel, a little calendar
descends.  A proper integration patch for this calendar would do the
following:</p>
<img border=0 align=right src="panel-calendar.png" alt="">

<ul> 
<li>Highlight in bold the days which have appointments.</li><br>
<li>Below the calendar, show a small summary of the appointments on the selected day.</li><br>
<li>Double clicking on a day opens the Evolution calendar to that day.</li><br>
<li>Aggregate multiple calendars, with a configuration dialog to select which calendars to aggregate.</li><br>
<li>Redo the QuickAlarm frame <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://patches.ximian.com/download.cgi?object=gnome-panel-clock.patch-3">patch</a> to take up less space.</li>
</ul>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>

There is code in gnome-cal.c and tag-calendar.c which is in <? bonsai
("evolution/calendar/gui/"); ?> to tag the mini calendar in Evolution,
which should serve as a useful starting point.  Essentially you will
need to create an ECalView (see <?php bonsai
("evolution-data-server/calendar/libecal"); ?>, and monitor it to
track the changes.  You can create a different ECalView for the
current day to get the list of events for the day and monitor them if
there are changes.

 <?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>
 
The clock applet is part of the <? bonsai ("gnome-panel"); ?> 
module. You will need to make use of the new calendar APIs in <?
bonsai ("evolution-data-server/calendar/libecal"); ?>.

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

You may find this <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="clock-calendar.tar.bz2">glade mockup</a> useful.

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Birthday and anniversary calendar backend]]></title>  <amount>500</amount> <category>Calendar</category>
<bug>127535</bug> <solved>http://lists.ximian.com/archives/public/evolution-patches/2004-January/004082.html</solved>
<html><![CDATA[

<p>Evolution's contact editor allows you to annotate a contact with
the dates of their birthday and anniversary.  However, these dates <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="contact-bday.png"><img border=0 align=right
src="contact-bday-thumb.png" alt=""></a> don't automatically copy themselves
into your calendar.  Unless you explicitly add the dates to your
calendar, you won't see them when you glance through your schedule,
and an alarm won't fire to warn you of a friend's upcoming
birthday.</p>

<p>Clearly, this is a travesty.</p>

<p>The right solution is to create a special calendar backend which
reads birthdays and anniversaries out of the user's addressbook.
Using Evolution 2.0's calendar aggregation feature, the user can then
overlay a friend's important life events into the calendar view by
clicking a single checkbox.</p>

<?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>

The only module affected will be <? bonsai ("evolution"); ?>.

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

Start by joining the <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://lists.ximian.com/mailman/listinfo/evolution-hackers">Evolution
Hackers</a> mailing list.

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Gaim/addressbook identity integration]]></title>  <amount>2500</amount> <category>Addressbook</category>
<bug>127513</bug> <solved>http://www.chipx86.com/gevolution/</solved>
<html><![CDATA[


<p>Gaim should be able to synchronize its buddy lists with the
Evolution addressbook. You will need to decide the details of this
work and discuss them with the other Gaim and Evolution
developers. Some beginning features:</p>

<ul>
<li>Auto-add buddies to your buddy list if their IM fields exist in  Evolution.</li>
<li>Auto-add buddies to your addressbook when you add them to your buddy list in Gaim. 
<li>Allow a user to select an addressbook entry that corresponds to a
buddy, which will fill the IM field of that addressbook entry. This
might work better if you can use the minicard widget and display a
list of minicards.</li>
<li>For extra credit: Allow the user to drag and drop buddies and
contacts between Gaim and Evolution.</li>
</ul>

<p>When the user clicks on the "Add Buddy" button in Gaim, or selects
the "Add a buddy" menu item, a dialog should appear allowing him to
select someone from his addressbook:</p>

<center>
<img src="IM-addbuddy1.png"><br>
</center>

<p>A separate entry should appear for each IM account a contact has,
so that the user can choose to add someone's AIM account to the buddy
list, for example, but not his Yahoo account.</p>

<p>If the user clicks on the "New Person" button, he gets prompted to
add a new contact and buddy at the same time:</p>

<center>
<img src="IM-addbuddy2.png"><br>
</center>

<p>Entering the contact's IM account information is required.
Entering his contact information is optional.</p>

<p>This same dialog will pop up if the user hits "Select Buddy" for a
contact whose IM information is not available in the Evolution
addressbook.  The user will have the opportunity to fill in the IM
information for that person, which will then be added to the Evolution
addressbook and the buddy list at the same time.</p>

<center>
<img src="IM-addbuddy3.png"><br>
</center>

<p>When "Add Buddy" is clicked, the person's IM account name is added to
the buddy list, and a new contact is added to the Evolution
addressbook.</p>

<?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>

Both <? bonsai ("evolution"); ?> and <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://gaim.sf.net/">gaim</a> are affected.

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

For Evolution information, join the <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://lists.ximian.com/mailman/listinfo/evolution-hackers">Evolution
Hackers</a> mailing list.  You'll find Gaim resources at <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://gaim.sf.net">the Gaim home page</a>.

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Gaim/Evolution presence integration]]></title>  <amount>2000</amount> <category>IM</category>
<bug>127546</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

<p>We want the notion of &quot;presence&quot; to be integrated into
the entire desktop, wherever the user encounters a person or a
reference to a person.</p>

<p>Providing a simple integrated presence concept in the mailer and
addressbook user interfaces is a step in this direction.</p>

<p>Post-2.0, Evolution will begin to integrate presence functionality
into the backend addressbook APIs.  That means that given a contact,
you'll be able to programmatically ask the addressbook questions like:
&quot;Is this user online?&quot; and &quot;How can I send him a
file?&quot;</p>

<p>That is our eventual goal.  This task is focused on more surface,
frontend integration.</p>

<p>This item has several subtasks, all of which involve displaying an
icon somewhere in Evolution to indicate whether a person is online or
not, and to allow the user to click on this icon to open an IM
conversation window with the person concerned.</p>

<p>And so, the first challenge is to have a simple, general mechanism
for displaying <b>presence icons</b>.</p>

<table border=1 align=right>
<tr>
<td width="33%"><center><img border=0 src="buddy-online.png" alt="Online icon"><br><tt>online</tt></center></td>
<td width="33%"><center><img border=0 src="buddy-offline.png" alt="Offline icon"><br><tt>offline</tt></center></td>
<td width="33%"><center><img border=0 src="buddy-away.png" alt="Away icon"><br><tt>away</tt></center></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan=3><i><font size=-4>You don't have to use exactly these icons or exactly these meanings. This is just to give a general idea, and an example of what to use in case the user doesn't have a buddy icon set. We can design better suitable icons if needed.</font></i></td>
</tr>
</table>

<p>The presence icon could be the "Buddy Icon" from Gaim. It
represents the other person well since everyone can control and update
their own buddy-icon.  We can show online/offline/away status with a
text label below the icon, plus for "away" we can desaturate the icon
and make it 50% transparent.  Examples are below.</p>

<p align=center><img src="online-offline-evo.png" alt=""></p>

<p>The Presence Icon can be used to invoke the appropriate gaim-remote
mechanisms to pop up an IM window with the user.</p>

<p>Evolution 2.0's addressbook allows the user to set a custom picture
for an addressbook entry.  This custom image should override the buddy
icon if it is set.</p>

Here are the places where a presence icon should be added to
Evolution:

<ol>

<li>In the message view (the window or pane displaying the contents of
a single mail message), display a full-size presence icon next to the
sender's name.<br>

<p align="center"><img src="imstatus-mailmessage.png" alt=""></p></li>

<li>Put a small presence icon next to names in the To:, Cc: and Bcc:
fields in the message composer window.  Buddy icons should also appear
for the relevant names in the recipient picker dialog, message
summaries, and preview panes.  Anywhere that currently displays "Foo
Bar &lt;foo@bar.com&gt;" could be extended to display "[ ] Foo Bar
&lt;foo@bar.com&gt;".  And again, clicking on these icons should pop
up a small floating dialog (like you get when right clicking an email
address in evolution) - and it lists you actions for sending IM messages
and such.<br>

<p align="center"><img src="imstatus-mailcomposer.gif" alt=""></p></li>

<li> Add a presence status field to the address book, so that the user
knows when a contact is online via IM, and can click to send an
instant message.  This field should be viewable in the minicard view
as the contact's buddy icon, in the list view as a separate column,
and in the contact editor dialog.</li>

</ol>

<?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>

Both <? bonsai ("evolution"); ?> and <? bonsai ("gaim"); ?> are affected.

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>

<p> 

First you will need to allow Evolution to determine if someone is
online. You may wish to work with <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://cvs.sourceforge.net/viewcvs.py/gaim/gaim/src/gaim-remote.c?view=markup"><tt>gaim-remote</tt></a>,
a command-line tool which communicates with a running gaim process
over a local Unix domain socket.  </p>

<p>You will want to extend the <tt>gaim-remote</tt> protocol to
support the &quot;<tt>ison</tt>&quot; mechanism.  You may also want to
separate <tt>gaim-remote</tt> into a library, maybe called
<tt>libgaimremote</tt> and a front-end command line tool.  Evolution
and <tt>gaim-remote</tt> will both use <tt>libgaimremote</tt>, which
should expose a non-blocking API.</p>

<p>On top of this library, you will want to build a widget which
handles all the rendering and interaction associated with a presence
icon.  This widget could probably exist inside Evolution at first,
though eventually it would be ideal if it were available to the entire
desktop.</p>

<p>Then you need to use this API to add the icons to various places where
addresses are displayed and formatted, including:
<p>
<dl>

<dt><?php bonsai ("evolution/addressbook/gui/component/select-names"); ?></dt>

<dd>This is used by the mail composer for the to/cc/bcc entry
widgets.  This will need to be extended to include the presence widget
for each name entered.
</dd>

<dt><?php bonsai ("evolution/mail/e-format-html-display.c"); ?></dt>
<dd>This formats messages for display.  You will have to output a tag
for a custom object, and in the object return handler, setup the
presence widget.
<b>NOTE:</b> All formatting operations are
done from a separate thread so no non-formatting logic can be
performed there.
</dd>
</dl>

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

For Evolution information, join the <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://lists.ximian.com/mailman/listinfo/evolution-hackers">Evolution
Hackers</a> mailing list.  You'll find Gaim resources at <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://gaim.sf.net">the Gaim home page</a>.

Some fun presence-related links, for your amusement:

<ul>
<li><a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://www.nwfusion.com/links/Encyclopedia/P/802.html">general information</a> </li>
<li><a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://www.aiai.ed.ac.uk/project/akt/coakting/documents/2002/wace02-figs/presence-radar.jpg">presence radar</a></li>
<li><a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://research.sun.com/research/netcomm/rhythmAwareness.html">rhythm awareness</a></li>
</ul>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Improve Nautilus &quot;Send to...&quot; feature]]></title>  <amount>1500</amount> <category>Miscellaneous</category>
<bug>127551</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

<p> The Nautilus file manager has a context menu item for "Send
to...", which opens the Evolution composer to mail a selected file to
someone.  This task involves implementing three major improvements to
this feature:

<ol>

<li>If you select multiple files, Nautilus should automatically prompt
you to create an archive (zip, tar, etc - user's choice) and mail that
instead.</li>

<li>Allow the user to send the files to another user over IM instead of
email. The user should be prompted to select an online buddy from the 
buddy list.  Be sure to only display the buddies can accept
file transfers.</li>

<li>Provide a recipient selection dialog that does name and address
completion.</li>

</ol>

Below is an animated mockup of a "Send to..." dialog that incorporates
all these improvements, and has a nice completion mechanism.

<p align=center><img border=0 src="send_file-anim-mockup.gif" alt=""></p>

<p>If the user has selected only one file and it is not a directory,
then we can present him with a simpler dialog including only the
recipient and the medium:</p>

<p align=center><img border=0 src="send_file_single.gif" alt=""></p>

<p>After the user clicks "Send" he gets either a IM "send file" dialog
or a mail composer window with the file(s) attached.</p>

<p>To implement this feature nicely, you may want to integrate with
file roller for the archive creation.  And you should in some way
indicate the total size of the compressed archive or file being sent
to the user.</p>

<?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>

<? bonsai ("nautilus"); ?>, <? bonsai ("evolution"); ?>, <? bonsai ("gaim"); ?> and <? bonsai ("file-roller"); ?>.  See our general note about <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="gaim.php">gaim extension</a>.

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

Check the <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://lists.gnome.org/mailman/listinfo/nautilus-list">Nautilus</a>
mailing list, as well as <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://lists.ximian.com/mailman/listinfo/evolution-hackers">Evolution
Hackers</a>, and visit <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://gaim.sf.net">the Gaim home page</a>.

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Addressbook/videoconferencing integration]]></title>  <amount>500</amount> <category>Addressbook</category>
<bug>127515</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

The desktop environment's central addressbook should be able to store
information about how to reach a given person via videoconferencing.
This involves two tasks:

<ul>
<li>Allow <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://www.gnomemeeting.org/">GnomeMeeting</a> to store the location information for a user in
the appropriate Evolution addressbook entry.</li><br>

<li>Add UI to the Evolution addressbook to allow a user to open a
videoconference with the contact.</li>
</ul>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>
<p>

You'll need to add fields to the Evolution addressbook that can
contain the videoconferencing coordinates for a person.  The <? bonsai
("gnomemeeting"); ?> code will need to be modified to use the
Evolution addressbook as its addressbook store.  </p>

<p>You will also need to add UI to Evolution's addressbook to allow
the user to start a videoconference from a contact.  This may also
require extending GnomeMeeting to enable videoconferences to be
programmatically started, and to create an interface that will report
whether a user is online and accepting videoconference calls.</p>

<?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>

<? bonsai ("evolution"); ?> and <? bonsai ("gnomemeeting"); ?>.

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

Begin with the <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://www.gnomemeeting.org/">GnomeMeeting home page</a> and the
list <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://lists.gnome.org/mailman/listinfo/gnomemeeting-devel-list">gnomemeeting-devel-list@gnome.org</a>.
You'll also want to subscribe to the <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://lists.ximian.com/mailman/listinfo/evolution-hackers">evolution-hackers</a>
mailing list.

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[&quot;Me&quot;]]></title>  <amount>300</amount> <category>Addressbook</category>
<bug>127517</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

<p>The Evolution 2.0 addressbook will have a "me" concept that will
allow programs to get the contact entry that corresponds to the user.
This should be integrated across the desktop, wherever extensive user
information (name, email address, etc) is needed or entered.</p>

<p>A couple of places where other applications could use this data:</p>
<ul>
<li>Web forms, via Epiphany's form autofill feature.</li>
<li>Document author fields in OpenOffice.</li>
</ul>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>
<p>
<? bonsai ("evolution-data-server/addressbook/libebook"); ?> contains
the function <tt>e_book_get_self</tt>, which can be used to retrieve
the contact associated with the user.  From there you can use the
methods on <tt>EContact</tt> to retrieve the bits of information you
need.
</p>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Planner (formerly MrProject) integration]]></title>  <amount>300</amount> <category>Addressbook</category>
<bug>127520</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

<p>There are lots of things that could be done here, though they might
require some extensions to Evolution:</p>

<ul>
<li>Automatically use the "me" tool from Evolution (see previous challenge).</li>
<li>Choose project resources from your addressbook.</li>
<li>Synchronize with the Evolution tasks (requires the subtask
feature in Evolution, which will probably be available in the Evolution 2.2 time frame.</li>
<li>Do task assignment through iMIP (requires polishing Evolution's task assignment code). </li>
<li>Automatically fill in local task status from iMIP messages received in Evolution.</li>
</ul>

<?php box_sec ("Modules Affected"); ?>
 

Both <? bonsai ("evolution"); ?> and  <? bonsai ("mrproject"); ?>.

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>
 

<p>
Start with <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://www.imendio.com/projects/planner">the Planner
home page</a>. You will need to work with both Planner and Evolution
developers. Both coding and communication skills will be crucial with
this challenge.
</p>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Set wallpaper from mailer]]></title>  <amount>100</amount> <category>Mailer</category>
<bug>127514</bug> <solved>http://bugzilla.gnome.org/showattachment.cgi?attach_id=22642</solved>
<html><![CDATA[

<p>
It would be handy to be able to set the desktop background picture
directly from images displayed in Evolution.
</p>

<p align="center"><img src="set-as-wallpaper.png" alt="" /></p>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>

<p>
In em-popup.c there is already a hook for this, but unimplemented (see
emp_part_popup_set_background).  The menu item will automatically be
added to any image or image attachment referenced from a context menu.
The guts merely needs to be implemented.
</p>
<ul>
<li>You have access to the message part in the EMPopupTarget of type EM_POPUP_TARGET_PART of the popup target.
<li>There are message saving routines in em-utils.[ch], although you may need to add a new api
to save to a specific file, if GNOME wont copy a temporary file
<li>You then need to notify the GNOME Desktop of the new backdrop file (how?)
</ul>

<?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>

<? bonsai ("evolution/mail") ?>

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

<p>
You should subscribe to the <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://lists.ximian.com/mailman/listinfo/evolution-hackers">
evolution-hackers</a> mailing list, and discuss any technical issues
there.  Michael Zucchi &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="mailto:notzed@ximian.com">notzed@ximian.com</a>&gt; and Jeffrey
Stedfast &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="mailto:fejj@ximian.com">fejj@ximian.com</a>&gt;
will be the primary contacts on the list.
<p>
GNOME Desktop programming and mailing list information is available on
<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://developer.gnome.org/">developer.gnome.org</a>
</p>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Implement a panel notification applet for new mail]]></title>  <amount>400</amount> <category>Mailer</category>
<bug>127516</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

<p>
An often requested feature has been to have new mail notified via the panel.
</p>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>

<p>
There are two parts to this task. The first is to write a panel applet
component for the user interface.  This should be incorporated into
the mail code (as em-panel-applet.c), and it should attempt to insert
itself into the panel notification area when the mailer starts up.
The applet should be started from mail-component-factory.c and be
configurable in the usual manner.
</p>
<p align="center"><img alt="" src="email-notification.gif" /></p>
<p>
The second part is to hook into new mail events.  Currently all new
mail events are routed (from multiple threads) through
mail-folder-cache.c, so it can trivially be hooked up into the appropriate
place in the real_flush_updates function in that file.
</p><p>
This code should also either merge with or replace the current new
mail notification code in mail-folder-cache.c and the preferences
pages.  The original functionality must work if there are no panels running
in the current session and the applet is not started.
</p>

<?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>

<? bonsai ("evolution/mail"); ?>

<?php box_sec ("Extended functionality"); ?>

<p>
It would be nice to only watch specific folders or stores rather than
all folders.  This could re-use the folder selector widget and
configuration mechanism as used for offline mode selection.  It would
probably be appropriate to support drag and drop of folders from the
folder list onto the applet to add/remove them from the list of
watched folders.
<p>
Another extension would be to use different
colors/methods/sounds to indicate the new mail depending on the
folder/store or priority of the folder.  This is all applet-specific code.
<p>

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

<p>
You should subscribe to the <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://lists.ximian.com/mailman/listinfo/evolution-hackers">
evolution-hackers</a> mailing list, and discuss any technical issues
there.  Michael Zucchi &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="mailto:notzed@ximian.com">notzed@ximian.com</a>&gt; and Jeffrey
Stedfast &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="mailto:fejj@ximian.com">fejj@ximian.com</a>&gt;
will be the primary contacts on the list.
</p>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Mailing list actions]]></title> <amount>500</amount> <category>Mailer</category>
<bug>127518</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

<p>Many mailing lists follow <?php rfc(2369); ?> and provide mailing list
information in their email headers.  This information can be used by
mail clients to present mailing list management functions to users.
For example, a mailing list can provide information on unsubscribing
from the list.

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>

<p>
The RFC gives these actions:
<ul>
<li>Unsubscribe - How to remove yourself from the list.
<li>Subscribe - How to subscribe to the list.  (Helpful for forwarded messages.)
<br><br>
<li>Help - How to get more information about the mailing list.
<li>Owner - The contact information for the list administrator.
<li>Archive - Access to the list archives.
<br><br>
<li>Post - How to post to the list.
</ul>
<p>

Note that the formats of these fields can vary widely and may contain multiple URLs or actions which provide the same result.  Also, there is no reason to expect that a mailing list which includes one or more mailing list headers will include all of them.
<p>
Evolution should provide an interface to these actions.  If any of these headers are present in a message, Evolution should present them in a "List" submenu off the "Actions" menu.  A successful patch to Evolution should follow the usability guidelines mentioned in the RFC.
<p>
The only special action is "Post."  If a mailing list has a "Post" header of "NO" then posting is not allowed on this list.  Replies to this message should only go to the message sender; the "Reply to List" menu item should be disabled.  The "Reply to List" menu item should always follow the "Post" header clue.  <tt>EMFolderView</tt> manages these menus.
<p align="center">
<img alt="" src="ml-headers.gif" /> 
</p>

<?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>

<p>The mail component, <?php bonsai("evolution/mail"); ?>.</p>

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

For Evolution information, join the <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://lists.ximian.com/mailman/listinfo/evolution-hackers">Evolution
Hackers</a> mailing list.

]]>

</html>
</bounty>


<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Finish NNTP support in Evolution]]></title>  <amount>750</amount> <category>Mailer</category>
<bug>127519</bug> <solved>http://home.wanadoo.nl/meilof/evolution-nntp-patch-17</solved>
<html><![CDATA[

<p>
Evolution has some initial NNTP (NEWS, or NNRP) support, but it is incomplete.
This task is to fill out the NNTP implementation and provide a
suitable user-interface for managing NNTP sessions.
<p>
This would help us get more adoption of Evolution inside the
OpenOffice team, since they use news for all their internal
discussions.
</p>

<?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>

<ul>
<li><? bonsai ("evolution/camel/providers/nntp"); ?>, is the existing
NNTP implementation, which should be extended/completed, rather than
being rewritten.
<li><? bonsai ("evolution/mail"); ?>, may need work for handling NNTP addressing.
<li><? bonsai ("evolution/composer"); ?>, similarly.
</ul>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>

<p>
The first aim should be to complete the CamelStore and CamelFolder
implementation of the NNTP provider.
<p>
For CamelNNTPStore, the folder list should be stored in a
CamelStoreSummary, which will require writing a CamelNNTPStoreSummary in
the same vein as CamelImapStoresummary.  It should support two modes,
one for a flat '.' separated list of folders, and another implementing
a hierarchy of folders canonicalized into '/' separated paths.
Once complete, offline operation, and the subscription interface can be implemented.
<tt>get_folder_info</tt> must also be finished, currently it doesn't
honor the path or mode arguments.
<p>
CamelNNTPFolder needs to have the append() method
implemented, which will be used to POST messages to the NNTP store.
<p>
The composer already has support for posting to folders, but it may
need additional support for NNTP addressing and cross-posting to NNTP
folders and email addresses.
</p>

<?php box_sec ("Extended functionality"); ?>

<p>CamelNNTPStoreSummary could also interact and cache standard NNTP
folder information into ~/.newsrc, to work with legacy news readers.
</p>

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

<p>
The NNTP protocol is described in <?php rfc(977); ?>.  An
additional information RFC, <?php rfc(2980); ?> provides an
overview of commonly implemented NNTP extensions.
<p>
You should subscribe to the <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://lists.ximian.com/mailman/listinfo/evolution-hackers">
evolution-hackers</a> mailing list, and discuss any technical issues
there.  Michael Zucchi &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="mailto:notzed@ximian.com">notzed@ximian.com</a>&gt; and Jeffrey
Stedfast &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="mailto:fejj@ximian.com">fejj@ximian.com</a>&gt;
will be the primary contacts on the list.
</p>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Inline PGP support for evolution]]></title>  <amount>250</amount> <category>Mailer</category>
<bug>127521</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

<p>
An often requested feature for Evolution is to support inline-pgp
('clearsigned') secure emails, in addition to the PGP-MIME format we
already support.  This will aid interoperability with legacy
secure-mail implementations.
<p>
See bugs <?php bug(17540); ?>, and <?php bug(17541); ?>.
</p>

<?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>

<ul>
<li><? bonsai ("evolution/mail") ?> will require changes to recognize
inline pgp armoring and for formatting signature info.
<li><? bonsai ("evolution/camel") ?> contains pgp verification code.
</ul>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>

<p>
<tt>mail/em-inline-filter.c</tt> already has code (some commented out)
to identify and separate inline pgp messages into separate
CamelMimePart objects.  This needs to be activated, and the content type (in
<tt>emif_types[]</tt> needs to be changed to something unique
(&quot;application/x-inline-pgp&quot; perhaps?).
<p>
<tt>mail/em-format-html-display.c</tt> then needs to be modified to
handle that mime-type (see <tt>type_builtin_table</tt>).  It should use
similar code to <tt>efhd_application_xpkcs7mime</tt> or
<tt>efhd_multipart_signed</tt>, and should share common code where
appropriate.  Some of this code is currently undergoing changes, so
discuss this on the lists first.
<p>
Finally, you need to support this (pseudo) mime-type in
<tt>camel/camel-gpg-context.c:gpg_verify</tt>.  It already has code to
test the mime type of the incoming part, this just needs to be
extended to execute a different code path for the inline-pgp type.  It
may also need additional support in the <tt>gpg_ctx</tt> engine (in
the same file).
</p>

<?php box_sec ("Extended functionality"); ?>

<p>
Allow the sending of ASCII armored PGP (aka inline pgp) messages too.
This requires adding the support for inline signing to
<tt>camel-gpg-context.c</tt>, and passing the option to it from the
security configuration page via the composer signing code in
<tt>composer/e-msg-composer.c:build_message</tt>.  See the way
<tt>camel-smime-context.c</tt> implements it's <tt>sign_mode</tt>
option for how this should be done.
</p>

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

<p>
You should subscribe to the <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://lists.ximian.com/mailman/listinfo/evolution-hackers">
evolution-hackers</a> mailing list, and discuss any technical issues
there.  Michael Zucchi &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="mailto:notzed@ximian.com">notzed@ximian.com</a>&gt; and Jeffrey
Stedfast &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="mailto:fejj@ximian.com">fejj@ximian.com</a>&gt;
will be the primary contacts on the list.
<p>
<?php rfc(2298); ?> contains details of the OpenPGP message format,
although much of the detail beyond ASCII armoring (section 6.2)
is not relevant.
</p>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Personal Security Services]]></title>  <amount>0</amount> <category>Ignore</category>

<html><![CDATA[
<p>
Evolution has integrated support for digital certificate management and
related crypto and security services based on the Mozilla Project's
NSS.  These could be exported using a common api to provide a central
crypto and security service for all applications.
<p>
<em>Note: This may compete/conflict with the SeaHorse effort and may not
be appropriate in terms of community conflict</em>
</p>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Custom mail headers display]]></title>  <amount>200</amount> <category>Mailer</category>
<bug>127523</bug> <solved>http://lists.ximian.com/archives/public/evolution-patches/2003-December/003697.html</solved>
<html><![CDATA[

<p>As in <?php bug(1186); ?>, it would be nice to configure the header
display to show different default headers, merely as a convenience to
users.</p>

<p align="center">
<img border=0 src="mail-custom-header.png" alt="">
</p>

<?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>

<p>
Various files in <? bonsai ("evolution/mail"); ?>.
</p>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>

<p>
EMFormat already has api for setting which headers are displayed
by default, so most of the backend work is already done.  What is
required is a GUI for configuring the options, and glue to store the
options.
<p>
The configuration GUI should be a new tab on the Mailer Settings page.
A new tab should be created in the glade file
<? bonsai ("evolution/mail/mail-config.glade"); ?>, and hooked into
<? bonsai ("evolution/mail/em-mailer-prefs.c"); ?>, and it should store
the options in a gconf key under &quot;/apps/evolution/mail/display&quot;, for
example <b>&quot;headers&quot;</b>.  The key should be a simple string
array.
<p>
<? bonsai ("evolution/mail/em-folder-view.c"); ?> is used to listen to
configuration changes used by EMFormat, <tt>emfv_setting_notify</tt> needs to
be extended to include the new gconf key to manage the header list.
<p>
A FIXME in
<? bonsai ("evolution/mail/em-format.c"); ?><tt>:emf_format_clone</tt>
needs to be finished to complete the task so the headers displayed are
properly honored for printing and redisplays.
</p>

<?php box_sec ("Extended functionality"); ?>

<p>EMFormat (and EMFormatHTML) also defines properties for each
header (e.g. <b>BOLD LABEL</b>).  These could be added to the
configuration page and configuration key, and even extended.
</p>

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

<p>
You should subscribe to the <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://lists.ximian.com/mailman/listinfo/evolution-hackers">
evolution-hackers</a> mailing list, and discuss any technical issues
there.  Michael Zucchi &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="mailto:notzed@ximian.com">notzed@ximian.com</a>&gt; and Jeffrey
Stedfast &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="mailto:fejj@ximian.com">fejj@ximian.com</a>&gt;
will be the primary contacts on the list.
</p>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Contact search applet]]></title>  <amount>750</amount> <category>Addressbook</category>
<bug>127522</bug> <solved>http://www.burtonini.com/computing/contact-lookup-applet-0.4.tar.gz</solved>
<html><![CDATA[

<p>
A panel applet where you can type in a search term and get matching contact cards. The
applet should reside in its own package, not in Evolution proper.
</p>

<img src="address-applet-anim.gif">

<p>
Once the wanted person is found in the list, one can click on it and the following
popup window is shown with the address card and some relevant action buttons.
</p>

<img src="address-applet-popup.png">

<p>
If the user is not online, one should just display the label as <b>"GFlash is not online."</b>
</p>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>

Most of this task revolves around writing a panel applet and GUI. The rest involves contacting
<? bonsai ("evolution-data-server"); ?>, and getting contact information from that. A useful starting point
is <? bonsai ("evolution-data-server/addressbook/libebook"); ?>, and the interfaces you'll find there.

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Support export of tasks or other items to Excel (CSV)]]></title>  <amount>300</amount> <category>Tasks</category>
<bug>127557</bug>
<html><![CDATA[



<p>
Currently, Evolution does not have any data export features, because
it uses standard file formats which other applications can
import. However, task list data is not easy to import into
spreadsheets or project management tools, and it should be.
</p>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>
 

<p>
The difficult part of this task will be altering the task storage
format to include a task ID field, which will match the WBS or "work
breakdown structure" code in a project management program. Once you
have that, the export to a CSV export should be relatively simple.
</p>

<?php box_sec ("Modules Affected"); ?>
 

Just <? bonsai ("evolution"); ?>.

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Allow custom task fields]]></title>  <amount>0</amount> <category>Ignore</category>

<html><![CDATA[
FIXME: Blah blah blah.
]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Choice of database for contacts back-end]]></title>  <amount>250</amount> <category>Addressbook</category>
<bug>127524</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

<p>
  Some people or system administrators want to use a local address
  back-end that is not the default (db3). The most popular request is
  SQLite, but a generalized SQL interface would be best.
</p>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>
 

<p>
  You will need to choose or design a database schema to match the
  Evolution addressbook, and then write wrappers to translate the
  Evolution addressbook manipulation functions to your choice of
  database. It is acceptable to leave database selection as an option
  'hidden' in gconf-editor. For the implementation,
  <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://www.gnome-db.org">libgda</a> seems the best choice
  for the database access part, since it allows access to many different
  database backends (PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite, SQL Server, Oracle, etc)
  and offers a rich data management API.
</p>

<?php box_sec ("Modules Affected"); ?>

You'll be working on <? bonsai ("evolution-data-server"); ?>, writing a new
addressbook backend.

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

<ul>
<li><a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://www.gnome-db.org/docs/libgda/index.html">libgda API reference</a></li>
<li><? bonsai ("evolution-data-server"); ?></li>
</ul>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Evolution/iPod synchronization]]></title>  <amount>500</amount> <category>Miscellaneous</category>
<bug>127552</bug>
<html><![CDATA[
<p>
Since the iPod supports calendars and addressbooks, it would be handy for
<img border=0 src="ipod.png" align=right alt="">

Evolution users to be able to automatically and easily synchronize

their personal data to their iPods.  Because the iPod is a read-only
device &mdash; the iPod cannot modify the data &mdash; the
&quot;synchronization&quot; is really just a one-way copy from
Evolution to the iPod.
</p>
<p>
Your solution must synchronize three kinds of data:
<ul>
<li>Contacts in the addressbook</li>
<li>Events in the calendar</li>
<li>Task list ("To Do" in the iPod)</li>
</ul>

<p>
The difficult part of this work will be to create a simple and
integrated user experience that doesn't require the user to do any
special setup or ever drop to a command line.  The winning entry will
offer an all-encompassing solution.
</p>

<?php box_sec ("Modules Affected"); ?>

You'll be working on <? bonsai ("evolution"); ?>.

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

To learn more about how Linux works with the iPod and how to
synchronize a device with Evolution, check out some of the following
links:
<ul>
<li><a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://multisync.sourceforge.net/">MultiSync</a></li>
<li><a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://gtkpod.sourceforge.net/">GTKPod</a>, a GUI iPod management system</li>
<li><a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/ipod-on-linux/">ipod-on-linux</a>, a conglomeration of other iPod and Linux work</li>
<li><a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://www.gnu.org/software/gnupod/">GNUPod</a>, Perl scripts for manipulating iPods</li>
</ul>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Bugzilla tasks backend]]></title>  <amount>500</amount> <category>Tasks</category>
<bug>127558</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

<p>Evolution and the GNOME project as a whole both use Bugzilla to
track bugs. Since Evolution is used by many GNOME developers, it would
be useful to have some degree of integration with Bugzilla.
<img border=0 src="bug.png" align=right alt="">
</p>

<?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>

<p><? bonsai ("evolution-data-server"); ?> and <? bonsai ("evolution"); ?>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>

<p>You will need to add a way to add a bugzilla server to your list of
task sources. (The user will need to configure server name, username,
and optionally have it remember his password.)</p>

<p>Evolution will have to parse the output of Bugzilla's "query.cgi"
page, and extract the list of saved queries from the pop-up at the
bottom. Each saved query should show up as a folder on that server in
Evolution.</p>

<p>When the user opens the folder, Evolution will fetch the results of
that query and show a task item for each bug. The summary of the task
should be the summary of the bug, and the URL field of the task should
be a link to the relevant bugzilla entry. If the user opens the bug,
the "Description" field should show the rest of the information. The
backend will probably need to be read-only.</p>

<p>There are various extensions you can make to the basic idea. For
example, you could try to map bug priority to task priority, or have
some indication of which tasks are assigned to the user.</p>

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

<ul>
<li><? bonsai ("evolution-data-server/calendar/backends"); ?> is where
your new backend should reside.
<li><? bonsai ("evolution-data-server/src"); ?> server needs to register
the method (e.g. bugzilla://) that maps to the backend.
<li><? bonsai ("evolution/calendar/gui/dialogs/new-calendar.c"); ?> and
its Glade file need to add a way for the user to specify the
username, server and saved query.  Multiple queries should be
supported.
</ul>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Weather calendar backend]]></title>  <amount>750</amount> <category>Calendar</category>
<bug>127537</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

<img border=0 src="suncloud.png" align=right alt="">
Write a calendar backend that contacts some weather source and provides
weather forecast data for the upcoming week or so as all-day events, so
it shows up in your calendar. This information should be cached locally,
so you can view it when offline.

<p>A mockup on how it should be integrated on the calendar view is below.</p>
<img src="cal-weather.png" align="center">

<? box_sec ("How"); ?>

<p>The backend just has to get the weather forecast information from
some place (determining that place is part of the job for this bounty,
you might start by looking at where the weather applet gets its
information) and, using ECalBackendFile, create a local copy of that
information (an all day event for each day) in the local file managed
by ECalBackendFile. The backend should probably remove old weather
forecasts, and just keep the ones for the current day and future
days.</p>

<p>The only question remaining is how to allow users to add that backend
to the list of calendars configured. An option could be to create the 'Weather'
calendar on startup, so that it's always available to users. Although there
probably should be a way to add it back if a user ever removes it. In that
case, the 'New Calendar' dialog, new-calendar.c in (<? bonsai ("evolution/calendar/gui/dialogs"); ?>)
could be extended to support the addition of local, remote and any special
kind of calendar backends (weather, birthdays, etc).</p>

<p>Another solution could be to have a config control page for the weather backend,
so that it can ask users all the required information.</p>

<p>Also, a way to use the different weather icons is needed. The best way could be
to use the categories stuff, which unfortunately is hard coded (a fixed set of categories
and icons for those categories is available), so there is the need to have a way for the
backend to register those new categories (Sunny, Rainy, etc) and the icons
associated with it.</p>

<?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>

<ul>
<li><? bonsai ("evolution-data-server/calendar/backends"); ?> is where
your new backend should reside.
<li><? bonsai ("evolution-data-server/src"); ?> server needs to register
the method (e.g. weather://) that maps to the backend.
</ul>

<?php box_sec ("Tips"); ?>

Use one of the existing backends, probably the http backend, as a
starting point. Grep sources for &quot;webcal&quot; and see how
it's hooked in. The old summary code used to pull weather data,
so that should provide some clues too.

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Advanced LDAP Configuration]]></title>  <amount>250</amount> <category>Addressbook</category>
<bug>127525</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

<p>Evolution can store contacts in an LDAP directory, but there is no way
to tell Evolution exactly where in the directory contact data should
be stored. </p>

<p>For example, user accounts are stored in
<tt>ou=Accounts,dc=gnome,dc=org</tt> but you may want to store the
addressbook in <tt>ou=miguel,ou=AddressBooks,dc=gnome,dc=org</tt>,
another user may want his addressbook in
<tt>ou=nat,ou=AddressBooks,dc=gnome,dc=org</tt>, etc.  Currently,
Evolution just puts things in the root <tt>dn</tt>
(<tt>dc=gnome,dc=org</tt>) which isn't very convenient.</p>

<?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>

<ul>
<li><? bonsai ("evolution-data-server/addressbook/backends/ldap"); ?><li> and <? bonsai ("evolution/addressbook/gui/component"); ?></ul>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>

<p>
There are a few places that need changing for this to work.  An extra
field needs to be added to the LDAP config UI.  It should probably
default to whatever the user typed in for the search base (since
many/most times they will be the same.)
</p>

<p>
The ldap:// URLs we generate will also need to have the additional
argument added to them.  There is no place in the RFC-specified URL
for the value, so they should be added like we already do with
limit/ssl/timeout arguments.  This will require changing code in both
<tt>addressbook-storage.c</tt> and in the <tt>_load_uri method</tt> of
the LDAP backend.
</p>

<p>
Lastly, the <tt>_create_contact</tt> method in the LDAP backend will
need to call <tt>create_dn_from_contact</tt> using the proper creation
root, instead of the rootdn as it does now.
</p>

<p>
You should subscribe to the <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://lists.ximian.com/mailman/listinfo/evolution-hackers">
evolution-hackers</a> mailing list, and discuss any technical issues
there.  Chris Toshok &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="mailto:toshok@ximian.com">toshok@ximian.com</a>&gt; and Hans Petter Jansson
&lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="mailto:hpj@ximian.com">hpj@ximian.com</a>&gt;
will be the primary contacts on the list.
</p>

<p>
<em>Note: We are currently moving from using URIs to using ESources to communicate with the backends.  This bounty should probably block on the completion of that work.</em>
</p>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Outlook-Evolution dictionary]]></title>  <amount>300</amount> <category>Documentation</category>
<bug>127544</bug>
<html><![CDATA[


<p> 
  To help people switching from Outlook to Evolution, assemble a list of
<img border=0 src="readme.png" align=right alt="">
  equivalent tasks for mail, calendar, and addressbook functionality,
  for the Evolution user's guide.  Ask yourself this question: "In
  Outlook, I did something by clicking here or selecting there. In
  Evolution, what do I do?"  
</p>

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>
 

<p>
 To get started, visit the
 irc.gnome.org channel #docs, or read up on the GNOME docs process at
 the <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://developer.gnome.org/projects/gdp">GNOME
 Documentation Project</a> home page and the <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
 href="http://www.docbook.org/tdg/en/html/docbook.html">official
DocBook manual</a>.  The primary contact for this task will be <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="mailto:aaron@ximian.com">Aaron Weber</a>.
</p>
<p> 
 Your work should reflect the Evolution 2.0 user interface; you may
 wish to wait until the GNOME 2.6 UI freeze to begin. 
 </p>

<?php box_sec ("Additional Requirements"); ?>

<p> 

 Please submit a single valid DocBook XML file, consisting of one
 &lt;chapter&gt; or &lt;appendix&gt;.
 You will probably want to format your work using the &lt;table&gt; or
 &lt;variablelist&gt; tags.  It may also help to include images
 of equivalent menus, dialogs, or windows. If you do include Evolution
 screenshots, use the same style as the existing Evolution user's
 guide screenshots. Screenshots should not display any actual personal
 information; if necessary, we can provide "dummy" mail folders,
 address books, and calendars.
  </p>

<p>
 You do not need to submit copyright assignment for this
 change; your work will be included in the Evolution User's Guide and
 distributed in accordance with the GNU Free Documentation License.
</p>


]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Publish your calendar]]></title>  <amount>1000</amount> <category>Calendar</category>
<bug>127538</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

<p>
   Apple's iCal has made "calendar sharing" popular. It's a nice feature where any user can create a calendar
   of events and then publish it on a website, to share it with other users. Others can then "subscribe" their
   calendar application to that calendar file, and updates are automatically synced to their imported calendar
   whenever the master file changes. This makes it easy and convenient to share conference schedules, meeting
   times, club events, moving dates and times and so on.
</p>

<p>
   Implement this calendar publishing feature in Evolution. There are two things: first, it needs to just upload
   the .ics file to a remote location, using gnome-vfs facilities (give the user a few common choices like
   ssh://, FTP, WebDav and saving to a file. Then automatically push updates to the exported file whenever new
   events are added or things are being changed. A GUI mockup for exporting is provided below:
</p>

<center>
<img src="publish_calendar.png" border=0>
</center>

<p>
   We should give a possibility to export to a simple HTML page as well for those visitors who don't use a
   calendar program that supports webcal:// (webcal is just a URI scheme that should invoke Evolution's
   "Calendar Import" dialog that does the same as this one but reverse).
</p>

<!--
<p>
   Also, you can use <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://phpicalendar.sf.net">PhpICalendar</a> to make a dynamic web page for users
   that have PHP support on their server. Evolution could contain a working, stable snapshot of phpical in the
   distribution and you could upload it and set it up for the user's website (proper error checking should
   naturally be carried out, including checking for an existing installation of phpical).
</p>
-->

<?php box_sec("Affected Modules"); ?>

<p>
   Both <? bonsai("evolution"); ?> and <? bonsai("evolution-data-server"); ?> will be affected.
</p>

<?php box_sec("How"); ?>

<p>
   Augment the calendar's http backend with the necessary export capabilities. The backend resides in
   <? bonsai ("evolution-data-server/calendar/backends/http"); ?>, and uses the file backend to operate on
   locally cached calendars. The backend could also handle the HTML generation, exporting it to one or more
   files alongside the ICS file. New named options need to be added to the backend's ESource - e.g.
   user, password, and a flag indicating whether to generate HTML. Additional GUI elements need to be
   added to <? bonsai ("evolution/calendar/gui"); ?> and <? bonsai ("evolution/calendar/gui/dialogs"); ?>.
</p>

<p>
   When implementing the HTML generator, you may want to look at HTML
  output from existing web calendars such as <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
  href="http://phpicalendar.sf.net/">PhpICalendar</a>.
</p>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Quick reference card]]></title>  <amount>300</amount> <category>Documentation</category>
<bug>127545</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

<p>
  Evolution has a quick reference section in the manual, but it's not
  obvious and it's not printable. It should have a link from the Help
  menu and it should be easy to print out on a single page and tape to
  the wall.
</p>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>
<p>
  The simplest approach to this will be to take the
  content from the "menuref.xml" help file in Evolution, and format it
  nicely as a card using any open-format desktop publishing tool (TeX,
  OpenOffice.org, etc.)  Convert the output to
  Postscript or PDF format, and create a link to it from the Help menu
  in Evolution.  Be sure to check that the content is up to date, and
  matches the Evolution development branch. Provide both the original
  and the PDF formatted version of your file.
 </p>

<p>
  Then, add a menu item in the Help menu. Make sure when you do so
  that it calls the appropriate application to display your choice of
  file format, and that this is based on the user's MIME database,
  rather than being hardcoded.
 </p>

<p>
  If that sounds too easy, you could work with the <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
  href="http://www.gnome.org/~shaunm/yelp/">Yelp help browser</a> team
  to add print support to the help browser, so that the reference
  section can be printed out directly.  However, this approach is much
  more difficult.  
</p>

<?php box_sec ("Modules Affected"); ?>
 

<p>
  This will change <? bonsai ("evolution"); ?>. If you wish, you can
  work with <?  bonsai ("yelp"); ?>. You may need to have, or obtain,
  some knowledge of <? bonsai ("gnome-print"); ?> as well.  
</p>

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>
 
<p>
For information on the DocBook XML format, check <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://www.docbook.org/tdg/en/html/docbook.html">DocBook: The
Definitive Guide</a>. To talk to GNOME documentation team members,
visit the #docs channel in irc.gnome.org.  For information on the
GNOME printing architecture, visit <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://www.gnome.org/projects/gnome-print/">the GNOME-print
page</a>.  Before you begin any work on the help browser, be sure to
<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://www.gnome.org/~shaunm/yelp/">check with the
maintainers.</a> The primary contact for this task will be <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="mailto:aaron@ximian.com">Aaron Weber</a>. </p>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Ask user to make Evolution default mail app]]></title>  <amount>100</amount> <category>Mailer</category>
<bug>127526</bug>
<html><![CDATA[
<p>It would be nice if Evolution would prompt the user if he or she would like to set
Evolution as the default "mailto:" handler for GNOME if:</p>
<ul>
<li>it is the first time the user has run Evolution</li>
<li>the default mailto handler gconf setting is unset</li>
</ul>

<?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>

<p>The only affected module will be <? bonsai ("evolution/mail"); ?></p>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>

<p>The best place to add this code is probably in <? bonsai ("evolution/mail/mail-component.c"); ?><tt>:mail_component_init</tt>
right after all the initialization happens.</p>
<p>You'll need to pop up a GtkDialog (probably a Yes/No; defaulting to Yes?)
with the prompt: "Would you like to make Evolution your default mail
application?". The setting should be saved to the gconf key
"/desktop/gnome/url-handlers/mailto"</p>

<p>You will probably also want to add a checkbox to the dialog to allow the
user to opt-out of ever seeing the dialog again. You will have to create a
new gconf key for this preference, probably something like
"/apps/evolution/mail/prompts/default_mailer" or some such.</p>

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

<p>
You should subscribe to the <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://lists.ximian.com/mailman/listinfo/evolution-hackers">
evolution-hackers</a> mailing list, and discuss any technical issues
there.  Michael Zucchi &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="mailto:notzed@ximian.com">notzed@ximian.com</a>&gt; and Jeffrey
Stedfast &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="mailto:fejj@ximian.com">fejj@ximian.com</a>&gt;
will be the primary contacts on the list.
</p>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Drag-n-drop task creation]]></title>  <amount>300</amount> <category>Tasks</category>
<bug>127559</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

It would be handy to be able to create tasks in Evolution by dragging
a mail, file or link into the tasks folder.  See <?php bug(4006); ?>.

]]>
</html>
</bounty>


<bounty> <title><![CDATA[OO.o slide view performance]]></title>  <amount>500</amount> <category>OpenOffice.org</category>
<bug>127554</bug>
<html><![CDATA[
<p>The slides view in impress suffers some from seriously slow,
un-cached slide thumbnailing, this makes scrolling the slide
list unacceptably slow.</p>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>
<p>Either profile and accelerate the thumbnail rendering to an
acceptable level, or render slides to a bitmap that can be
rendered more quickly subsequently.</p>

<?php box_sec ("Acceptance Criteria"); ?>
<p>The solution providing the greatest speedup, and ergonomic 
improvement in this area wins</p>
]]>
</html>
</bounty>
<!-- Commented by Srini, as Nat wanted to discontinue this bounty and use it for beagle related stuff.
<bounty> <title><![CDATA[OO.o slides side-pane]]></title>  <amount>1500</amount> <category>OpenOffice.org</category>
<bug>127555</bug>
<html><![CDATA[
<p>
  When editing a slide in the drawing view, it is often helpful
  to have some context. We need to add a side-pane that provides
  a scrollable vertical 'slide view' of the presentation.
</p>

<center>
<img src="OpenOffice-slidepane.gif" border=0 alt="">
</center>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>
<p>It is assumed that the existing 'slide view' widget can be
re-used here, in a scroll pane.</p>

<?php box_sec ("Acceptance Criteria"); ?> 
<p>
  As the user edits a slide, its appearance in the side view should
  change at a reasonable rate.  The side view should be sensibly sized
  &amp; aesthetically pleasing. The user should be able to navigate among
  slides by selecting them in the side view.
</p> 
]]> </html> </bounty>
-->
<bounty> <title><![CDATA[OO.o Image Save]]></title>  <amount>300</amount> <category>OpenOffice.org</category>
<bug>127556</bug> <solved>http://ooo.ximian.com/ooo-build/patches/OOO_1_1/sd-save-image-context-menu.diff</solved>
<html><![CDATA[ 
<p> 
 After inserting an image into a document or presentation, you may
 wish to save it as a separate file.  However, it is not currently
 easy to do so.
</p>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>
<p>
  Add a 'Save As' item to the right-click context menu for images in
  documents or presentations. The menu item should open up a dialog
  allowing the image to be saved to disk as an individual file.
</p> ]]> </html> </bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[OO.o Calc - function precision]]></title>  <amount>500</amount> <category>OpenOffice.org</category>
<bug>127771</bug>
<html><![CDATA[
<p>oocalc's numeric precision is pretty awful for a load of common
functions. This should be substantially improved, in-line with
gnumeric. Functions VAR, LINEST, SKEW, PRODUCT, GEOMEAN, POWER\
at a minumum should be improved.</p>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>
<p>For example, check out the VAR algorithm; <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://ooo.ximian.com/lxr/source/cvsup/sc/sc/source/core/tool/interpr1.cxx#2387">
here</a> and in fn. (ScVar). It should not discard precision in big handfulls.
To see an example of it's bad behavior enter A1: 30000 B1: 0.001 C1: =VAR(A1;A1+B1)
(format the cells with scientific notation).
</p>

<?php box_sec ("Acceptance Criteria"); ?>
The functions should behave more correctly, preferably as well as
gnumeric. There should also be a spreadsheet containing these corner
cases for future smoke regression testing.
]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[OO.o / Evolution Cut and Paste]]></title>  <amount>0</amount> <category>Ignore</category>

<html><![CDATA[
<p>Make sure that cut and paste between OO.o and the Evolution
composer works perfectly.</p>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>
<p>dunno</p>

<?php box_sec ("Acceptance Criteria"); ?>
<p><i>[Maybe provide a sample document and a sample email message and
say you have to be able to cut+paste between them arbitrarily? The
specific problems I know about right now involve extra newlines being
added, and tables sometimes getting extra rows.]</i></p>
]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Publish free/busy information]]></title>  <amount>500</amount> <category>Calendar</category>
<bug>127539</bug> <solved>http://cvs.gnome.org/bonsai/cvslog.cgi?file=evolution%2Fcalendar/ChangeLog&amp;rev=1.2066&amp;root=/cvs/gnome#1.2066</solved>
<html><![CDATA[

<p><?php rfc(2445); ?> describes a method of describing free/busy
information (VFREEBUSY components).  Evolution currently
can only publish free/busy information via email attachments.
</p>

<p> Evolution should support publishing free/busy information to an
http:// type URL, as discussed in <?php bug(16567); ?>.</p>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?> <p>

<p>
There should be a configuration control (see cal-prefs-dialog in <?php
bonsai ("evolution/calendar/gui/dialogs"); ?> for an example) that
allows the user to setup the URLs to publish to and which calendars to
use for creating the free/busy information.  There should be a
configuration option for the user to detail when they want their
calendar published, ie "Every Day", and Evolution should endeavor to
do this.  There should also be a menu option added to the calendar to
allow the user to publish the information whenever desired.
</p>

<p>
  To actually obtain the free/busy information, you simply need to call
e_cal_get_free_busy in <?php bonsai("evolution-data-server/calendar/libecal"); ?>, 
see calendar-commands.c in  <?php bonsai ("evolution/calendar/gui/"); ?> for an example of this.

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

<p>
You should subscribe to the <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://lists.ximian.com/mailman/listinfo/evolution-hackers">
evolution-hackers</a> mailing list, and discuss any technical issues
there.  JP Rosevear &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="mailto:jpr@ximian.com">jpr@ximian.com</a>&gt; and Hans Petter Jansson 
&lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="mailto:hpj@ximian.com">hpj@ximian.com</a>&gt;
will be the primary contacts on the list for the Calendar.
</p>

]]></html>
</bounty>


<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Default free/busy URI]]></title>  <amount>300</amount> <category>Calendar</category>
<bug>127541</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

<p><?php rfc(2445); ?> describes a method of describing free/busy
information (VFREEBUSY components).  Evolution currently will obtain
obtain free/busy information from the addressbook if the vCard or LDAP
property calFBURL (described in <?php rfc(2739); ?>) is set.
</p>

<p> Evolution should support a default free/busy uri for users that do
not have the calFBURL property set.
</p>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>

<p>Add a setting to cal-prefs-dialog.c in <?php bonsai("evolution/calendar/gui/dialogs"); ?> 
so the user can specify a template uri, for instance "http://freebusyserver.org/&lt;USERNAME&gt/freebusy.ifb".
</p>

<p>
When Evolution tries to obtain free/busy information for users, it
first requests the information from the calendar it will be saving the
data to.  If that fails, it tries to find an addressbook entry for the
username and look at the calFBURL property.  The code for these things
resides in e-meeting-model.h in <?php bonsai("evolution/calendar/gui/"); ?>.  
To accomplish this bounty,
there should be a third method of obtaining the free/busy information,
namely the use of the template uri with appropriate substitution. Most
of the code that loads the calFBURL can be used again to update the
attendee's information.
</p>
]]>

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

<p>
You should subscribe to the <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://lists.ximian.com/mailman/listinfo/evolution-hackers">
evolution-hackers</a> mailing list, and discuss any technical issues
there.  JP Rosevear &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="mailto:jpr@ximian.com">jpr@ximian.com</a>&gt; and Hans Petter Jansson 
&lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="mailto:hpj@ximian.com">hpj@ximian.com</a>&gt;
will be the primary contacts on the list for the Calendar.
</p>

</html>
</bounty>


<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Calendar attachments]]></title>  <amount>750</amount> <category>Calendar</category>
<bug>127543</bug>
<html><![CDATA[
<p>Add support in evolution for attaching files to events.</p>

<p>The iCalendar specification, <?php rfc(2445); ?>, describes a
property ATTACH (4.8.1.1) for attaching data to an iCalendar object
(event or task).  The event and task editor should allow the user to
add and remove documents and files.  It should also allow the user to
open the attached using an appropriate mime handler (similar to
Nautilus or the mail portion of evolution)</p>

<p>The following picture illustrates the point:</p>

<img src="calendar-attachments.gif">

<p>To attach file, drag it on the event. The event should draw a two
pixel black outline to give visual feedback to "drag accept". You should
also be able to attach documents with a right-click menu.  There should
be a contextual menu item to open the editor and get the list of files
and documents</p>

<?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>
<?php bonsai ("evolution-data-server"); ?><br>
<?php bonsai ("evolution"); ?>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?> 

<p>The first step is to confirm that <?php bonsai
("evolution-data-server/calendar/libical/src/libical"); ?> supports
the ATTACH property properly.  You will want to check that icalrecur.h
and icalrecur.c are adequate and that icalparser.c correctly reads in
the ATTACH property.  If it does not, you will need to correct
that.<p/>

<p>The second step is to to allow drag and drop of files on the day
view, week view and list view calendar items and the task list item
(see e-day-view.c, e-week-view.c and e-cal-list-view. in <?php bonsai
("evolution/calendar/gui"); ?>). It can accept the file uri drop, look
up the event and then attach the item.</p>

<p>The third step is to create a page containing the attachment
information for the editor, and add it to the event editor and task
editors, and example of this is recurrence-page.c in <?php bonsai
("evolution/calendar/gui/dialogs"); ?>.  There should also be an
"Attach" button that pops up a file dialog.  The page should not be
visible unless there are attachments or the user clicks the "Attach"
button.  Double clicking and attachment should allow the user to open
the item with an appropriate handler.  You might design this page
similar to the mail composer's attachment area.</p>

<p>The fourth step is to add contextual menu item, "Edit
Attachments..." that should open the editor and display the attachments page.
a similar thing is done by the "Schedule Meeting..." context item.</p>

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

<p>
You should subscribe to the <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://lists.ximian.com/mailman/listinfo/evolution-hackers">
evolution-hackers</a> mailing list, and discuss any technical issues
there.  Rodrigo Moya &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="mailto:rodrigo@ximian.com">rodrigo@ximian.com</a>&gt; and Hans Petter Jansson 
&lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="mailto:hpj@ximian.com">hpj@ximian.com</a>&gt;
will be the primary contacts on the list for the Calendar.
</p>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Drag and drop printing in Nautilus printers: view]]></title>  <amount>0</amount> <category>Ignore</category>

<html><![CDATA[
also context menu print in nautilus
]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[timezone clock support]]></title>  <amount>0</amount> <category>Ignore</category>

<html><![CDATA[
Gman: well, the way i imagined it would be you have something like 
<br>Gman: 2:2pm [NZ]
<br>Gman: and then clicking on the clock somehow [perhaps on a flag]
<br>Gman: then opens up a menu with a set of zones that you've configured
<br>Gman: so you could see what time it was in Boston, France, ...
<br>Gman: for meetings and stuff ;)
<br>Gman: hell, it would help me anyway

<p align="center"><img alt="" src="timezone.png" /></p>
]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Attachment bar and drag-and-drop in the composer]]></title>  <amount>500</amount> <category>Mailer</category>
<bug>127527</bug> <solved>http://lists.ximian.com/archives/public/evolution-patches/2004-January/004052.html</solved>
<html><![CDATA[
<p>
Currently, to drag and drop a file into an Evolution message, you
must drop it outside the message body. To make it easier to
attach files via drag and drop, we would like to make the attachments
bar more visible.
</p>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>

<p>
<img alt="attachments bar mockup" src="composer-attachments.gif" />
</p>

<p>
First you will need to add an arrow widget with a label saying
&quot;Show/Hide Attachments Bar (drop attachments here)&quot;. When
the arrow is pressed it should show/hide the attachment bar as shown
in the animation.
</p>

<p>
When you drag a file over that arrow or label, the attachment bar
should be shown. Note that an <u>A</u> accelerator (M-a) should toggle
the attachment bar visibility. The direction of the arrow widget
should change depending on the attachment bar visibility.
</p>

<p>
Once there are files attached, it will be indicated on the right side
by an attachment icon and a label saying: &quot;%d File(s)
Attached&quot;, where %d will be substituted by the number of attached
files to that message (as shown in the animation).
</p>

<?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>
<p>
This will require work in Evolution's composer (<?php
bonsai("evolution/composer");?>), which is part of the Mailer
component. You will need an understanding of Gtk+ and especially of
Gtk's drag-and-drop API.
</p>

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

<p>
You should subscribe to the <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://lists.ximian.com/mailman/listinfo/evolution-hackers">
evolution-hackers</a> mailing list, and discuss any technical issues
there.  Michael Zucchi &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="mailto:notzed@ximian.com">notzed@ximian.com</a>&gt; and Jeffrey
Stedfast &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="mailto:fejj@ximian.com">fejj@ximian.com</a>&gt;
will be the primary contacts on the list for the Mailer. Larry Ewing
&lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="mailto:lewing@ximian.com">lewing@ximian.com</a>&gt; and
Radek Doulik &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="mailto:rodo@ximian.com">rodo@ximian.com</a>&gt; might help you
with composer knowledge as well.
</p>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Templates for new messages and replies]]></title>  <amount>500</amount> <category>Mailer</category>
<bug>127529</bug>
<html><![CDATA[
<p>
We would like to allow people to prepare their own message
templates. The templates will be stored in a Templates folder and may
contain patterns which will be substituted when the template is used.
</p>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>

<p>
First you will need to add a new special folder, named Templates to
the local mail folders tree (~/.evolution/mail/local). That folder
will act similar to the Drafts folder, except that it will not delete
the message template when writing of the new message/reply is sent (or
saved as a Draft).
</p>

<p>
The Action submenu in the menubar and the context popup menu in the
message list of the Templates folder will contain additional items
&quot;Default New Mail&quot; and &quot;Default Reply&quot;. When
activated, that template will become the default template which will
be used when composing a new message or replying to a message,
respectively. A &quot;Reset templates&quot; item should reset the
templates so that no template, but the original reply and new message
code will be used. In the other folders, the menubar items should be
grayed out and items should not appear in the popup menu.
</p>

<p>
Next you have to implement substitution patterns. These will be
substituted by common information like &quot;Me&quot; for user's used
account mail address, &quot;Sender&quot; for sender of a mail you are
replying to, &quot;Date&quot;, &quot;Received&quot; and so on. These
should be available in the composer's menus. The mailer component
should substitute these when formatting a reply or a new message. The
composer menu will have a &quot;Save Template&quot; item, which will
save the current message to the Templates folder. The patterns should have
the case-insensitive format: ${Me}, ${Sender}, ${Date}, ...
</p>

<?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>
<p>
This will require work in Evolution's composer (<?php
bonsai("evolution/composer");?>), which is part of the Mailer
component. You will also need to know GtkHTML editor control API
(<?php bonsai("gtkhtml");?>).
</p>

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

<p>
You should subscribe to the <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://lists.ximian.com/mailman/listinfo/evolution-hackers">
evolution-hackers</a> mailing list, and discuss any technical issues
there.  Michael Zucchi &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="mailto:notzed@ximian.com">notzed@ximian.com</a>&gt; and Jeffrey
Stedfast &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="mailto:fejj@ximian.com">fejj@ximian.com</a>&gt;
will be the primary contacts on the list for the Mailer. Larry Ewing
&lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="mailto:lewing@ximian.com">lewing@ximian.com</a>&gt; and
Radek Doulik &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="mailto:rodo@ximian.com">rodo@ximian.com</a>&gt; might help you
with GtkHTML knowledge.
</p>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Language selection in composer]]></title>  <amount>400</amount> <category>Mailer</category>
<bug>127530</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

<p>Add a pop-up menu to the composer toolbar for selecting the
language. This would affect the default spell-checking dictionary, the
"On DATE, PERSON said:" attribution, the Content-Language header, and
various other things. See <?php bug(10577); ?> for more details.</p>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>
<p>
<img alt="toolbar mockup" src="composer-lang.gif" />
</p>
<p>Add a pop-up menu to the toolbar. (Maybe using the flag icons from
the keyboard layout applet?) Add hooks to update the choice of
spell-check language, etc, as appropriate. Turn the strings like the
reply attribution and "Forwarded Message", etc, into special objects
so that they can be dynamically translated (the same way the signature
changes when you select a new one).</p>
<p>The user should be able to configure what languages appear in the
pop-up, and which is the default. If you receive a message with a
Content-Language header indicating a specific language, then the
composer should start with that language selected by default.</p>
<p>The switching should be implemented in a similar fashion
to the current signature switching code using gtkhtml private data.
And the current setting of the language should be exposed to the
composer through a bonobo property on the editor control.  The setting
should also be saved in the html output in a lang attribute on the
body element. 
<?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>
This will require work in <?php bonsai("gtkhtml");?> particularly the
editor component (<?php bonsai("gtkhtml/components/html_editor");?>) and
parts of the Mailer component (<?php bonsai("evolution/composer");?>)
<?php box_sec ("Pointers");?>
You should subscribe to the <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://lists.ximian.com/mailman/listinfo/evolution-hackers">
evolution-hackers</a> mailing list, and discuss any technical issues
there.    Larry Ewing &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="mailto:lewing@ximian.com">lewing@ximian.com</a>&gt; and Radek
Doulik &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="mailto:rodo@ximian.com">rodo@ximian.com</a>&gt;
will be the primary contacts on the list for GtkHTML.
Michael Zucchi &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="mailto:notzed@ximian.com">notzed@ximian.com</a>&gt; and Jeffrey
Stedfast &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="mailto:fejj@ximian.com">fejj@ximian.com</a>&gt;
will be the primary contacts on the list for the Mailer.
]]></html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Better smiley substitution in the composer]]></title>  <amount>200</amount> <category>Mailer</category>
<bug>127533</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

<p>Make automatic smiley substitution easier to work around when enabled</p>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>
<p align="center"><img alt="" src="smiley.gif" /></p>
<p>Currently the when smiley substitution is on in the editor there
is no easy way to reverse the substitution.  Modify the behavior such
that if the user hits backspace while the cursor is on a smiley the 
first time the substitution is undone, but the smiley text remains.</p>
]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Drag and Drop between Gnome and Mozilla]]></title>  <amount>300</amount> <category>Miscellaneous</category>
<bug>127553</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

<p></p>

<p>Currently dragging and dropping back and forth between nautilus and
mozilla is very problematic.  Bookmarks and copying actions are easily
confused with surprising results.</p>

What happens now:
<ul>
<li>Drag an image (foo.gif) from a web page  to desktop. You get a "default" 
  icon with "foo.gif" as the name. 
<li>Drag a web page link to the desktop, it makes a similar .desktop
  file, which is  probably OK in this case ("make bookmark"). But dragging it back
  either does nothing, or makes the browser load the actual .desktop
  file as plaintext.
</ul>
What we'd like to see:
</ul>
<li>
  Dragging a bookmark .desktop file to Mozilla should open the url the
  bookmark file contains, not the bookmark file itself.
</li>
<li>
  Dragging an http: uri from mozilla to the desktop should ask you if you
  prefer to download the file or make a bookmark point to the location.  If a
  desktop bookmark is created the resulting .desktop file should specify a
  hyperlink icon (or possibly use the shortcut icon if the link points to an
  html page).
</li>
</ul>
<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>
  Add the behavior dialog and download options to Nautilus upon
  receipt drops containing http: uris.  Add code to mozilla to recognize
  the difference between the various .desktop filetypes and take the
  appropriate action.
<?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>
  <? bonsai ("nautilus"); ?> is where the changes related to dropping
  on the desktop will live.  Mozilla will also probably need changes to
  recognize .desktop files and take the appropriate action.
<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>
  The <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://mail.gnome.org/archives/desktop-devel-list/">desktop-devel-list</a> and 
<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://mail.gnome.org/archives/nautilus-list/">nautilus-list</a> are a valuable place to discuss the nautilus changes. The <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://freedesktop.org/">freedesktop.org</a> site has addtional pointers to common <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://freedesktop.org/Main/Draganddropwarts">drag and drop warts</a> (but ignore the parts about using XDS).  Information about Mozilla can be found at <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://mozilla.org/">mozilla.org.</a>
]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Make Evolution Use the gnome-icon-theme]]></title> <amount>500</amount>
<category>Miscellaneous</category>
<bug>127812</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

<p>Currently Evolution's icons are not themeable and are a mixture
of RGBA PNGs and 1bit transparent XPMs. Evolution should use the
icon theme spec' defined method of looking up icons from
gnome-icon-theme. Most of the icons are already in place
(gnome-icon-theme CVS module).</p>

<?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>

<p>This bounty requires changes to the components and shell.</p>

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

<p>The icon theme spec is available at <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://freedesktop.org/Standards/icon-theme-spec">freedesktop.org</a>,
particulary the <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://freedesktop.org/Standards/icon-theme-spec/0.7/ar01s05.html">icon
lookup section</a> may be handy.</p>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Gaim drag and drop file transfer]]></title>  <amount>400</amount> <category>IM</category>
<bug>127547</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

<p>For those protocols that support it, Gaim allows you to send and
receive files with other IM users.  Currently, you have to right click
on the user in the Gaim buddy list and select the &quot;Send
file&quot; popup menu entry to send the user a file.</p>

<p>This task is to modify Gaim to support drag-and-drop as a means of
initiating a file transfer to a user.  Dragging a file from the file
manager or desktop and dropping it onto a Gaim conversation window
should initiate a transfer of that file to the user.</p>

<p>One subtlety is how <tt>.desktop</tt> files are handled.  The
contents of the <tt>.desktop</tt> file are probably not what the user
wants to send, so you'll have to figure out how to handle these.</p>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Gaim drag and drop of links]]></title>  <amount>250</amount> <category>IM</category>
<bug>127548</bug> <solved>http://bugzilla.gnome.org/showattachment.cgi?attach_id=23279</solved>
<html><![CDATA[

<p>This one is pretty straightforward: Make it so that dragging a URL
from the browser or the desktop onto a Gaim conversation window copies
the URL into the text of the conversation.</p>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Handle <tt>aim:</tt> links in Epiphany]]></title>  <amount>100</amount> <category>IM</category>
<bug>127549</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

The <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://cvs.sourceforge.net/viewcvs.py/gaim/gaim/src/gaim-remote.c?view=markup"><tt>gaim-remote</tt></a>
command-line tool makes it easy to remotely open a conversation with a
buddy.  Your job is pretty easy: set the default protocol handler for
<tt>aim:</tt> to be <tt>gaim-remote</tt>.

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Message receipts]]></title>  <amount>500</amount> <category>Mailer</category>
<bug>127534</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

<p><?php rfc(2298); ?> describes a standard method for clients to
request a "Message Disposition Notification" (aka "Read Receipt") from
the recipient indicating that they have received the message.</p>

<?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>

<p>The mailer (<?php bonsai("evolution/camel"); ?>, <?php
bonsai("evolution/mail"); ?>, and <?php bonsai("evolution/composer");
?>).</p>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>

<p>Supporting this in Evolution would require the following things:</p>

<ul>
<li> Add an option to the composer for "Request a Read Receipt
for this Message" (or something like that). This would always
default to being off. Make the composer generate proper MDN request
headers if the option is turned on. </li>
<li> Add code to the mailer to recognize MDN requests and generate
MDNs, according to the rules in <?php rfc(2298); ?> and <?php
rfc(3503); ?>.  This would probably sit in em-folder-view somewhere.</li>
<li> Add configuration options allowing the user to configure when
MDNs should be returned. There should at least be options for
"Never", "Always", and "Ask each
time". The default should be either "Never" or
"Ask". </li>
<li> Create the dialog box to be used in the "Ask" case.
</li>
</ul>

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

For Evolution information, join the <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://lists.ximian.com/mailman/listinfo/evolution-hackers">Evolution
Hackers</a> mailing list. Michael Zucchi &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="mailto:notzed@ximian.com">notzed@ximian.com</a>&gt; and Jeffrey
Stedfast &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="mailto:fejj@ximian.com">fejj@ximian.com</a>&gt;
will be the primary contacts on the list.

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Link URLs in the status bar]]></title> <amount>200</amount> <category>Mailer</category>
<bug>127536</bug> <solved>http://lists.ximian.com/archives/public/evolution-patches/2004-January/003949.html</solved>
<html><![CDATA[

<p>Evolution should make URLs embedded in emails visible to the user.
When the user tabs to, or hovers the mouse over a link in an email,
Evolution should show the selected URL in the status bar.

<p>The URLs should be displayed in a friendly way to the user.  For
example, "mailto:foo@bar.com" should display: "Click to send mail to
foo@bar.com".  Other URLs, like "http://www.foobar.com/", should
display the message: "Click to open http://www.foobar.com/".

<p>The URL could be shown in the status bar.  However, the message
window does not yet have an associated status bar.  The message window
would need a status bar in order to work correctly.

<p align="center">

<img alt="" src="evo-tooltip.png" />

</p>

<?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>

<p>This bounty requires changes to the mailer and shell.</p>

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

<p>The GtkHTML widget emits an <tt>on_url</tt> signal when the user
mouses over a URL. <?php bug(3383); ?> has some more discussion of
this bug (though some of it may be specific to APIs that are changing
in 2.0).</p>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>


</bounties>
