<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Improve login time]]></title>
<amount>4500</amount> <category>Optimization</category> <funder>Google</funder>
<bug>306042</bug>
<funder>Novell</funder>
<html><![CDATA[
The time it takes a user to login to GNOME has not changed very much
in the last five years, despite massive improvements in hardware
performance.  Some analysis has shown that login time is bounded by a
heavy I/O load.  Havoc Pennington has pointed out a 3-4 second delay
caused by GConf initialization.<p>

This bounty will go to the person (or team) who submits a
maintainer-accepted patch which results in the single largest
reduction in login time.
]]> </html> </bounty>


<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Reduce Evolution memory usage]]></title>
<amount>4500</amount> <category>Optimization</category> <funder>Google</funder>
<bug>306043</bug>
<funder>Novell</funder>
<html><![CDATA[

This bounty will go to the person who submits the best accepted patch
to Evolution which results in the greatest reduction of run-time
memory usage under ordinary usage.  Memory reductions to the mailer,
addressbook and calendar will all be considered.

]]>
</html>
</bounty>


<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Live documentation editing]]></title> <amount>4500</amount>
<category>Documentation</category> <funder>Google</funder>
<bug>306308</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

Implement a live web-based wiki-like editor that allows generation of
content that can be rolled back into our documentation. Allows users
to contribute annotations and additions to documentation (e.g. can add
documentation to an undocumented function), save it. Other people
visiting the page will see your additions to the documentation, and
the maintainer of the module can extract the addition and
trivially roll it into the official documentation source.
   
]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Gnome architecture overview]]></title> <amount>4500</amount>
<category>Ignore</category> <funder>Google</funder>
<bug>306309</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

Write a document giving an overview of the GNOME development
platform's architecture.  The target audience for this document
includes developers who want to begin developing software on GNOME,
people who want to begin contributing to GNOME, or system
administrators who want a better understanding of how the pieces fit
together.  This bounty will go to the authors of the best paper.
   
]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[library.gnome.org]]></title> <amount>4500</amount>
<category>Documentation</category> <funder>Google</funder>
<bug>306311</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

Implement "library.gnome.org" which aggregates documentation
from releases of GNOME platform libraries into a searchable,
readable, consultable form.
        
]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Most unprecedented application]]></title> <amount>4500</amount>
<category>Features</category> <funder>Google</funder>
<bug>306312</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

Have an idea you think no one's ever had before?  An innovative
application that doesn't exist but that everyone needs?  Something so
cool it just has to be done? <p>

This bounty will be awarded to the authors of the most unprecedented
application.  Submissions will be judged by a panel appointed by the
GNOME board of directors.
        
]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Panel applet bundle system]]></title> <amount>4500</amount>
<category>Features</category> <funder>Google</funder> 
<bug>306314</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

A framework that lets developers implement panel extensions as
simple to write single file bundles. Bundles will require no
native code, probably written in Python (so they work between
library versions etc), and will be user installable from web
pages. Must include a tool for building the bundles.
           
]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Group mails by conversations in Evolution]]></title> <amount>4500</amount>
<category>Features</category> <funder>Google</funder> 
<bug>306315</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

<a href="http://www.gmail.com/">Gmail</a> provides an innovative new
way of reading your emails: as conversations wherein the mails you
send and the mails you receive in a given thread are all visible once,
in chronological order.  Implement this in Evolution.
           
]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Paste by example]]></title> <amount>4500</amount>
<category>Features</category> <funder>Google</funder>
<bug>306316</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

Paste by example is a feature that allows users to learn "by example"
the features of an office suite. It will let people learn to create
any formatting or object seen in a document sent to them (or one they
created 3 years ago). Office objects in the clipboard buffer (e.g. a
graph or a formatted sentence) can be pasted into the current
document, but step by step as a dynamically generated tutorial
(showing the dialogues and commands users could have used to recreate
the object in question). Feature can be implemented in OpenOffice.org
or AbiWord.
           
]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Search party]]></title> <amount>4500</amount>
<category>Features</category> <funder>Google</funder>
<bug>306179</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

Search party is a feature that allows adhoc chat rooms to form based
on what people are searching for on the web (using e.g. Google).
Implement the search party web browser extension for Firefox or
Epiphany.  Define the search party client/server "protocol" and
implement a server.

<a href="http:/www.gnome.org/~seth/summerofcode/searchparty">Mockups and More Details</a>
           
]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Shared music spaces]]></title> <amount>4500</amount>
<category>Features</category> <funder>Google</funder>
<bug>306317</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

Shared music spaces allow people in a shared chat room (e.g. an IM
chat room) to listen to a music stream playing on any of their
computers.  Feature will be added using Rhythmbox and Gaim.
           
]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Conference content]]></title>
<amount>4500</amount> <category>Ignore</category> <funder>Google</funder>
<bug></bug>
<html><![CDATA[

Develop a complete set of content for shows. This includes posters,
imagery, and brochures targeted toward different purposes (prospective
developers, trade shows, corporate sponsors, etc)
                   
]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[The GIMP resource distribution system]]></title>
<amount>4500</amount> <category>GIMP</category> <funder>Google</funder>
<bug>306713</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

Develop a distribution system for brushes, palettes, patterns,
gradients, plug-ins, scripts and any other resources of The GIMP that
are available. It should be usable from within GIMP and be available
on any platform GIMP can be run on.
                   
]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[The GIMP vector based shapes tool]]></title>
<amount>4500</amount> <category>GIMP</category> <funder>Google</funder>
<bug>65197</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

The GIMP urgently needs a tool to draw shapes (rectangles, ellipses, polygons,
stars, clouds, speech bubbles ... based on vectors.
       
]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[National, religious, event calendars]]></title>  <amount>15</amount> <category>Calendar</category>
<bug>127528</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

<p>In Evolution 2.0, users can aggregate multiple simultaneous
calendar sources into a single view.  This means that you can overlay
group calendars and other people's calendars into your own calendar
view, which helps you keep others in mind while you schedule your
life.  The various backend calendars can even be color-coded in the
calendar view.</p>

<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="evo-webcal-1.png"><img align=right border=0 src="evo-webcal-1-small.png" alt=""></a>

<p>We would like Evolution to ship with a large number of calendars
containing the schedules for national holidays, religious holidays,
and other events of general interest.  For example, calendars of
sporting events or a Linux conference schedule would be neat.</p>

<p>Because Evolution 2.0 allows you to specify a URL to a calendar, it
is even possible for these to be hosted online and cached locally.
This might be useful for things like the GNOME release schedule.</p>

<?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>

This task probably won't involve patching any existing modules, though
we will include any accepted calendars in the <? bonsai ("evolution"); ?> module.

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>

<p>Find and check the schedules for various types of events, and create a
calendar in the standard iCal format.  Submit the calendar file or
files, along with a short description, to <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="mailto:evolution-patches@ximian.com">evolution-patches@ximian.com</a>.</p>

<p>Until Evolution provides an 'Export' mechanism, the files should be
copied (if created in Evolution) from the Evolution2.0 tree, that is
<code>~/.evolution/calendar/local/OnThisComputer/"name"</code>, where
"name" is the name of the calendar you created.  If created in
Evolution 1.4, the file to copy is
<code>~/evolution/local/Calendar/subfolders/"name"</code>.</p>

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

The following links might be helpful:

<ul>
<li><a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://lists.ximian.com/mailman/listinfo/evolution">Evolution users list</a></li>
<li><a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://www.icalshare.com/">Apple's iCalShare site</a></li>
<li><?php rfc(2445); ?>, the iCalendar specification</li>
<li>The <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="#28528410">calendar publication</a> task is obviously somewhat related.</li>
</ul>

Please note that downloading proprietary <tt>.ical</tt> files and
submitting them is <i>not acceptable</i>.  To collect this bounty, you
must provide an unencumbered, freely-licensed (X11) iCalendar file.

<?php box_sec ("Special Note"); ?>

The bounty for this task is per-calendar.  We will pay bounties for up
to 30 calendars.</p>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[&quot;Me&quot;]]></title>  <amount>300</amount> <category>Addressbook</category>
<bug>127517</bug> <eliminated>Yes</eliminated>
<html><![CDATA[

<p>The Evolution 2.0 addressbook will have a "me" concept that will
allow programs to get the contact entry that corresponds to the user.
This should be integrated across the desktop, wherever extensive user
information (name, email address, etc) is needed or entered.</p>

<p>A couple of places where other applications could use this data:</p>
<ul>
<li>Web forms, via Firefox's form autofill feature.</li>
<li>Document author fields in OpenOffice.</li>
</ul>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>
<p>
<? bonsai ("evolution-data-server/addressbook/libebook"); ?> contains
the function <tt>e_book_get_self</tt>, which can be used to retrieve
the contact associated with the user.  From there you can use the
methods on <tt>EContact</tt> to retrieve the bits of information you
need.
</p>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>


<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Drag-n-drop task creation]]></title>  <amount>300</amount> <category>Tasks</category>
<bug>127559</bug> <eliminated>yes</eliminated>
<html><![CDATA[

It would be handy to be able to create tasks in Evolution by dragging
a mail, file or link into the tasks folder.  See <?php bug(4006); ?>.

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[OO.o slides side-pane]]></title>  <amount>1500</amount> <category>OpenOffice.org</category>
<bug>127555</bug> <eliminated>yes</eliminated>
<html><![CDATA[
<p>
  When editing a slide in the drawing view, it is often helpful
  to have some context. We need to add a side-pane that provides
  a scrollable vertical 'slide view' of the presentation.
</p>

<center>
<img src="OpenOffice-slidepane.gif" border=0 alt="">
</center>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>
<p>It is assumed that the existing 'slide view' widget can be
re-used here, in a scroll pane.</p>

<?php box_sec ("Acceptance Criteria"); ?> 
<p>
  As the user edits a slide, its appearance in the side view should
  change at a reasonable rate.  The side view should be sensibly sized
  &amp; aesthetically pleasing. The user should be able to navigate among
  slides by selecting them in the side view.
</p> 
]]> </html> </bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Calendar attachments]]></title>  <amount>750</amount> <category>Calendar</category>
<bug>127543</bug> <eliminated>yes</eliminated>
<html><![CDATA[
<p>Add support in evolution for attaching files to events.</p>

<p>The iCalendar specification, <?php rfc(2445); ?>, describes a
property ATTACH (4.8.1.1) for attaching data to an iCalendar object
(event or task).  The event and task editor should allow the user to
add and remove documents and files.  It should also allow the user to
open the attached using an appropriate mime handler (similar to
Nautilus or the mail portion of evolution)</p>

<p>The following picture illustrates the point:</p>

<img src="calendar-attachments.gif">

<p>To attach file, drag it on the event. The event should draw a two
pixel black outline to give visual feedback to "drag accept". You should
also be able to attach documents with a right-click menu.  There should
be a contextual menu item to open the editor and get the list of files
and documents</p>

<?php box_sec ("Affected Modules"); ?>
<?php bonsai ("evolution-data-server"); ?><br>
<?php bonsai ("evolution"); ?>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?> 

<p>The first step is to confirm that <?php bonsai
("evolution-data-server/calendar/libical/src/libical"); ?> supports
the ATTACH property properly.  You will want to check that icalrecur.h
and icalrecur.c are adequate and that icalparser.c correctly reads in
the ATTACH property.  If it does not, you will need to correct
that.<p/>

<p>The second step is to to allow drag and drop of files on the day
view, week view and list view calendar items and the task list item
(see e-day-view.c, e-week-view.c and e-cal-list-view. in <?php bonsai
("evolution/calendar/gui"); ?>). It can accept the file uri drop, look
up the event and then attach the item.</p>

<p>The third step is to create a page containing the attachment
information for the editor, and add it to the event editor and task
editors, and example of this is recurrence-page.c in <?php bonsai
("evolution/calendar/gui/dialogs"); ?>.  There should also be an
"Attach" button that pops up a file dialog.  The page should not be
visible unless there are attachments or the user clicks the "Attach"
button.  Double clicking and attachment should allow the user to open
the item with an appropriate handler.  You might design this page
similar to the mail composer's attachment area.</p>

<p>The fourth step is to add contextual menu item, "Edit
Attachments..." that should open the editor and display the attachments page.
a similar thing is done by the "Schedule Meeting..." context item.</p>

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

<p>
You should subscribe to the <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" 
href="http://lists.ximian.com/mailman/listinfo/evolution-hackers">
evolution-hackers</a> mailing list, and discuss any technical issues
there.  Rodrigo Moya &lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="mailto:rodrigo@ximian.com">rodrigo@ximian.com</a>&gt; and Hans Petter Jansson 
&lt;<a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="mailto:hpj@ximian.com">hpj@ximian.com</a>&gt;
will be the primary contacts on the list for the Calendar.
</p>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>


<bounty> <title><![CDATA[Choice of database for contacts back-end]]></title>  <amount>250</amount> <category>Addressbook</category>
<bug>127524</bug>
<html><![CDATA[

<p>
  Some people or system administrators want to use a local address
  back-end that is not the default (db3). The most popular request is
  SQLite, but a generalized SQL interface would be best.
</p>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>
 

<p>
  You will need to choose or design a database schema to match the
  Evolution addressbook, and then write wrappers to translate the
  Evolution addressbook manipulation functions to your choice of
  database. It is acceptable to leave database selection as an option
  'hidden' in gconf-editor. For the implementation,
  <a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://www.gnome-db.org">libgda</a> seems the best choice
  for the database access part, since it allows access to many different
  database backends (PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite, SQL Server, Oracle, etc)
  and offers a rich data management API.
</p>

<?php box_sec ("Modules Affected"); ?>

You'll be working on <? bonsai ("evolution-data-server"); ?>, writing a new
addressbook backend.

<?php box_sec ("Pointers"); ?>

<ul>
<li><a STYLE="text-decoration:none" href="http://www.gnome-db.org/docs/libgda/index.html">libgda API reference</a></li>
<li><? bonsai ("evolution-data-server"); ?></li>
</ul>

]]>
</html>
</bounty>

<bounty> <title><![CDATA[OO.o slide view performance]]></title>  <amount>500</amount> <category>OpenOffice.org</category>
<bug>127554</bug>
<html><![CDATA[
<p>The slides view in impress suffers some from seriously slow,
un-cached slide thumbnailing, this makes scrolling the slide
list unacceptably slow.</p>

<?php box_sec ("How"); ?>
<p>Either profile and accelerate the thumbnail rendering to an
acceptable level, or render slides to a bitmap that can be
rendered more quickly subsequently.</p>

<?php box_sec ("Acceptance Criteria"); ?>
<p>The solution providing the greatest speedup, and ergonomic 
improvement in this area wins</p>
]]>
</html>
</bounty>
