<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN"
"docbook/xml-dtd-4.2-1.0-17/docbookx.dtd" []>
<!--  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.2/docbookx.dtd" [] > -->
<book>
<bookinfo>
<title>ORBit2 Frequently Asked Questions - FAQs</title>
<authorgroup>
  <author>
    <firstname>Michael</firstname><surname>Meeks</surname>
  </author>
  <author>
    <firstname>Michael</firstname><surname>Rumpf</surname>
  </author>
  <author>
    <firstname>Frank</firstname><surname>Rehberger</surname>
  </author>
</authorgroup>
<pubdate>2003</pubdate>
</bookinfo>

<toc></toc>

<!-- ============= Document Body ============================= -->
<!-- ============= Introduction ============================== -->
<!-- Use the Introduction section to give a brief overview of what
     the application is and what it does. -->

  <chapter id="CORBA">
  <title>CORBA</title> 
  <!-- =========== Linc related Questions ======================= -->
    <sect1 id="ClientConnection">
    <title>How does a client connect to a server?</title> 

    <para>
    This is a well known problem in CORBA (more precisely in any
    distributed object system). It is commonly known under the term
    &quot;bootstrapping&quot;. In general, object references can be
    obtained from a <application>Name Service</application> (or a
    <application>Trading Object Service</application>), but a name
    service (thanks to the clear design of CORBA) is itself an
    object. So, how do you get the reference to the name service if it
    is itself an object ?  </para>

    <para> The standard solution for a client, finding a first object
    reference to a server is by exchanging an Interoperable Object
    Reference (IOR). The server process produces an IOR of the created
    object by using the method <funcsynopsis> <funcprototype>
    <funcdef>CORBA_string
    <function>CORBA_ORB_object_to_string</function></funcdef>
    <paramdef>CORBA_ORB <parameter>orb</parameter></paramdef>
    <paramdef>const CORBA_Object <parameter>obj</parameter></paramdef>
    <paramdef>CORBA_Environment* <parameter>env</parameter></paramdef>
    </funcprototype> </funcsynopsis> The generated string, also called
    stringified object reference, can be transfered by any kind of
    media, like email, HTTP, NFS, filesystem, or even as a message in
    a bottle ;-) . The client process reads the IOR from the medium
    and converts it back into its binary representation via
    <funcsynopsis> <funcprototype> <funcdef>CORBA_Object
    <function>CORBA_ORB_string_to_object</function></funcdef>
    <paramdef>CORBA_ORB <parameter>orb</parameter></paramdef>
    <paramdef>const CORBA_char *<parameter>str</parameter></paramdef>
    <paramdef>CORBA_Environment *<parameter>env</parameter></paramdef>
    </funcprototype> </funcsynopsis> Afterwards the client holds a
    valid object reference to the server and thus is able to invoke
    methods in the usual way.  </para>

    <para> Until now non-standard ways to solve this bootstrapping
    issue have been introduced by different ORBs. One example is the
    Visibroker Location Service. The ORB registers each object at a
    central service by a proprietary _bind() method. The discovery of
    the service is done by network broadcasts. The drawback of this
    mechanism is that the information about the objects is stored in a
    central table.  The table needs to be updated on a regular
    basis. This is necessary because of malicious objects not cleanly
    deregistering.  If the broadcast interval is to short the updates
    will cause a lot of noise on the network. If the interval is to
    long the table contains zombie objects. Such kind of proprietary
    solutions exists for many major CORBA implementations.  </para>

    <para> Ideally the method resolve_initial_references() could be
    used to find a reference to the naming service. Therefore the ORB
    must be able to read IORs without requiring the developer to write
    some additional code. In the past each ORB had its own command
    line parameters to pass IORs to the ORB's core (ORBit:
    ORBNamingIOR=IOR:.....). <application>The Interoperable Naming
    Service (INS) </application> specification introduces the
    standardized command line parameter <envar>-ORBInitRef</envar> to
    achieve this.  </para>

    <screen>
    <prompt>bash$</prompt><userinput>appname -ORBInitRef NameService=IOR_of_naming_service</userinput> </screen>
          
    <para> The only trick is to pass argc and argv to the ORB_init()
    call of the ORB, so that the ORB's core can extract the relevant
    parameters.  Afterwards the call </para>

    <para><command>nsobj =
    resolve_initial_references("NameService");</command> returns the
    desired object reference. The INS specification defines, besides
    the IOR, other human readable object references.
    <command>corbaloc:iiop://IIOPVersion@hostname:port/ObjectKey</command>
    </para>

    <para>This offers the possibility for a client to point to a
    server object just by providing a human readable address. Another
    proposed naming scheme is corbaname, which refers to a naming
    service running on the host the, specified by hostname.
    <replaceable>corbaname://hostname#a/b/obj</replaceable> The
    a/b/obj specifies a Name, i.e. a sequence of NameComponents, which
    resolves to an object reference.  These mechanisms will extremly
    improve the whole bootstrapping process and finally solve the
    problem, as it has been one of the most annoying issues in the
    past. There are are also a few critics of the human readable
    object reference corbaloc. They think that the fact of having
    opaque IORs is weakened by the INS specification. Specifying
    protocol details, like port numbers or protocol version numbers,
    can result in references to become invalid when the protocol, used
    for transportation is exchanged. The Object URLs have to be
    extended to support the new protocol information, whereas IORs
    always remain the same, a sequence of numbers. </para>


    <para>The CVS HEAD version of ORBit has a partial implementation
    of the INS specification.  <ulink type="http"
    url="http://www.ooc.com.au/staff/michi/binding.txt">Michi Henning
    has a more elaborate description of the problem here.</ulink>
    </para>

    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="DefaultParameterInIDL">
    <title>How can I specify default parameters in IDL?</title> 
     
    <para>
    IDL does not allow to specifiy default parameters. There are
    mainly two reasons for that. First, IDL is some kind of least
    common denominator of all the languages for which a CORBA mapping
    is available. Many languages do not support the concept of default
    parameters and thus have difficulties in supporting this feature
    in the mapping. And second, default parameters are not really
    necessary. The designer of an interface can easily split such
    funtionality into two or more separate methods (Attention:
    Overloading is not supported for the same reasons, so that methods
    must have different names). </para> </sect1>

    <sect1 id="GettingIpAdressOfObject">
    <title>How can I get the IP address of a cient/server object in
    CORBA?</title> 

    <para> The IP address (as well as the port number or any other
    protocol related feature) is hidden in the IOR (Interoperable
    Object Reference). The reason for this opacity is that CORBA can
    use any protocol for transportation of requests between object
    instances. The GIOP (General Inter ORB Protocol) is independent
    from any special network protocol. The IIOP (Internet Inter ORB
    Protocol) is a translation of GIOP into TCP/IP. IIOP support is
    not a mandatory feature of an ORB, but because of the Internet it
    has become a must for any ORB to implement. If we start relying on
    the presence of a specific protocol the original intention becomes
    weakened and may render object references, valid today, invalid in
    the future. (see TAO (The ACE ORB, ACE - Adaptive Communication
    Environment) for an ORB which supports pluggable protocols)
    </para>
   
    </sect1> 

   <sect1 id="Who_is_resonsible">
   <title>Who is responsible ?</title>
   <para>
   The bulk of the initial work is down to Elliot Lee, and various
   people whose ideas he fused liberaly Kennard White, Sebastian
   Wilhelmi - the polishing and recent work down to Mark McLoughlin,
   Martin Baulig and Michael Meeks.
   </para>
   </sect1>



      <sect1 id="why_cant_i_keep_a_pointer_to_an_argument">
      <title>Why can't I keep a pointer to an argument ?</title>

      <para>
      If you are implementing a CORBA method, often you are sent data
      and wish to keep it around; one scenario might be where you are
      sent a sequence as an 'in' or 'inout' argument:

      <programlisting>static void
impl_MyModule_myMethod (PortableServer_Servant            servant,
			const CORBA_sequence_CORBA_octet *data,
			CORBA_Environment                *ev)
{
	/* This code contains an error */
	g_hash_table_insert (my_hash, data);
}</programlisting>
 
      The lifetime of the 'data' variable is only that of the method
      invocation. What this means is that when the invocation comes in
      across the wire - the arguments are de-marshaled to temporary
      storage.  The method is then invoked - on the data, and then the
      data is freed after the invocation ( to avoid leaking it, or the
      user having to explicitely free it ).
      </para>

      <para>
      Thus - if you want to keep a pointer to data; you need to copy
      it to insert it into the table. ORBit2 provides a helpful
      convenience function to copy any value, specified by type:

      <programlisting>{
	CORBA_sequence_CORBA_octet *copy;

	copy = ORBit_copy_value (data, TC_CORBA_sequence_CORBA_octet);
	g_hash_table_insert (my_hash, copy);
}</programlisting>

	is correct.
	</para>
      </sect1>

  </chapter> 

  <chapter id="orbit">
   <title>ORBit2</title>

   <sect1 id="what_is_ORBit2">
   <title> What is ORBit2?</title>
   <para>
   ORBit2 is the next revision in the ORBit development plan. It is
   substantialy re-written, and contains a number of new, advanced
   features. One of these is an abstract IO layer split out into the
   separate 'linc' library. This allows features such as SSL operation
   and multiple new connection types.
   </para>
   </sect1>

  <sect1 id="when_and_who_started_the_project">
  <title>When and who started the project?</title> <para>The project
  was started by Elliot Lee and Dick Porter around February 1998.
  </para>
  </sect1>

   <sect1 id="how_is_orbit2_better_than_orbit_stable">
   <title>How is ORBit2 better than ORBit 'stable' ?</title>
   <para>
   In many ways:
   <itemizedlist>
        <listitem><para> 
        Targets CORBA 2.4 instead of CORBA 2.2
        </para></listitem>
        
        <listitem><para> 
        Theoreticaly thread safe - see later.
        </para></listitem>

        <listitem><para> 
        In conjunction with linc allows all manner of new transports
        </para></listitem>

        <listitem><para> 
        Protection against malicious / badly formed wire data
        </para></listitem>

        <listitem><para> 
        Type centric
        <itemizedlist>
                <listitem><para> smaller - stubs / skels are tiny: ~50% smaller.</para></listitem>
                <listitem><para> generic operation, eg. method tracing</para></listitem>
                <listitem><para> fast in-proc language bindings</para></listitem>
                <listitem><para> marginaly slower currently</para></listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        </para></listitem>

        <listitem><para> 
        Uses glib mainloop
        </para></listitem>

        <listitem><para> 
        "URL for IOR" to allow retrieving an IOR via HTTP
        </para></listitem>

        <listitem><para> 
        Cleaner
        <itemizedlist>
                <listitem><para> lots of code cleaning and re-factoring</para></listitem>
                <listitem><para> most CORBA interfaces generated from pseudo-IDL</para></listitem>
                <listitem><para> a more pleasant directory structure</para></listitem>
                <listitem><para> more complete implementations of many things</para></listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        </para></listitem>

        <listitem><para> 
        Tested - fairly comprehensive stress testing.
        </para></listitem>

        <listitem><para> 
        No resource leakage of TypeCodes
        </para></listitem>

        <listitem><para> 
        Lots of bugs fixed, and new ones created.
        </para></listitem>
   </itemizedlist>
   </para>
   </sect1>

  <sect1 id="how_can_i_install_a_version_of_orbit_without_affecting_my_gnome_desktop">
  <title>How can I install a version of ORBit without affecting my GNOME desktop </title>
  <para>
Configure the package with the following command:

<command>./configure --prefix=~/orbit_test_dir --exec-prefix=~/orbit_test_dir</command>

   Where orbit_test_dir is an arbitrary subdirectory. Then call make
   and make install, which will copy ORBit to the specified
   directory. Finally you just need to adapt your PATH and
   LD_LIBRARY_PATH environment variables by adding
   ~/orbit_test_dir/bin to PATH and ~/orbit_test_dir/lib to
   LD_LIBRARY_PATH respectively.
  </para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="where_can_i_get_the_cvs_head_version_of_orbit2">
  <title>Where can I get the CVS HEAD version of ORBit2?</title>
  <para>The gnome <ulink type="http"
  url="http://www.gnome.org/projects/ORBit2/download.html">developer
  site </ulink>has a description on how to use the anonymous CVS access. After
  logging on you just need to type "cvs -z3 co ORBit2", whereas
  "ORBit2" is the name of the module
  </para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="what_is_the_difference_between_the_cvs_version_and_the_gnome_package">
  <title>What is the difference between the CVS version and the GNOME
  package?</title> <para>The <ulink type="http"
  url="http://www.gnome.org/start/2.3">Roadmap for GNOME</ulink>
  version 2.x requires ORBit2 to be binary and source-code
  compatible. Therefore updates on the ORBit2 package are accepted as
  long as these requirements are not violated.
  </para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="i_cant_connect_to_my_remote_objects">
  <title>I can't connect to my remote objects ?</title>
  <para>
   A GNOME <ulink type="http"
   url="http://mail.gnome.org/archives/gnome-list/2000-June/thread.html#00439">
   security discussion</ulink> led to disabling IIOP over IP server
   sockets (i.e. ports) per default. Instead either UNIX domain
   sockets or shared memory for interprocess communication are
   used. This disables communcation over the network but prevents the
   system from Denial of Service attacks. If you want to use ORBit
   over the network you need to turn it on again. This can either be
   done in /etc/orbitrc (system-wide settings), in ~/.orbitrc (user's
   settings), or on a per application basis by passing a parameter to
   the ORB. For Solution one and two you need to put ORBIIOPIPv4=1
   into one of the orbitrc files. Controlling the settings for each
   application can be done by providing ORBIIOPIPv4=1 at the
   command-line to your client/server application and passing the argc
   and argv parameters to the CORBA_ORB_init() call
   (default-handling).  You can check the setting with the command:
   <command>netstat -ao | grep LISTEN</command>. You should not have
   any orbit related sockets in listen mode (a line: "unix 0 [ ACC ]
   STREAM LISTENING XXXX /tmp/orbit-USER/orb-YYYYYYYYYYYYYYYY" should
   not appear). See docs/internals/orbitrc.txt for more information.
  </para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="which_parameters_are_supported_by_corba_orb_init">
  <title>Which parameters are supported by CORBA_ORB_init() ?</title>
  <para> ORBit specific parameters:
   <itemizedlist>

	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	    <guilabel>ORBDebugFlags=traces|inproc_traces|timings|types|messages|errors|objects|giop|refs</guilabel>
	    The amount of debugging information to display. The
	    modules can be combined by using , ":" as separator.
	    </para>
	  </listitem>

	  
	  <listitem>
	    <para><guilabel>ORBIIOPIPv4=0|1</guilabel>
	     Disable/Enable IPv4 server sockets.</para>
	  </listitem>
	  
	  <listitem>
	    <para><guilabel>ORBIIOPIPv6=0|1</guilabel>
	    Disable/Enable IPv6 sockets.</para>
	  </listitem>

	  <listitem>
	    <para><guilabel>ORBIIOPIPName=HostInterface</guilabel>
	    Defines the IP host-name the server shall bind to.</para>
	  </listitem>

	  <listitem>
	    <para><guilabel>ORBIIOPIPSock=#port</guilabel> Number of
	    port to listen for IIOP connections. This parameter is
	    required for persistent object references
	    (PortableServer_PERSISTENT policy).  </para>
	  </listitem>

	  <listitem>
	    <para><guilabel>ORBInitialMsgLimit=#</guilabel> Amount of
	    data accepted on first method invocation. Succeeding
	    method invocations are not limited. This option is used to
	    prevent DOS attacks - ie. opening a connection to service,
	    sending huge amount of junk data. </para>
	  </listitem>

	  <listitem>
	    <para><guilabel>ORBIIOPUNIX=0|1</guilabel>
	    Disable/Enable UNIX domain sockets.</para>
	  </listitem>

	  <listitem>
	    <para><guilabel>ORBIIOPIrDA=0|1</guilabel>
	    Disable/Enable IrDA capabilities.</para>
	  </listitem>

	  <listitem>
	    <para><guilabel>ORBIIOPSSL=0|1</guilabel>
	    Disable/Enable IIOP over SSL.</para>
	  </listitem>

	  <listitem>
	    <para><guilabel>ORBIIOPIrDA=0|1</guilabel>
	    Disable/Enable IrDA capabilities.</para>
	  </listitem>

	  <listitem>
	    <para><guilabel>ORBNamingIOR=IOR</guilabel> (Available for
	    ORBit2.8) Define specific reference of NameService, ie. on
	    command line define reference of NameService by
	    -ORBNamingIOR=IOR:010000002800000.., or as human readable
	    CORBA-Loc URL
	    -ORBNamingIOR=corbaloc:iiop:gnome.org:8884/NameService%00. The
	    suffix %00 terminates the char-sequence forming a
	    C-string.  If used in combination with option ORBInitRef,
	    the option ORBInitRef dominates. </para>
	  </listitem>

	  <listitem>
	    <para><guilabel>ORBInitRef=Id=IOR</guilabel> (Available
	    for ORBit2.8) Define initial reference of generic service,
	    ie. on command line define reference of NameService by
	    -ORBInitRef=NameService=IOR:010000002800000..</para>
	  </listitem>
 
	  <listitem>
	    <para><guilabel>ORBCorbaloc=0|1</guilabel>(Available for
	    ORBit2.9) If set, object_to_string will create corbaloc
	    URL terms instead of IORs, ie. corbaloc:iiop:1.2@gnome.org:8884/NameService%00 
          </para>
	  </listitem>
   </itemizedlist>

  </para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="calling_orb_init_what_is_orbit_local_orb_good_for">
      <title>
      Calling ORB_init(), what is string "orbit-local-orb" good for?
      </title>
      <para>
      ORBit2 supports single- and multi-threaded mode. the string is
      used to tell ORBit2 what mode it shall run into. Using the
      string "orbit-local-mt-orb" for initialization, ORBit2 will
      enter the multi-threaded mode:
      <programlisting>
       (*orb) = CORBA_ORB_init(argc_ptr, argv, "orbit-local-mt-orb", ev);
      </programlisting>
 
      For single threaded application usually "orbit-local-orb" is
      given as argument:
      <programlisting>
       (*orb) = CORBA_ORB_init(argc_ptr, argv, "orbit-local-orb", ev);
      </programlisting>

      Footnote: Since release ORBit2-2.7.5 multi-threaded setup is
      used by default. To force single threaded setup you must give
      string argument "orbit-local-non-threaded-orb", any other string
      will keep multi threaded settings.
      <programlisting>
       (*orb) = CORBA_ORB_init(argc_ptr, argv, "orbit-local-non-threaded-orb", ev);
      </programlisting>
      </para>
  </sect1>

   <sect1 id="is_orbit2_thread_safe">
   <title>Is ORBit2 thread safe ?</title>
   <para>
   ORBit2 is theoreticaly thread safe, ie. we thought about it a bit
   during the design - which is nominaly thread safe, we added a lot
   of locks, and we fixed deadlocks when they were found. With release
   ORBit2-2.7.5 thread safe setup is used by default.
   </para>
   </sect1>

   <sect1 id="mem_debug_mode">
   <title>How do I debug memory leaks?</title>
   <para>
   OK - if you compile ORBit2 with --enable-debug (perhaps you did
   this already), then export ORBIT2_DEBUG=refs, then re-run - it
   should show you the type of object that is leaked - which may help.
   Probably you are missing a CORBA_Object_release (foo, NULL);
   somewhere.  
   </para>

   <para> You might want to use memory debugger of some sort; I would
   recommend valgrind - google for it; you need to build ORBit2 with
   --enable-purify and run with --alignment=8 but it's an extremely
   powerful &amp; useful tool.
   </para>
   </sect1>

   <sect1 id="what_is_this_re_enterancy_thing"> 
   <title>What is this re-enterancy thing ?</title>
   <para>
   When a method is invoked, while the ORB is waiting for a return
   value or exception (if applicable) the ORB processes any other
   incoming requests in a re-enterant fashion. This occurs even during
   threaded operation currently.
   </para>
   </sect1>

   <sect1 id ="can_i_invoke_methods_from_multiple_threads">
   <title>Can I invoke methods from multiple threads ?</title>
   <para>
   Yes, this should present no particular problem.
   </para>
   </sect1>

   <sect1 id="can_i_receive_invocations_in_multiple_threads">
   <title>Can I receive invocations in multiple threads ?</title>
   <para>
   Yes - assuming you have a glib mainloop ( or a linc_mainloop )
   running in one or several of your threads. The precice thread that
   the invocation is recieved in is unpredictable.
   </para>
   </sect1>

   <sect1 id="can_i_have_each_invocation_handled_by_a_different_thread">
   <title>Can I have each invocation handled by a different thread ?</title>
   <para>
   Yes - much effort has been put into this. POA policies must be used to
   define behaviour of newly created POAs; eg. 'THREAD_PER_REQUEST' policy.
   </para>
   </sect1>

   <sect1 id="how_does_the_new_type_system_work">
   <title>How does the new 'type' system work ?</title>
   <para>
   The new type system forms a fundamental part of ORBit2 and presents
   a major simplification.
   </para>
   </sect1>

   <sect1 id="what_do_mean_by_type_data">
   <title>What do you mean by 'type' data ?</title>
   <para>
   By type data we mean not only structure layout information, but
   also full interface and method information. ie. not just value
   class types but interfaces as well.
   </para>
   </sect1>

   <sect1 id="how_do_we_get_type_data_for_an_interface">
   <title>How do we get type data for an interface ?</title>
   <para>
   There are two answers to this. Firstly, if you have a pointer to an
   Object reference and you know nothing more than that it is a ORBit2
   handled CORBA object, you can (via. an ORBit2 extension) request
   it's type id, and from this, a full interface description.
   </para>
   <para>
        see ORBit2/include/orb/orb-core/orbit-small.h
        and ORBit2/include/orb/orb-core/orbit-iinterface.h (from)
            ORBit2/src/orb/orb-core/orbit-iinterface.idl
   </para>

   <sect2 id="type_data_from_an_object_reference">
   <title>Type data from an object reference ?</title>
   <para>
   <programlisting>
        CORBA_char *type_id;
        ORBit_IInterface *iface;

        type_id = ORBit_small_get_type_id (obj, ev);
        iface   = ORBit_small_get_iinterface (obj, type_id, ev);
   </programlisting>
   </para>
   </sect2>

   <sect2 id="type_data_from_a_type_library">
   <title>Type data from a type library ?</title>
   <para>
   If we wish to implement an interface in our scripting language
   that is not currently registered with the ORB, then we can load it
   dynamicaly from the type library interface:
   <programlisting>ORBit_small_load_typelib ("Bonobo");</programlisting>
   
   We can then suck all the interface and TypeCode information out of
   the library, in order to construct local language bound peers:
   
   <programlisting>CORBA_sequence_CORBA_TypeCode   *ORBit_small_get_types ("Bonobo");
CORBA_sequence_ORBit_IInterface *ORBit_small_get_iinterfaces (...);</programlisting>
   </para>
   </sect2>
   </sect1>

   <sect1 id="what_is_type_library_or_imodule"> 
   <title>What is a type library (or imodule) ?</title>
   <para>
   Type libraries are essentialy the same generic interface
   information that the ORB uses to marshal and de-marshal information
   in the C stubs. It is contained in the -common.c file of a compiled
   set.
   </para>
   <para>
   To install a type library correctly you need to have some
   automake a little like:
   </para>
   <programlisting>
orbittypelib_LTLIBRARIES = Bonobo_module.la
orbittypelibdir = $(libdir)/orbit-2.0
IMODULE_SOURCE =        \
        Bonobo.h        \
        Bonobo-common.c \
        Bonobo-imodule.c
Bonobo_module_la_SOURCES = \
        Bonobo-imodule.c
Bonobo_module_la_LIBADD = \
        $(LIBBONOBO_LIBS)
Bonobo_module_la_LDFLAGS = \
        -export-dynamic -module

$(IMODULE_SOURCE): $(idl_DATA) $(ORBIT_IDL)
        $(ORBIT_IDL) $(idl_flags) --imodule \
                     $(top_srcdir)/idl/Bonobo.idl
   </programlisting>
   <para>
   Note that the library is installed into $(libdir)/orbit-2.0.  When
   a typelib is loaded, an explicit path can be passed in, otherwise
   the ':' delimited path environment variables ORBIT_TYPELIB_PATH and
   GNOME_PATH are searched.
   </para>
   </sect1>

   <sect1 id="how_do_i_find_what_type_libraries_are_installed">
   <title>How do I find what type libraries are installed ?</title>
   <para>
   There is a utility ORBit2/test/typelib-dump that will display a
   list of available libraries for your path setup:
   </para>
   <para>
   Installed type libraries:
   <programlisting>
        /opt/ngnome2/lib/orbit:

                Everything
                Accessibility
                Bonobo
   </programlisting>
   It can also rudimantarily dump the contents of a type library.
   </para>
   </sect1>

   <sect1 id="why_bother_generating_type_information_from_an_interface">
   <title>Why bother generating type information from an interface ?</title>
   <para>
   With ORBit stable, language bindings had to load and parse the IDL
   definitions for the interface. This had several disadvantages.

   <itemizedlist>
   <listitem><para>
   Primarily performance - loading a load of IDL text, forking the
   pre-preocessor to pre-process it, resolving all the symbols as
   strings, converting to an internal representaton - took time. With
   a standard internal representation, and a simple dlopen to grab it
   we have a major performance win.
   </para></listitem>

   <listitem><para> 
   Include problems: many IDL files are grouped into a
   single file to build, and can cause grief when included
   individualy. This contrasts with a working bundle of interfaces,
   verified at package IDL compile time.
   </para></listitem>

   <listitem><para>
   libIDL - is an unmaintained mess, and is not particularly
   pleasant to link against, or code to.
   </para></listitem>
  
   <listitem><para>
   Finding the IDL files - there was no standard path structure, or
   method of reliably locating all the relevant IDL files.  Now at
   least there is an ad-hoc shared standard.
   </para></listitem>
   
   </itemizedlist>
   </para>
   </sect1>

   <sect1 id="why_is_a_type_based_orb_better">
   <title>Why is a type based ORB better ?</title>
   <para>
   Firstly ABI reduction, in ORBit stable the API usage by the stubs
   was very considerable - many methods were called, and there was a
   considerable body of code in a stub or a skel.
   </para>

   <para>
   With ORBit2 a stub looks like a bit like this:
   <programlisting>
Bonobo_Unknown
Bonobo_Unknown_queryInterface (Bonobo_Unknown     obj,
                               const CORBA_char  *repoid,
                               CORBA_Environment *ev)
{
        Bonobo_Unknown _ORBIT_retval;

        ... local fast case ... else ...
        { /* remote marshal */
                gpointer _args[] = {
                        (gpointer) &amp; repoid
                };

                ORBit_small_invoke_stub (
                        obj,
                        &amp;Bonobo_Unknown__iinterface.methods._buffer[2],
                        &amp;_ORBIT_retval, _args, NULL, ev);

        }

        return _ORBIT_retval;
}
   </programlisting>

        ie. we expose a single method call here
'ORBit_small_invoke_stub'. This method is passed the object reference,
the arguments in a normalized form ( as an array of gpointers ) a
pointer to the return value, any CORBA_Context we might be _sing and
the exception environent.
   </para>

   <para>
   The skeleton is similar, unwinding a gpointer array of arguments
   and invoking the C method. NB. for language bindings, you can hook
   the a virtual invocation pointer on the servant to recieve a method
   type data pointer and handle the invocation fully yourself.
   </para>

   <para>
   The indirection and allocation semantics of the argument passing,
   as well as the C CORBA semantics are lucidly documented in
   ORBit2/docs/internals/interface-indirection.gnumeric.
   </para>
   </sect1>

   <sect1 id="why_is_a_type_based_orb_potentialy_faster">
   <title>Why is a type based ORB potentialy faster ?</title>
   <para>
   Well - partly due to encapsulation. Encapsulation often carries a
   cost; in ORBit stable there are several layers. Even though the
   stubs and skels are substantialy unrolled, there are a considerable
   amount of method calls, and lots of wasteful indirection.
   </para>

   <para>
   In ORBit2 we can hide an _extremely_ optimized, top to bottom to
   the wire generic marshaler behind ORBit_small_invoke_stub. This
   would be totaly private to the ORB, maintaining ORB encapsulation,
   but giving us buckets of room for optimization.
   </para>
        
   <para>
   Secondarily, in ORBit stable the stubs and skels are massively
   unrolled, giving not only a size penalty but also a speed penalty
   in terms of the processors instruction cache (Icache). In contrast
   ORBit2 maintains a far smaller Icached working set, since the
   generated code that is different per method is tiny, and the same
   generic code is executed to do the marshaling for each method.
   </para>

   <para>
   Hence - although currently what performance tests we have suggest
   that ORBit2 is ~20% slower than ORBit stable, it will be possible (
   in a totaly binary compatible fashion ) to tweak and optimize the
   marshal / de-marshal process to make it arbitarily fast.
   </para>
   </sect1>
   
   <sect1 id="what_is_the_purify_cleanliness_autoconf_option">
   <title>What is the "purify cleanliness" autoconf option ?</title>
   <para>
   This (unfinished) option allows the ORB to be configured to run in
   a slightly slower, but 'cleaner' mode. Purify is a tool that
   performs advanced memory debugging, and it will detect many common
   errors. Some of the things ORBit2 can do eg. using uninitialized
   stack space as a source of randomness will flag false positives as
   purify errors ( an Uninitialized Memory Read or UMR ). Enabling
   this flag ensures that all such memory will be blanked first before
   being read.  This also applies to initializing return values before
   returning them, even on exceptions - a case where CORBA specifies
   an uninitialized return value.
   </para>

   <para>
   The performance impact of having a putify clean ORB is probably
   fairly minimal, perhaps ~10% slower max., finger in the air
   guestimation.
   </para>
   </sect1>

   <sect1 id="using_strings">
   <title>How do I use CORBA_strings?</title>
   <para>
   For instance if you have a struct like so:
 <programlisting>
struct employee
{
    CORBA_string name;
}</programlisting>

  As long as you do not permit any CORBA/ORBit to free it, you can do:
<programlisting>
  struct employee thisemployee;
  thisemployee.name = "someone";</programlisting>

Otherwise / the more correct way is to use the CORBA API:
<programlisting>
/usr/include/orbit-2.0/orbit/orb-core/corba-string.h:
	CORBA_char          *CORBA_string_dup  (const CORBA_char *str);
	CORBA_char  *CORBA_string_alloc  (CORBA_unsigned_long len);
</programlisting>
therefore simply <programlisting>
	thisemployee.name = CORBA_string_dup ("someone");</programlisting>
   </para>
   </sect1>

   <sect1 id="my_skels_leak_memory">
   <title>My skels leak memory - why ?</title>
   <para>
	Sometimes people post to the list saying I'm doing:
    <programlisting>
CORBA_sequence_CORBA_string *
get_StringSequence (PortableServer_Servant servant,
                    CORBA_Environment     *ev)
{
	int i;
	CORBA_sequence_CORBA_string *s;
         
	s = CORBA_sequence_CORBA_string__alloc ();
	s->_buffer = CORBA_sequence_CORBA_string_allocbuf (100);
	s->_length = 100;

	for (i = 0; i < 100; i++)
		s->_buffer[i] = CORBA_string_dup ("A string");

	return s;        
} </programlisting>

	Why am I leaking huge chunks of memory ? The answer is the
        _release feature. This field is set to FALSE when the sequence
        is allocated (s->_release), and when you return from the
        implementation to the skel, the skel marshals the sequence,
        and then CORBA_free's it.  However, if the _release flag is
        FALSE, the _buffer and it's contents are not freed. This
        allows people to return static copies of their data which can
        be a big efficiency win.
        </para>
        <para>
	In this case you want the release flag set; this can be done
        by:
        <programlisting> s->_release = TRUE; </programlisting>

        before you return, or

	<programlisting>CORBA_sequence_set_release (s, TRUE); </programlisting>

	A similar scheme is used for the value of a CORBA_any being
        returned.
        </para>
        </sect1>

        <sect1 id="why_should_I_not_use_the_release_flag ">
        <title> Why should I not use the _release flag?</title>
        <para>
	While _release works really well out of process, if you are
        writing library code, or code that might be used by another
        component in process - then the _release flag is a
        nightmare. The reason is quite simple; in the remote case, the
        data is copied to the wire, and the client receives a copy of
        which he controls the lifecycle. The problem is that in-proc,
        the client receives only a shallow copy and has no control (
        or idea ) of it's lifecycle.

	Thus you might return some data, and then in a later method
        alter the data - the client's copy then would contain bad
        information.
        </para>
      </sect1>

  <sect1 id="why_is_the_ior_from_orb_xyz_not_understood_by_orbit">
  <title>Why is the IOR from ORB XYZ not understood by ORBit?</title>
  <para>Check whether the IOR has some whitespaces at the end. ORBit version below 0.5.x does not accept IORs with trailing whitespaces. 
  </para>
  </sect1>
</chapter>

  <chapter id="help">
    <title>Help</title>

  <sect1 id="is_there_a_mailing_list_howto">
  <title>Is there a mailing list HOWTO?</title> <para>The mailing-list
  demon provides a short description on how to use it. Send an e-mail
  to <email>orbit-list-requestNOSPAM@gnome.org</email> with subject "help".
  </para>
  </sect1> 


  <sect1 id="how_can_i_subscribe_to_the_mailing_list">
  <title>How can I subscribe to the mailing list?</title> <para>Go to
  <ulink type="http"  url="http://mail.gnome.org/mailman/listinfo/orbit-list">
   mail.gnome.org/mailman/listinfo/orbit-list</ulink>.
  </para>
  </sect1> 

  <sect1 id="how_can_i_unsubscribe_from_the_mailing_list">
  <title>How can I unsubscribe from the mailing list?</title>
  <para>Go to
  <ulink type="http"  url="http://mail.gnome.org/mailman/listinfo/orbit-list">
   mail.gnome.org/mailman/listinfo/orbit-list</ulink>.
  </para>
  </sect1> 


  <sect1 id="how_can_i_send_an_email_to_the_mailing_list">
  <title>How can I send an e-mail to the mailing list?</title>
  <para>Send e-mail to <email>orbit-list@NOSPAMgnome.org</email>.
  </para>
  </sect1> 


  <sect1 id="is_there_a_mailing_list_archive">
  <title>Is there a mailing list archive?</title> 

  <para>There is a searchable archive available on <ulink type="http"
  url="http://mail.gnome.org/archives/orbit-list/">mail.gnome.org/archives/orbit-list</ulink>.
  </para>
  </sect1> 


  <sect1 id="i_am_new_to_corba_what_books_are_available">
  <title> I'm new to CORBA. What books are available?</title> <para>
  There are a lot of books available. The major online stores have
  ratings and comments of almost any CORBA book on the market.
   <itemizedlist>
	<listitem><para><ulink type="http" url="http://btobsearch.barnesandnoble.com/booksearch/results.asp?WRD=CORBA&amp;userid=2XMF0OO66D&amp;btob=Y"> CORBA books at Barnes&amp;Noble</ulink></para> </listitem>
	<listitem><para><ulink type="http" url="http://www.infosys.tuwien.ac.at/Research/Corba/books.html"> CORBA books at TU Vienna (2000)</ulink></para> </listitem>
	<listitem><para><ulink type="http" url="http://www.javaworld.com/isearch?qt=book+corba&amp;x=0&amp;y=0&amp;site=javaworld&amp;ms=1&amp;tid=1&amp;st=1&amp;rf=0">CORBA books &amp; whitepapers at JavaWorld </ulink></para> </listitem>
   </itemizedlist>

   One of the best books is Michi Henning's and Steve Vinoski's book:
   "Advanced CORBA Programming with C++" (ISBN
   0-201-37927-9). Although the title seems to address only for C++
   programmers it contains explanations of many fundamental concepts
   and is thus useful for a general understanding.
  </para>
  </sect1> 
 
</chapter>
</book>
